president Trump was threatening personal
特朗普总统威胁要进行人身攻击。
and political retaliation because they
以及政治报复，因为他们
tried to help Harris get elected do you
你曾试图帮助哈里斯当选吗？
think you'll be penalized yes and Direct
你认为你会受到处罚吗？是的，直接处罚。
on you and direct me you're not planning
你指着我，告诉我你没有计划
on leaving the US are
离开美国时是
you um Reed Hoffman is the co-founder of
嗯，里德·霍夫曼是联合创始人
LinkedIn and one of the world's most
LinkedIn 是世界上最……之一
successful entrepreneurs playing pivotal
成功的企业家发挥着关键作用
roles in the success of influential
在有影响力人士的成功中所扮演的角色
companies including PayPal Airbnb
包括PayPal和Airbnb在内的公司
Facebook and open Ai and now he is a
Facebook 和 OpenAI，现在他也是其中一员。
leading voice in AI helping people
人工智能领域帮助人们的领军人物
utilize this new technology to empower
利用这项新技术来赋能
themselves in their life and careers you
他们自己，在他们的生活和事业中，你
were part of what they call the PayPal
他们都是他们所谓的PayPal的一部分
Mafia who went on to create Tesla
后来创建特斯拉的黑手党
YouTube Reddit SpaceX LinkedIn and
YouTube、Reddit、SpaceX、LinkedIn 和
become multi-billionaires and so I've
成为亿万富翁，所以我
got so many questions let's do it what
有很多问题，我们开始吧！
are the key factors of a great
是伟大成就的关键因素。
entrepreneur's mindset one is you have
企业家思维模式之一：你拥有
to understand that you don't get to an
要明白你无法达到
optimistic future by trying to avoid
通过试图避免而对未来抱有乐观态度
failure when we started LinkedIn
我们创办 LinkedIn 时遭遇了失败。
everyone said this won't work but just
大家都说这行不通，但是……
because you don't have a 100% chance of
因为你没有100%的把握
succeeding doesn't mean that you
成功并不意味着你
shouldn't do it but there's also a set
不应该这样做，但也有一套
of skills that are rare that you can
拥有一些稀有技能，你可以
actually teach to entrepreneurs makes
实际上，教给企业家们
you much more likely to be successful
你成功的可能性大大增加。
the first is and then how do you know
首先，你怎么知道？
when to quit the job what's your view on
何时辞职？你对此有何看法？
work life balance and if you were
工作与生活平衡，以及如果你是
advising anyone to build wealth in 2025
建议任何人于 2025 年积累财富
what would you say here's some simple
你会怎么说？这里有一些简单的
tips one is Reed what is your take on AI
第一个问题是里德，你对人工智能有什么看法？
it gives us super powers now there will
它现在赋予我们超能力，将会
be costs to it but like electricity it
会对它造成成本，但就像电力一样。
does electrocute people but it's
确实会电死人，但是……
essential for human society and is there
对人类社会至关重要，而且是否存在？
anything that the average person should
普通人应该拥有的东西
be doing to capitalize on the
正在采取哪些措施来利用
opportunity that AI presents 100% this
人工智能带来的机遇百分之百属于这一类。
is what you do so
这就是你所做的。
this has always blown my mind a little
这件事一直让我有点难以置信。
bit 53% of you that listen to the show
53% 的听众收听了该节目
regularly haven't yet subscribed to the
经常还没有订阅
show so could I ask you for a favor
所以，我能请你帮个忙吗？
before we start if you like the show and
在我们开始之前，如果你喜欢这个节目，
you like what we do here and you want to
你喜欢我们在这里做的事情，并且你想……
support us the free simple way that you
您支持我们的方式很简单，而且完全免费。
can do just that is by hitting the
做到这一点的方法就是点击
Subscribe button and my commitment to
订阅按钮以及我对订阅的承诺
you is if you do that then I'll do
如果你那样做，那我也会那样做。
everything in my power me and my team to
我和我的团队将竭尽全力
make sure that this show is better for
确保这个节目对……更好
you every single week we'll listen to
我们每周都会听你的节目。
your feedback we'll find the guest that
您的反馈将帮助我们找到合适的客人
you want me to speak to and we'll
你想让我跟谁谈谈，我们……
continue to do what we do thank you so
请继续做我们正在做的事情，谢谢。
much
很多
[Music]
[音乐]
read as I read through your life it's
我读着你的人生，就像读着你的人生故事一样。
remarkable in it's almost impossible
这简直令人难以置信，几乎不可能
that one individual could be involved in
一个人可能参与其中
so many companies that have had such a
很多公司都经历过这种情况
big impact on
对……产生重大影响
society but at the same time someone
社会，但同时也是某人
would be able to seemingly see the
似乎能够看到
future over and over and over and over
未来一遍又一遍地
again so because as I read through your
再次强调，因为我读了你的文章后，发现你
life I thought this can't be one
我心想，人生不可能是这样。
individual this can't be one lifetime it
个人而言，这不可能是一生一次的事。
it begs the question to me what is in
这让我不禁要问，里面究竟是什么？
your view the causal factors that set
你认为造成这种情况的因果因素是什么？
you up for such a
你愿意做这样的事吗？
life well that's interesting I've never
生活啊，真有趣，我从来没有
been asked that question before
之前有人问过这个问题。
um probably it's a
嗯，可能是……
combination of the fact that my passion
结合我的热情这一事实
is who are we as human beings and where
我们作为人类是谁？我们身处何方？
are we going so like that's from from a
我们是不是要这样？就像是从……开始的
very young age like I've been like and I
从小到大，我一直都是这样，而且
think I got it by reading science
我想我是通过阅读科学书籍理解的。
fiction right this kind of like what is
小说，对吧？这种小说就像什么？
the scope of humanity like you know
人类的广度，就像你所知的那样。
Isaac asimov's foundation and you know
艾萨克·阿西莫夫的《基地》以及你知道的
this kind of stuff and then
诸如此类的事情，然后
um I ended up growing up I was born in
嗯，我最终长大成人，我出生在……
the Stanford hospital I ended up growing
我最终成长的斯坦福医院
up in Silicon Valley and and so I got
我在硅谷，然后我就……
the exposure to technology can change
接触技术的程度可能会发生变化
the world and so focusing on thinking
世界，因此专注于思考
about you know kind of this intersection
你知道，就是这种交叉路口。
of humanity and technology and of course
人类与科技，当然还有
obviously science fiction has some play
显然，科幻小说也发挥了一定的作用。
to that too although most the technology
虽然大多数技术也存在这种情况，但这项技术
in science fiction is just fiction right
科幻小说就是虚构的，对吧？
just like we have wormholes and we do
就像我们有虫洞一样，而且我们确实有。
Intergalactic travel it's like as far as
星际旅行就像远在……
we know there is no such thing as
我们知道根本不存在这样的东西
wormholes for Intergalactic travel right
用于星际旅行的虫洞
I mean all current contemporary Theory
我指的是所有当前的当代理论
of physics would suggest that there
物理学原理表明，
isn't I mean there may be wormholes but
我的意思是，也许存在虫洞，但是
they're not for you know put your Star
它们不是给你的，你知道，把你的星星放上去。
Trek spaceship in it and go somewhere
乘坐星际飞船前往某个地方
and then probably the other part of it
然后可能还有另一部分
is um I played a lot of board games when
嗯……我以前玩过很多桌游。
I was kid and so it gave me a very deep
我当时还是个孩子，所以这件事给我留下了非常深刻的印象。
sense of strategy and so approaching
战略意识，以及由此而来的方法
life yeah exact wow this one here you
生活啊，没错，哇，就是这个，你
probably remember this yes I do remember
可能记得，是的，我记得。
that right in the names on the cover
封面上的名字就写着呢。
Borderlands what age were you when you
无主之地 你玩的时候多大了
started playing Rune Quest you were very
你开始玩《符文探索》的时候非常
young uh when I started playing Rune
年轻的时候，我开始玩符文游戏。
Quest
寻求
probably
大概
10 and what is the link between the life
10. 生命与此有何联系？
you lived in the board games you played
你生活在你玩过的棋盘游戏中。
as a 10-year-old um well mostly as a
10岁的时候，嗯，主要是作为……
function again like the role playing
再次发挥角色扮演的作用
games is like strategy right so it's
游戏就像策略游戏，对吧？
kind of um you know how do you uh kind
有点像，你知道，你怎么做，呃，那种
of think about like uh like an adventure
想想就像一场冒险
is both a narrative experience but it's
它既是一种叙事体验，又是一种
also a strategic experience like you
还有像你这样的战略经验
know how do you save the town from the
你知道如何拯救这座小镇吗？
from the you know the bandits you know
你知道的，那些强盗。
that kind of thing and so um so it gave
就是那种事，所以，嗯，它给了
me a deep sense of kind of like how do
我内心深处有一种感觉，就像……
strategy and tactics and problem solving
战略、战术和问题解决
um and how do you do it as a group
嗯，你们团队是怎么做的呢？
right because you know in fantasy role
对，因为你知道在奇幻角色中
playing games it tends to be you know
玩游戏的时候，你知道的。
especially when I was doing it as a kid
尤其是我小时候做这件事的时候。
a set of blos around the table uh I hear
桌子周围有一群花儿，呃，我听到了。
it's now a little bit more gender Balan
现在性别平衡方面稍微多了一些
which is good and especially especially
这很好，尤其特别
for the blos it's like oh we're not
对于blos来说，就好像“哦，我们不”
we're not just Geeks by ourselves here
我们这里不只有极客。
right um and um and so and the way that
对，嗯，嗯，所以，还有那种方式
I got to doing this is I was enough
我之所以能做到这一点，是因为我足够优秀。
because this is kind of the focused you
因为这是某种程度上专注的你
know kind of kid I was is what I um I'd
我知道我小时候是什么样的孩子，嗯，我……
heard that the chaosium had their
听说混沌组织有他们的
offices were were down the street from a
办公室就在街对面
friend of minees and so I literally
我的一个朋友，所以我真的
walked in the door and started hanging
走进门就开始挂东西
out at their office and they're the
他们在办公室里，他们是
maker of this game they're maker of this
这款游戏的制作方，他们就是这款游戏的制作方。
game the chief editor I think wanted to
我认为游戏主编想要的是
get me out of the office so he said he
他说，让他带我离开办公室。
handed me the pre the the in development
递给我预开发阶段的资料
draft of this and said here go look at
这是草稿，我说去看一下。
this and so I took it home as an
于是我就把它带回家了。
obsessive kid I I like redlined it I
我是一个痴迷的孩子，我喜欢把它涂成红色。
worked my way through it and I brought
我努力克服了困难，然后我把它带了回来。
it back like he gave me a Friday and I
就像他给了我一个星期五一样，我
brought it back on Monday so he failed
他周一把它带回来了，所以他失败了。
on his get this kid out of the office
他想把这孩子弄出办公室。
mission right but he's he was then and I
任务对，但他当时是，而我
I I still remember this look of vague
我仍然记得那种茫然的表情。
irritation when I handed him this
当我把这个递给他时，他很恼火。
because he's like ah this kid is handing
因为他觉得，啊，这孩子真厉害。
me this thing oh [__] I don't want to be
我，这东西，哦，该死，我不想这样
a meany guy and then he started looking
一个卑鄙的家伙，然后他开始寻找
at it and went oh this is actually good
我试了一下，然后说，哦，这其实还不错。
work and it was like I want to use this
工作，感觉就像我想用这个
work and I was a kid so I didn't
我当时既要工作又要照顾孩子，所以我不工作。
understand he needed to pay me to use it
我明白他需要付钱才能使用它。
I was that wasn't why I was just doing
我当时那样做并不是因为这个原因。
it because I wanted to show that I that
因为我想表明我
I knew how to do this stuff and so he
我知道怎么做这些事，所以他
then wrote me a check um so it was my
然后给我写了张支票，嗯，所以那是我的
like my very first paycheck to to be
就像我的第一份工资一样
able to to use the work in the
能够运用这项工作
publication um because you know this is
出版嗯，因为你知道这是
how copyright that that means he then
他如何获得版权？这意味着他
owns all the work that I did so he could
他拥有我所做的所有工作，这样他就可以……
publish it and is your work still in
发布它，你的作品还在吗？
here today yes uhuh so edits that you
今天在这里，嗯哼，所以你做的修改
made to this game are still in here at
为这款游戏制作的内容仍然在这里
what age uh that was 12 wow that's
几岁？呃，那是12岁，哇，那真是……
incredible and how much did he pay you
太不可思议了，他付给你多少钱？
oh it's like $160 or something it's not
哦，大概160美元左右吧，不是这样的。
bad for 12-year-old no no no my dad my
对12岁的孩子不好，不不不，我爸爸，我的
dad was originally opposed to Fantasy
爸爸最初是反对幻想的。
role play games it was like uh what what
角色扮演游戏，就好像……呃……什么？
are you doing like you know go like be
你是不是像你知道的那样，像……
on a path to a real life and then when I
走上通往真实生活的道路，然后当我
brought home the paycheck I like well
我把满意的薪水带回家了。
maybe that
或许是这样
works and what was your what were your
作品以及你的……你的
dreams at that age what did you think
你那个年纪的梦想是什么？
you were going to be when you were older
你长大后会成为那样的人
sort of 12 13 14 years old frankly I had
坦白说，我大概12、13、14岁的时候就有了。
no idea other than the following
除了以下几点之外，我没有其他想法了。
entertaining thing which is since both
有趣的事情，因为两者
my mother and father are lawyers when I
我父母都是律师。
was asked when I was 12 what I wanted to
我12岁的时候被问到想做什么
be when I grew up the answer was not a
当我长大后，答案并不是一个
lawyer really yes well because
律师真的吗？是的，因为
lawyers um look obviously bunch of are
律师们，嗯，看起来很明显是一群人
barister the side of the pond um lawyers
律师在池塘边，嗯，律师们
are essentially modern Gladiators who
本质上是现代角斗士
are paid to be the Gladiator of whatever
他们受雇成为任何领域的角斗士
their paycheck is whether it's a client
他们的薪水取决于客户是否在服务他们
or whether it's you know being a
或者你知道，成为一名
full-time employee and so forth and it's
全职员工等等，就是这样。
quality work it's important for society
高质量的工作对社会至关重要。
but like I was like no no I want to
但我当时就想，不不，我想要
create things I don't want to be a you
创造我不想成为的你
know you know belt on my sword and you
你知道，你知道我剑上的腰带，还有你
know go to verbal battle for you know
知道为了你而进行口头交锋是可能的。
whatever the you know contract or or
无论你知道的合同或其他什么
litigation or any of those things and I
诉讼或任何类似的事情，而我
was like no no no I I actually want to
当时我就想，不不不，我其实想……
go build things and so I didn't know
去建造东西，所以我并不知道
what I wanted
我想要的
to be when I grew up other than and
长大后除了……之外，我还想成为……
maybe I still don't know right um but
也许我还不清楚，嗯……
what I evolve to is I normally have
我最终的演变过程通常是这样的：我通常有
about a two to three year plan that's
大约是一个为期两到三年的计划。
iterating right and that's that's tends
迭代正确，这就是趋势
to be what I do and being born at
成为我所做的人，以及我的出生地
Stanford hospital is pertinent as well I
斯坦福医院也与此相关。
don't think people in the UK and around
不要认为英国及周边地区的人们
the world necessarily know the
世界必然会知道
significance of that yeah but can you
是的，那意义重大，但是你能做到吗？
explain why that's important Silicon
解释一下为什么硅很重要
Valley um is a it's a network of a
Valley um 是一个网络
generative platform so like one of the
生成平台，就像其中一个
things that that I have learned to think
我学会思考的事情
about is networks amplify productivity
关于网络如何提高生产力
that's not just as we get to you know
不仅仅是我们后来才知道的
why it is i f i conceptualized and
为什么我构思了它？
founded LinkedIn but but it's think in
创立了LinkedIn，但我认为……
terms of networks it's one of the
就网络而言，它是其中之一
reasons why cities are such uh engines
城市之所以如此强大，原因如下
like basically if you really look at
基本上，如果你仔细观察……
economies it's city regions and U it's
经济体，它是城市地区和美国，它是
because the city region creates a
因为城市区域创造了
network right it's a network of could be
网络对，它是一个可能是的网络
suppliers and all the rest but also
供应商以及其他所有人，但也
talent and capital and and and and
人才和资本，以及，以及，以及
knowledge and communication and and
知识和沟通以及
strategic lenses onto the world and so
以战略视角看待世界，因此
Silicon Valley has been an like like
硅谷一直都像这样
people go oh I'm a genius it's like no
人们会说“哦，我是个天才”，但事实并非如此。
no I'm in Silicon Valley right and that
不，我现在在硅谷，对吧？
really helps and so being born in
真的很有帮助，所以出生在
Stanford gave me this a set of different
斯坦福给了我一套不同的
you know kind of perspectives one
你知道，某种视角
technology is a lens into the uh future
科技是通往未来的窗口。
another one is as an individual you can
另一个方面是，作为个人，你可以
go create a technology or technology
去创造一种技术或科技
company that can be a lever that can
能够成为杠杆的公司
move the world right and that an
让世界向正确的方向发展，而那是一个
individual you know from anywhere can
你认识的任何人，无论来自哪里，都可以
kind of do that um and all of those
有点像那样，嗯，还有所有这些
things were were part of the luck of
事情的发生是运气的一部分
being born in
出生于
Stanford the luck yes well I don't
斯坦福的运气，嗯，我不知道。
choose you don't choose where you're
你无法选择你身在何处。
born but a lot of people were born there
出生，但很多人都出生在那里。
and they didn't go on to do the things
他们并没有继续做那些事。
that you did people like to tell stories
你做的那些事，人们都喜欢讲故事。
of manifest destiny it's because I am
这是我命中注定的，因为我就是
great it I would have been great
太好了，我本来会很棒的
anywhere that I was right and it's self-
无论我做什么都是对的，而且它本身就是如此。
delusional I mean yes I think I'm smart
妄想？我的意思是，没错，我觉得自己很聪明。
yes I think I'm hardworking yes I think
是的，我认为我很努力。
I'm strategic yes I think I have skills
是的，我很有策略，我认为我有能力。
that are rare in in in human condition
在人类疾病中罕见
but any great achievement also has luck
但任何伟大的成就也离不开运气。
right and and I can point it in any
对，我可以把它指向任何方向
companies I can point it at any
我可以把它指向任何一家公司。
individuals um and for example one of
个人，例如其中之一
the basic luck is like I had exposure
基本的运气就像我接触到了某种东西。
and connection to Silicon Valley if I
以及与硅谷的联系，如果我
didn't have that the technology Destiny
当时没有那种技术，命运
or the technology achievements I've done
或者我取得的技术成就
wouldn't have been able to do those or
本来不可能做到那些事，或者
wouldn't have been able to do those the
本来不可能做到那些事。
amazing way that I did them
我做得太棒了
so what would you say then because
那你打算怎么说呢？
there's people that listen to the show
有人会听这个节目。
all around the world um I we just
世界各地，嗯，我们只是
Spotify rap just came out and globally
Spotify rap 刚刚上线，并且在全球范围内都取得了成功。
we have quite an extensive audience it's
我们的受众群体相当广泛。
funny it's funny that it's so globally
真搞笑，它居然如此具有全球性
distributed but I think a factor of
分布，但我认为一个因素
being on YouTube and speaking English
在 YouTube 上说英语
what would you say to people that are
你会对那些……的人说什么？
born in we've got an audience in Cape
我们出生在开普敦，我们有观众。
Town in Indonesia in Australia New
澳大利亚印度尼西亚新镇
Zealand what would you say to people in
你会对新西兰的人们说什么？
those parts of the world can you still
世界那些地方你仍然可以
be quot unquote massively successful yes
取得“巨大成功”？是的
but but you have to think so um and I
但是，但是你得这么想，嗯，还有我
see you have a few of my books there um
我看到你那里有几本我的书，嗯。
my very first book the startup review um
我的第一本书，《创业评论》
which um came from the commencement
嗯，这源于开学典礼
speech I gave at my high school the
我在高中发表的演讲
Putney School in Vermont because I was
我在佛蒙特州的普特尼学校就读，因为我
like what do I say to a bunch of 17y
我该对一群17岁的孩子说什么呢？
olds right and I was like well be the
老家伙说得对，我就想，好吧，就这么定了。
entrepreneur of your own life and what
成为自己人生的企业家，以及什么
that means there's a chapter in there
这意味着里面有一章。
that
那
says uh uh the bad advice you're usually
他说，呃呃，你通常给出的那些糟糕的建议
given is just follow your passion and
答案就是追随你的热情。
the problem is the passion your passion
问题在于你的激情
might be very passionate but does do you
或许你热情洋溢，但你真的……
have a strategic Advantage there is that
在那里拥有战略优势是
something you can do and so applying the
你可以做一些事情，所以要应用
rules of Entrepreneurship yes of course
创业规则，当然！
you have to be passionate about what
你必须对你所做的事情充满热情。
you're doing because if you're not
你这样做是因为如果你不这样做的话
passionate you can never be world class
即便充满热情，你也永远无法成为世界级选手。
unless you're passionate about what
除非你对某件事充满热情。
you're doing but that's not the only
你正在做的，但这并非唯一的原因。
thing and so you look at okay what are
事情就是这样，所以你看看，好吧，是什么
Market realities what's the market what
市场现实：什么是市场？
does a competition look like and within
一场比赛看起来是什么样的？
those what can your aspirations be and
你的抱负可能是什么？
there's a whole chapter on that in that
那本书里有一整章都在讲这个。
book because that's by the way similar
这本书，因为顺便说一句，它很相似。
to how you plot out if you're founding a
如果你要创办一家公司，你该如何规划呢？
company right if you're founding a
如果你正在创办一家公司，那么这家公司就对了。
company you have to think the same way
公司要求你必须有同样的思维方式
about this but think about it as an
关于这一点，但请把它看作是一个
individual so if you're in Cape Town
所以，如果你在开普敦的话，那就个人吧。
there are many great things you can do
你可以做很多很棒的事情
now if you say what I'm going to do is
现在，如果你说我要做什么，那就是
create a search company to compete with
创建一家搜索公司来与之竞争
Google ah don't do that I mean unless
谷歌啊，别那样做，我的意思是，除非
you really have some real unique thing
你确实拥有一些非常独特的东西。
because remember you're competing with
因为记住，你是在和……竞争
this intensely powerful not just the
这种强大的力量不仅仅是
company but the network of Silicon
公司，但硅谷网络
Valley which attracts amazing talent
吸引杰出人才的山谷
from around the world Capital knowledge
来自世界各地的资本知识
and they're all sharing it with each
他们彼此分享着它
other at a very fast clock speed and so
另一个则以非常高的时钟频率运行，因此
wherever you are that doesn't work now
无论你在哪里，现在这都行不通。
you do think about okay what can the
你会思考，好吧，接下来会发生什么
thing I do so for example um you know on
我做的事情，比如，你知道的，在
I love podcasts as you know I you know
你知道，我喜欢播客。
Master scale possible Etc and so I had
主规模可能等等，所以我有
the Delight of of um of doing like
做某事的乐趣
interviews with Toby lutka right or
对托比·卢特卡的采访（右）
Daniel a and what you do is you look at
丹尼尔，你所做的就是观察
part of their success Shopify you know
他们的成功部分归功于Shopify，你知道的。
Spotify is is what how do I run my
Spotify是什么？我该如何运行我的Spotify？
strategy from here like how is it that
从这里开始的策略是什么？
I'm
我是
competitive and and can win a global
具有竞争力，并且能够赢得全球比赛
field Marketplace that Silicon Valley
硅谷的市场领域
doesn't do and so for example one of the
不这样做，例如其中一个
things that they're different in the
它们的不同之处在于
cases because like for example in
例如，在某些情况下，比如在……
Spotify that was hey I can get the
Spotify，嘿，我可以获取
record labels to give me a chance to
唱片公司给我一个机会
start doing the business by doing just
开始做生意，只需做到以下几点：
Scandinavia prove it and then expand it
斯堪的纳维亚半岛证明了这一点，然后加以扩展。
whereas those record labels the capital
而那些唱片公司则位于首都
to do it in the US would never happen
在美国这样做绝不可能发生。
and hence you have Spotify and in
因此，你才有了Spotify，并且在
Shopify it's hey the silkon valley tends
Shopify，嘿，丝绸谷倾向于
to go oh e-commerce is over its own by
哦，电子商务已经结束了。
Amazon we're not going to do any of that
亚马逊，我们不会做任何此类事情。
as a platform maybe you know this thing
作为一个平台，你可能知道这件事。
or that thing but we're not going to do
或者那件事，但我们不会去做。
it as a platform well but they're wrong
它作为一个平台确实不错，但他们错了。
and I can do a long place and then once
我可以去一个很长的地方，然后一次
I get to this network effect of a whole
我逐渐意识到这种整体的网络效应。
bunch of you know small and medium
你们很多人都知道中小型企业
businesses doing their own you know kind
企业都在做他们自己的事，你知道的。
of websites in e-commerce then I am the
如果我是电子商务网站领域的佼佼者，那么我就是……
plat for that so it's kind of a long
为此，平台有点长。
under the radar strategy where you're
低调策略，你
not directly competing with Silicon
它不与硅直接竞争。
Valley companies and by the time the
硅谷公司，到那时
sellon value companies go oh there's a
卖出价值公司会说，哦，那里有……
Manor opportunity you've got it so those
庄园的机会你已经得到了，所以那些
are plays that you can do if you're
如果你是……，你可以尝试以下策略
smart and strategic but you have to know
聪明且有策略，但你必须知道
like uh Toby lutka um like is deeply
就像托比·卢特卡那样，嗯，就像深深地
informed what what's going on in Silicon
了解硅谷正在发生的事情
Valley like when he's charting a
就像他绘制图表时那样，山谷
strategy he's aware of that he's got
他很清楚自己拥有的策略。
connections he visits I mean I'm a
他拜访的人脉关系，我的意思是，我是一个
friend of his right and um and that's
他右边的朋友，嗯，那就是
part of like if you're doing a global
比如，如果你正在进行一项全球性的工作
software
软件
play you have to be aware that your
玩游戏时你必须意识到你的
competition is global there's an element
竞争是全球性的，其中存在一个因素。
of self-awareness required here yeah and
是的，这里需要一定的自我意识。
it's funny because when I was younger I
这很有趣，因为当我年轻的时候……
certainly didn't have that
当然没有那种经历。
self-awareness I thought that I could
自我意识，我以为我可以
start a social network from my bedroom
在我的卧室里创建社交网络
without ever doing it before and I
我以前从未做过这件事，而且
wasn't necessarily thinking about the
未必是考虑到这一点
geographical situation or Silicon Valley
地理位置或硅谷
um how important is self-awareness as an
嗯，自我意识对一个人来说有多重要？
entrepreneur and how does one cultivate
企业家精神以及如何培养
it to know what they what challenge is
了解他们面临的挑战是什么
actually befitting of their skills so I
实际上与他们的技能相符，所以我
think um self-awareness is generally a
我觉得自我意识通常是一种
very good thing for all human beings um
对所有人类来说都是非常好的事。
and um you still have to be irrationally
而且，你仍然需要保持非理性。
ambitious which is I think very
雄心勃勃，我认为这非常
important and so sometimes
重要，所以有时
self-awareness and and just you know uh
自我意识，还有，你知道的，呃
immense ambition sometimes don't go
远大的抱负有时并不会实现。
together it's better when they do but
他们一起行动时效果更好，但是
that's fine what you do have to do is be
没关系，你必须做的就是……
very aware of what your competitive
非常清楚你的竞争对手是谁
space looks like right so just about
太空看起来差不多就是这样
everybody who succeeds in substantive in
所有在实质性方面取得成功的人
a substantial way is good at being
实质性的方式擅长成为
competitive right and and you if you're
有竞争力，如果你是
blind to your
对你视而不见
competition H you're kind of hosed if
竞争对手H，如果你遇到这种情况，那就有点惨了。
you're successful it's just because
你之所以成功，仅仅是因为……
you're lucky right because uh and that's
你很幸运，对吧？因为……嗯，就是这样。
part of what I was referring to earlier
我之前提到的那一部分。
in luck if you if you start a business
如果你创业，那你就走运了。
where you have the luck where
你运气好的地方
competitors haven't haven't identified
竞争对手尚未确定
it haven't gotten you get a long head
它还没让你长出头
start on it that's an instance of luck
开始行动，这真是运气使然。
not all the successful companies are
并非所有成功的公司都是
that way but that's very that that can
那样做，但那非常……可以
be very good and very useful on that um
在这方面会非常出色且非常有用。
but you have to be very aware of what
但你必须非常清楚什么
the competitive landscape looks like now
目前的竞争格局是这样的
that's also true of individuals right um
对个人来说也是如此，对吧？
because it's like well who am I
因为这就好比，我是谁？
competing against is a relevant question
与其他竞争对手竞争是一个相关的问题。
but it's uh you can be kind of
但是，呃，你可以有点……
competitively blind as an individual
个人竞争性盲目
and still be very successful because of
而且仍然会非常成功，因为
the way it works but if you're
它的运作方式是这样的，但如果你是
competitive blind leading a business
竞争性盲人领导企业
leading a
领导
startup almost always that's hosed right
创业几乎总是会搞砸的。
that's one of the reasons why like you
这也是我喜欢你的原因之一。
know the all investors in Silicon Valley
认识硅谷的所有投资者
always ask about your competition and if
一定要了解你的竞争对手，以及如果
you say I don't have any competition
你说我没有竞争对手。
you're like well if they disagree with
你会想，如果他们不同意的话……
you they're not going to invest because
他们不会投资，因为
they go you're competitively
他们说你很有竞争力
blind is there any such thing as an
盲人真的存在吗？
entrepreneur in the sense of you know
企业家，你知道的那种意义上的企业家
people always ask me they say can anyone
人们总是问我，他们说任何人都可以吗？
be an entrepreneur and a founder and
成为一名企业家和创始人
there's so many different types of
有很多不同类型的
companies one can start these days that
如今人们可以创办这样的公司。
it's a quite tricky question to answer
这是一个相当棘手的问题。
but do you think any because there's
但你认为会有吗？因为有……
going to be people listening to this now
现在应该会有人听这个吧
that are in they're managers in
他们是经理
companies they're you know they're
这些公司，你知道，他们是
they're working in a law firm or
他们在律师事务所工作，或者
whatever and maybe they've got an idea I
随便吧，也许他们有什么想法。
mean everyone's got an idea and they
意思是每个人都有自己的想法，而且他们
don't know if they're the type of person
不知道他们是不是那种类型的人
that should pursue it or not is there a
那是否应该继续进行下去呢？
framework one can run through run
一个可以运行的框架
through to decide that yeah I'll run
最终决定，是的，我要跑
through a framework to help the folks
通过一个框架来帮助人们
the um the short answer is no not
嗯，简而言之，答案是否定的。
everyone should be an entrepreneur just
每个人都应该成为企业家
like not everyone should try to be a
并不是每个人都应该尝试成为……
professional mus musician not everyone
专业音乐家并非人人都是如此
should try to be an athlete not everyone
应该努力成为运动员，并非每个人都如此。
should be you have to look at what your
你应该看看你的
competitive advantages are and does
竞争优势是，而且确实如此。
your disposition skill sets path give
你的性格技能组合路径赋予
you a Competitive Edge in this case of
在这种情况下，您将获得竞争优势。
being an entrepreneur right because any
成为一名企业家，对吧？因为任何
game that's competitive right and
这是一款具有竞争性的游戏，对吧？
Entrepreneurship is a highly competitive
创业是一项竞争非常激烈的行业。
game that's that's part of the you know
你知道，这是游戏的一部分。
it's as competitive is trying to become
它就像试图变得具有竞争力一样。
you know a uh a globally renowned actor
你知道，一位全球知名的演员
it's as competitive as trying to become
竞争之激烈，堪比努力成为……
the CEO of a major bank or anything else
一家大型银行的首席执行官或其他任何职位
so it's it's a competitive
所以这是一场竞争
game so for an entrepreneur what you
所以对于企业家来说，游戏是什么？
have to do is you have to say okay well
你只需要说“好的”。
um I have to be uh able one of the
嗯，我必须能够成为其中之一
classic ones to uh to take substantial
经典的那些，嗯，要认真对待。
risks now it's not being risk blind
现在面临的风险并非盲目冒险。
Entre rurs are actually not risk blind
Entre rurs 实际上并非盲目无视风险。
or occasionally they are and
或者偶尔他们确实是
occasionally they're lucky and it works
偶尔他们运气好，就能成功。
but almost all the successful ones
但几乎所有成功的
realize that I'm that when you start a
当你开始……时，你就会意识到我就是这样的人
company you're default debt right by
您公司拖欠的债务就在您旁边
default the company is out of business
默认情况下，该公司已倒闭。
right and so you're trying to get to a
对，所以你试图达到一个
point where it's default alive versus
默认情况下，它处于存活状态。
default dead then there's a whole bunch
默认死亡，然后还有一大堆。
of different things that go into that
构成这一过程的不同因素
game so one is um well can you go get
游戏之一就是……嗯，你能去拿吗？
the capital um are you in in a market
资本，嗯，你参与市场了吗？
that allow you to get the capital um can
那可以让你获得资金。
you move to a market that allows you to
你搬到一个允许你……的市场
get the capital um how do you pitch the
获得资金？嗯，你如何进行项目推介？
capital how does pitching Capital go and
资本推介是如何进行的？
then you get this this kind of flywheel
然后你就得到了这种飞轮。
going between you know Capital um Talent
在资本和人才之间穿梭，你知道的。
uh business realization Capital Talent
呃，商业实现资本人才
right and you're doing that and the
对，你正在这样做，而且
business realization obviously includes
商业实现显然包括
customers includes go to market includes
客户包括上市策略包括
building products and services Etc and
建筑产品和服务等
by the way it's Dynam so you say well I
顺便说一下，它是 Dynam，所以你说，嗯，
wouldn't worked at a large company and I
在大公司里我肯定干不下去。
learned a bunch of things like well yeah
学到了很多东西，嗯，是的。
but you didn't learn how your default
但你并没有学会如何默认
dead you didn't learn how to launch a
你死了，你没学会怎么发射……
new product you didn't learn how to how
新产品，你还没学会怎么用
do you start with a small product and
你是从小产品开始的吗？
grow to a larger product right you
发展成为更大的产品，对吧？
didn't learn how do you set up a team
没学会如何组建团队
from scratch and by the way a team from
从零开始，顺便说一句，这是一个团队
scratch when the vast majority of human
当绝大多数人类……时，抓挠
beings like more certainty in what their
生物更喜欢对自己所拥有的东西有更大的确定性。
week looks like right like I'm going to
这周看起来应该没问题，我打算……
come work at a place because I can
来这里工作吧，因为我可以
continue to work at a place and as long
继续在某个地方工作，只要
long as I'm capable of what I'm doing I
只要我还能胜任我正在做的事情，我
keep my job right in terms of what I'm
保住我的工作，就我目前的情况而言。
doing and so I understand the certainty
这样做，我就能理解这种确定性。
so so entrepreneurs have to do all that
所以，创业者必须做到这一切。
sort of thing so in addition to kind of
诸如此类的事情，所以除了某种程度上
risk taking you have to be good at
你必须擅长承担风险
bringing many resources from different
汇集来自不同领域的众多资源
uh vectors into your vision and working
呃，将向量融入你的视野和工作中
with you so there's investors there's
和你在一起，所以有投资者，有
employees there's customers there's
员工，有顾客，有
advisors there's Partners you have to
顾问，还有合作伙伴，你必须
bring the right set of those people
找到合适的人选
along with you in this iterative this
与你一起参与这个迭代过程
this kind of you know iterative Journey
你知道，这种迭代之旅
um you have to be able to grow yourself
嗯，你必须有能力自我提升。
and learn because the game changes um
并且要学习，因为游戏规则会改变。
like one of the metaphors I use to to to
就像我常用的一个比喻……
train and and conceptualize young
训练和构思年轻人
entrepreneurs is kind and there's a
企业家们都很友善，而且还有……
bunch of different parallels between
一系列不同的相似之处
military strategy it's part of like the
它是军事战略的一部分，就像……
board games thing and and and business
棋盘游戏、生意
strategy but it's like Marines take the
战略，但就像海军陆战队采取的行动一样
beach army takes the country police
海滩军队接管了国家警察
governs the country three three very
统治这个国家的是三个非常
crude broad generalizations about how
关于如何的粗略概括
you do it so you go what's your Marine
你这么做，所以你就会想，你的海军陆战队是什么？
strategy do you have because you must as
你有什么策略？因为你必须……
a C Series a you must have a good
C系列，你必须要有良好的
strategy how you get on the beach how
策略：如何到达海滩
you get you know initial product Market
你了解了初始产品市场
fit how you're heading towards scale
符合你向规模化发展的方向
product Market fit okay you're there how
产品市场契合度？好的，你已经做到了。
do you win the country right the market
你是否赢得了全国市场？
right what how do you get to scale
那么，如何才能实现规模化呢？
product Market fit how is that going to
产品市场契合度将如何实现？
work how are you going to play against
工作方面，你打算如何应对
competition different in these two how
这两种竞争方式有何不同？
do you get up to scale you have to learn
要想达到规模化，你必须学习
this game is different than this game
这款游戏和这款游戏不一样。
right and you're learning new things as
没错，你正在学习新东西。
you're doing it so you have to have this
你既然这么做了，就必须拥有这个
kind of um what I refer to as being an
有点像我所说的……
infinite learner like you're learning
像你一样，是一个无限学习者。
what the new game is because by the way
顺便问一下，这个新游戏是什么？
no entrepreneur shows up at door one at
没有哪个企业家会亲自上门拜访。
day one going well I know how to do
第一天进展顺利，我知道该怎么做。
marketing I know how to do sales I know
我知道市场营销，也知道如何做销售。
how to do uh product development I know
我知道如何进行产品开发。
how to do engineering I know how to do
我知道如何做工程。
engineering operations I know how like
我知道工程操作就像
no no no you have to bring all that in
不不不，你必须把所有那些都带来。
you to be learning what you need to
你要学习你需要知道的东西。
learn in order to do that through that
通过学习才能做到这一点
and and and and that's part of how you
而且，而且，而且，这就是你如何做到的其中一部分。
you grow into that and then by the way
你会慢慢习惯的，顺便说一句
once you you've established a business
一旦你建立了一家企业
because the thing another thing that
因为还有另一件事
brings in a lot of competition is people
引入大量竞争的人
say oh that's a valuable business I'd
我会说，哦，那是一项很有价值的生意。
like to possibly that and then you then
可能就是这样，然后你
a new generation of heavy competitors
新一代重型竞争对手
come in so can you can you kind of keep
进来吧，所以你能……你能……保持……
your position and grow your position in
你的地位，并提升你在以下方面的地位
a market which is the police part right
一个属于警方管辖范围的市场
the police part yes exactly and so so
警察那部分，没错，就是这样。
you have to you have to look and each of
你必须，你必须去看，而且每一个
these three is different games and
这三款游戏各不相同。
there's more games than that but it's a
游戏不止这些，但这只是其中之一。
a way of kind of Simply understanding
一种简单理解的方式
that so uh always being learning being
所以，嗯，总是在学习。
an infinite learner and changing your
一个永无止境的学习者，不断改变你
mindset and so frequently like for
心态，所以经常喜欢
example when I'm talking to an
例如，当我与人交谈时
entrepreneur
企业家
um especially the first few times is I
嗯，尤其是最初几次……
will push them on their Vision to see if
会推动他们实现愿景，看看他们是否
their Learners now one they should have
他们的学员现在应该有一个
persistence and grit because like no
坚持和毅力，因为就像没有
I've thought about this I've got a good
我考虑过这个问题，我有一个不错的答案。
plan this is how I'm going to go to
计划是这样的，这就是我打算去的地方
market I understand what the competition
我了解市场竞争情况。
looks like because if they go oh you're
看起来像是因为如果他们说“哦，你是……”
right I should totally change that
对，我应该彻底改变这一点。
you're like okay you have to have some
你会想，好吧，你必须得有一些
grit and precis
坚韧与精准
but on the other hand if they're not
但另一方面，如果他们不是
like going oh yeah no if we can counter
就像说“哦，是的，不，如果我们能反驳的话”
that yeah we'd have to do something
是的，我们得做点什么。
about that like if our competitor
关于这一点，比如如果我们的竞争对手
started doing that and maybe we do this
开始这样做，也许我们会这样做
right so they also are learning they
对，他们也在学习他们
have flexibility so you want that
你希望有灵活性，所以你想要这个。
combination like one of the things about
组合就像是其中一件事
startups is uh you have to um bring kind
创业公司嘛，你必须……带来……
of this dual lensed focus of things that
这种双重视角下的事物
seemingly are a little contradictory so
看起来似乎有点矛盾，所以
like persistence flexibility another one
就像持久性和灵活性一样，另一个
is right now now long term right now you
现在就是长期的，你
have to do right now but if you don't
我现在必须做，但如果你不做的话
have a long term of how you're building
要对你如何建设有一个长远的规划。
something that's insanely ambitious no
一些极具野心的事情？不。
you're never going to get there if if if
如果如果，你永远也到不了那里。
you shoot for the hillside you're never
你瞄准山坡，你永远不会
going to get to the moon you have to
要想登上月球，你必须
shoot for the moon so you're shooting
瞄准月亮，这样你才能真正有所作为
for the moon but it's me and my two
为了月亮，但只有我和我的两个
friends in a garage right now it's
现在朋友们在车库里。
interesting because the middle bit yes
有趣的是，中间那部分确实如此。
does that matter it does but it's it's a
那重要吗？当然重要，但那是一个
remember like the Marines Army police
就像海军陆战队和陆军警察一样
yeah
是的
Army when you're doing the Marines is
当你加入海军陆战队时，陆军是
the middle bit right okay right right so
中间那部分对吧，好的，对，对，所以
so it does but it's not by the way and
确实如此，但这不是顺便一提的事。
one of again mistakes and that's part of
其中之一又是错误，这是其中的一部分
the reason why there's another chapter
之所以会有另一章，原因就在于此。
in Starview is abz planning the mistakes
在 Starview 中，abz 正在计划错误
is like you have a plan and then you
就像你制定了一个计划，然后你
have a plan B it's like no no no you
有个备选方案，就像“不不不，你”一样。
have a plan and then you have a lot of
制定计划，你就会有很多……
micr plan BS right so you're kind of
微型计算机计划是胡扯，所以你有点……
like well if that doesn't work then
如果那样行不通的话……
let's try this if that doesn't work then
如果那样行不通，我们就试试这个方法。
let's try this you know and and you're
我们试试这个，你知道，而且你是
iterating through them and when you know
反复尝试，直到你明白
to do a major pivot because by the way
进行重大转型，因为顺便说一句
many successful businesses also do major
许多成功的企业也做了很多重要的事情。
pivots um PayPal started as encryption
PayPal 最初是加密技术。
on cell phones right that's that's where
在手机上，对，就是那里。
it started right so you do major pivots
开局不错，所以你才能做出重大调整。
it's when you go
就是当你去的时候
oh my current plan which I've iterated
哦，我目前的计划，我已经反复修改过
for my first plan is worse than my first
我的第一个计划比我的第一个计划更糟糕。
plan like the market circumstances its
计划就像市场环境一样
chance of
机会
succeeding those are now worse mhm
现在情况更糟了，嗯。
that's when you think about okay let's
这时你就会想，好吧，我们开始吧。
do a major pivot so with your analogy of
进行重大转型，就像你举的比喻一样。
evading the beach how do you know what
避开海滩，你怎么知道什么
beach to invade like how do you know if
像入侵海滩一样，你怎么知道
you've got a good idea and how do you
你有个好主意，那么你怎么做呢？
know what a good idea is because most
知道什么是好主意，因为大多数
people as I said listen to this they've
正如我所说，人们听着，他们已经
got a business idea yeah and they how do
有个商业想法，是的，他们怎么做？
they know if it's good and part of the
他们知道它是否好，以及它是否是……的一部分
issue they often have is they've heard
他们经常遇到的问题是他们听说
anecdotally or they've seen that someone
他们根据一些轶事或亲眼所见，看到过某人
else is already doing it so they go oh
其他人已经在做了，所以他们就说“哦”。
gosh it's already been done yeah
天哪，已经有人做过了。
there's call it two kinds of ideas is
可以称之为两种想法：
and frankly by the way you think you
坦白说，就你的想法来看……
know there's over 8 billion people in
要知道世界上有超过80亿人口
the world the fact that you think you're
世界，你认为自己是的事实
the one person who thought of this idea
提出这个想法的人
you may not be doing math well right um
你可能数学不太好，对吧？
so so thinking you're the one person
所以，我以为你是唯一一个
who's thought of the idea that's a
谁想到了这个想法？
mistake right the question is are you
错误，对吧？问题是你是……
the person who can pull it together in
能够把事情统筹安排好的人
the
这
momentum and and pull it together and
势头并将其凝聚在一起
it's still by the way that may be well
顺便一提，这可能也不错。
okay that gets down to 100 people okay
好的，那就只剩下100人了，好的。
well am I the one who's in motion right
难道是我在行动吗？
now am I the mo person who's willing to
现在我是最愿意……的人
take the risk quit my job and do it um
冒这个险，辞掉工作，去做这件事。
and you never really get down to one
而且你永远也达不到只剩一个的程度。
right so so startups are risky
没错，创业公司确实有风险。
businesses like one of the things let's
像我们这样的企业之一
get back to entrepreneurs like I think
回到像我这样的创业者身上吧
the greatest chance and even when I was
最大的机会，甚至在我……的时候
starting LinkedIn after having started
在开始之后才开始使用 LinkedIn
social land after having you know uh
社交领域，你知道的，呃
co-founded PayPal as a board member even
甚至作为董事会成员共同创立了PayPal
when I was starting LinkedIn what I
当我开始使用LinkedIn时，我
would tell the people like look we have
会告诉人们，看，我们有
about a maximum of 20 25% chance of
最多有 20% 到 25% 的概率
being successful right just to be clear
成功，说清楚点。
right we're GNA try to grow that to 100%
没错，我们GNA正努力将这个数字提升到100%。
right but but we're a couple people in a
对，但是，我们是两个人
garage right now right like there's all
现在车库里就像什么都有一样
kinds of things that can go wrong anyone
任何人都可能遇到的各种问题
who's telling you it's 100% now they're
谁跟你说现在百分之百确定了？
lying to themselves or they're lying to
他们要么在自欺欺人，要么在对别人撒谎。
you and and you know like I'm very
你，你知道，就像我非常
realist and ambitious in my strategy and
我的策略既务实又雄心勃勃。
so so you you should never think you're
所以，你永远不应该认为自己是
starting something 100% now within the
现在就开始百分百投入某件事
ideas you go there's roughly speaking
你在那里的想法大致是这样的
two kinds of ideas one kind of idea is
两种想法，其中一种想法是
people generally think that's a good
人们普遍认为这是件好事。
idea they think it's a good idea because
他们认为这是个好主意，因为
you go to customers and customers say
你去拜访客户，客户会说
yeah I'd like that right they go to they
是的，我喜欢那样，对吧，他们去了那里
go oh well hey AI is going to create a
哦，好吧，人工智能将会创造一个
whole bunch of new SAS businesses right
一大堆新的SAS公司，对吧？
oh yeah that makes sense and new new
哦，对，这说得通，而且是新的。
technology trans
技术传输
transformation that or people in
转变或人们
e-commerce they're going to want buy
他们想在电子商务平台购买
this kind of stuff okay you know makes
这种东西还行，你知道的。
sense so there's a stack of things where
所以感觉上，这里有很多东西……
they're pretty measurable as ideas like
它们作为想法来说是相当可衡量的，例如
you can measure them with customers you
你可以用客户数据来衡量它们。
can you can you can do feedback and
你能提供反馈吗？
polling and other kinds of things now
现在的民意调查和其他类似的事情
the good news there's good news bad news
好消息，有好消息，也有坏消息
on this category the good news is you
在这个类别中，好消息是……
can drisk is there a market for your
风险可行吗？你的产品有市场吗？
idea mostly not not entirely but mostly
这个想法大部分是，但不完全是，但大部分是。
the bad news is so can a lot of other
坏消息是，很多其他情况也是如此。
people yeah right and so in this
人们，对，没错，所以在这个
category there always tends to be
类别中总是往往存在
competition and your competitive
竞争以及你的竞争力
strategy generally speaking needs to be
总体而言，战略需要是
why against like in this category you
为什么反对这类观点？
should be expecting competition why am I
应该预料到会有竞争，为什么是我？
going to win out sufficiently against
将会取得足够的胜利
this competition in a global
这项全球性竞赛
Arena I have invested in those
我投资的竞技场
businesses Greylock invests in a bunch
Greylock投资了多家企业。
of those businesses because we do we're
因为我们确实如此，所以我们也是这些企业的一员。
you know one of the best VCS in
你知道最好的VCS之一吗？
Enterprise on the planet you know blah
企业号在你知道的那个星球上
blah blah then um the other kind of I
巴拉巴拉，然后嗯，另一种我
thing which is the one I tend to start
我通常会先开始做这件事。
and the one I tend to most invest in is
而我最倾向于投资的是
people think that you're uh that you're
人们认为你是……呃，你是……
crazy when you're starting your business
创业初期真是太疯狂了
and by the way that can be a by the way
顺便说一句，这也可以算作顺便说一句
and frequently you are right yeah but
很多时候你是对的，没错，但是
but people think you're crazy which
但人们认为你疯了，
means most people think you're crazy
这意味着大多数人都认为你疯了
which means your competitive field is a
这意味着你的竞争领域是
lot less right so for example I'll give
正确性差了很多，例如，我会给出
LinkedIn um as an example and I'll give
以LinkedIn为例，我会给出
Airbnb as an example so l in um I go and
以Airbnb为例，所以我就去了。
I say hey um individuals will join this
我说，嘿，嗯，个人会加入这个
network and bring in their and establish
网络并引入他们的资源，建立
a public identity and profile and bring
公众身份和形象，并带来
in their Network and and use that even
在他们的网络中，甚至使用该网络
as the vast majority of the billion
作为十亿人中的绝大多数
people register for LinkedIn are you
人们注册LinkedIn的人中，你也是吗？
know basically work at companies right
基本上知道在公司工作对吧
they're not starting company like it's a
他们创办公司的方式不像是在……
great platform for entrepreneurs
非常适合创业者的平台
entrepreneurs get it right away but like
企业家们很快就明白了，但是就像
I'm like well I'm working in a company
我心想，我在一家公司工作。
is am I going to seem disloyal to my
我这样做会不会显得对我和我的家人不忠？
company if I establish a profile here
如果我在这里建立个人资料，公司会怎么做？
you know cuz back back when we started
你知道，因为早在我们开始的时候
it like no one's going to use that why
好像没人会用那个，为什么？
well because like they're worried about
因为他们担心……
uh will their company fire them or not
呃，他们的公司会解雇他们吗？
give them a bonus or something else
给他们奖金或其他奖励。
because they have a LinkedIn profile
因为他们有领英个人资料
because they're saying they're dis oil
因为他们说他们正在搞石油
so it looks like they're shopping
看来他们是在购物。
because I mean for most people that use
因为我的意思是，对于大多数使用
LinkedIn now you don't see it as I'm
LinkedIn 现在你看不到我了
looking for another role exactly but
我正在寻找另一份工作，但
back then people do 2003 literally
那时候人们真的会把2003年当作现实。
everyone said to me this won't work
所有人都跟我说这行不通。
because you're individual focused you
因为你以个人为中心
need to be selling products to companies
需要向公司销售产品
okay right right and so I was like no no
好吧，对对，所以我就说不不
I think I'm right about the way the
我认为我对这种方式的看法是正确的。
world can and should be right and um and
世界可以而且应该是正确的，嗯，
so uh I'm gonna take that risk and
所以，我打算冒这个险。
that's the contrarian risk I'm gonna
这就是我要承担的逆向风险。
take that risk and I'm gonna I'm gonna
承担这个风险，我就要，我就要
play it forward and if I'm right I will
继续推进，如果我没猜错，我会
create something that will transform the
创造一些能够改变世界的事物
industry that will be amazing for
这将是令人惊叹的行业
individuals amazing for companies Etc
优秀的人才对公司等都很有帮助
and we can go obviously whatever length
我们显然可以做到任何程度。
you want to go through the LinkedIn
你想浏览一下LinkedIn
Journey we can do that now Airbnb is as
旅程我们现在可以通过 Airbnb 实现。
an investor example so Airbnb was my
以投资者为例，Airbnb 就是我的一个例子。
first investment at Greylock and so and
在 Greylock 的第一笔投资等等
I was at Greylock because David Z who
我当时在格雷洛克，因为大卫·Z
was my partner who was the Greylock
我的搭档是灰洛克。
partner who was my most valuable board
我最宝贵的合作伙伴
member at LinkedIn convinced me that I
LinkedIn 的一位成员让我相信我
should do Venture AT Greylock and I'm
应该去格雷洛克探险，而我是
very close to David and so I bring in
我和大卫关系很亲近，所以我把他带进来
Airbnb as an investment and David looks
Airbnb作为一种投资，David的看法
across the table from me and says look
他坐在我对面，说：“你看。”
every VC has to have a deal they're
每个风险投资家都必须有一笔交易。
going to fail on Airbnb can be yours
在Airbnb上失败，也可能发生在你身上。
really yes because arbnb at the time had
是的，因为当时的 Airbnb 有
so little volume in its transactions
交易量如此之小
that the founders could have called
创始人本可以这样称呼
everyone who used Airbnb that week if
那一周所有使用过Airbnb的人
what they did is dedicated making phone
他们所做的就是致力于制造手机
calls like you know five minutes of
就像你知道的五分钟通话
phone call you know through the through
你知道，通过电话
the week that was how small it was and
那一周，它就是这么小。
David's argument at the Greylock Round
戴维在格雷洛克回合的论点
Table was look this is very strange
桌子看起来很奇怪
staying in other people's houses you
住在别人家里
know like the danger of something going
知道某种危险的发生
wrong um cities are going to hate it
错了，城市居民会讨厌它的。
hotel lobbies are going to try to Outlaw
酒店大堂将试图取缔这种行为。
it within cities You Know da like this
在城市里，你知道，就像这样
is just going to be a train wreck all
简直就是一场灾难。
over the
超过
place and I was like no but I want to
地点，我当时想，不，但我想要
take the v he's like great like we hired
拿V来说吧，他就像我们雇佣的那个人一样，太棒了。
you as a partner we think you're smart
我们认为你作为合作伙伴很聪明。
go ahead right now to David's credit six
现在就继续，感谢大卫的贡献，第六点
months later the trend the transaction
几个月后，交易趋势依然存在。
volume in airbn is like this classic
Airbnb 的房源数量就像这种经典模式一样
hockey stick it was years a very small
曲棍球棒，那是好几年前一个很小的东西。
and then it grew to being very big um so
然后它就发展得非常大了，嗯……
the hockey stick hadn't started yet and
曲棍球杆还没开始挥动，
David came to me and said okay because
大卫走过来对我说，好的，因为
because like they always be learning is
因为他们总是在学习
also useful in Venture Capital he came
他在风险投资领域也很有用。
and said okay you were totally right
然后他说，好吧，你说的完全正确。
about Airbnb and I was I was totally
关于Airbnb，我当时完全
wrong what did you see that I didn't see
错了，你看到了什么我没看到的东西？
like how did you know when I was sitting
你怎么知道我当时坐在那里？
there blowing smoke at you saying this
他们这是在对你胡说八道
is going to be a total failure you said
你说，那将会彻底失败。
nope I'm I want to do this I said well
不，我想这么做，我说好的
look you were right about all of the
你看，你说的都对。
risks about that could happen with
可能出现的风险
Airbnb you absolutely right any of those
Airbnb，你说的完全正确。
things could have made the business
事情本可能成就这家企业。
worth zero but this is the reason as
一文不值，但这就是原因。
investors we do a portfolio because yes
我们为投资者构建投资组合，因为是的。
Airbnb could be zero but if it worked it
Airbnb 的收益可能为零，但如果它成功了……
was going to be huge right it was going
本来会非常火爆的，对吧？
to transform an industry this is the
要改变一个行业，这就是……
kind of investment I like doing as an
我喜欢做的投资类型
entrepreneur or as an investor and I
作为一名企业家或投资者，我
said look we had a plan for each of
他说，你看，我们为每个目标都制定了计划。
those risks we had a plan a we had plans
这些风险，我们有应对计划。
B we're going to try to navigate it
B 我们要尝试应对它
isn't that we could guarantee
我们无法保证这一点。
the risk but the fact that everyone else
风险固然存在，但其他人却都如此。
saw those risks meant that we had years
意识到这些风险意味着我们有多年时间
of no competition that we could
没有竞争对手，我们可以
establish the network we could establish
建立我们能够建立的网络
the marketplace and then once we're
市场，然后一旦我们
there we are the marketplace for how
那里是我们展示如何运作的市场。
that works and that's the kind of
那样做是可行的，而且就是这样的
investment I like doing that's the same
我喜欢做同样的投资。
thing with LinkedIn as I as I founded it
我与LinkedIn的关系，就像我创立它时一样。
same thing with you know kind of uh with
跟你一样，你知道，有点像……
Airbnb as an investment and so that
将Airbnb视为一项投资，因此
category of investment you cannot
您无法参与的投资类别
validate with the customers I was going
与客户确认我的行程
to say so if everybody thinks it's a
如果大家都这么认为，那就这么说吧
good idea it's probably not a big idea
好主意，但可能算不上什么大主意。
yes it it's much more challenging to be
是的，这更具挑战性。
a big idea
一个大想法
interesting really
真有意思。
interesting because it's funny because
有趣是因为它很搞笑，因为
when people pitch to you they say I've
当人们向你推销产品时，他们会说我已经……
asked everybody and everybody thinks
问了所有人，每个人都这么认为。
it's great yes so that's probably an
是的，这很棒，所以这可能是一个
indicated that it's probably not big or
这表明它可能不大或
they bullshitting yes yes and I'm
他们胡说八道，没错，没错，而我
looking for both in my creation of ideas
我在创作过程中力求兼顾两者。
and in my funding of ideas it's not dumb
而且，就我资助的想法而言，这并不愚蠢。
people who think it's a bad idea it's
那些认为这是个坏主意的人是
smart people who think it's a bad idea
聪明人也认为这是个馊主意
you want smart people to yes because
你想让聪明人点头同意，因为
then you have something that's
然后你就得到了某种东西，那就是
contrarian because that's what contan
持相反意见，因为这就是包含
contrarian isn't I don't understand
我不明白，我不明白为什么有人会反对这种观点。
technology at all and I think it's a
科技方面，我认为它是一种
terrible idea it's like well who cares
真是个糟糕的主意，就好像谁会在乎似的。
you don't understand anything right it's
你什么都不懂，对吧？
smart people who think it's a bad idea
聪明人也认为这是个馊主意
right right and then you have a theory
对对，然后你就有了一个理论。
of the game that's a good one not
游戏中，这算是一个好例子，不是吗？
perfect very risk can be very risky
完美主义的风险可能非常高。
about why they're
关于他们为什么是
wrong so I'll give you the LinkedIn
错了，所以我给你LinkedIn账号。
example literally John Lily partner mind
举个例子，约翰·莉莉的伴侣心思
gr I recruited him into Greylock later
后来我把他招进了灰洛克。
he was the CEO of Milla that I was on
他是我当时所在的Milla公司的CEO。
the board of super smart guy friend of
董事会成员是超级聪明的朋友
mine I sat down with him about LinkedIn
我和他坐下来聊了聊LinkedIn的事。
because this is how I go when I'm
因为我就是这样做的
starting a company I go to all my
创办公司时，我去了我所有的……
smartest friends and I go here's what
我和我最聪明的朋友们会这样做
I'm doing what's wrong with it I don't
我做错了什么？我不知道。
want to have the conversation of them
想和他们谈谈。
going oh it's great useless doesn't help
说“哦，这太棒了，但没用”并没有什么帮助。
me right what's wrong with it why will
没错，它有什么问题？为什么会这样？
this go why will this fail and so I sat
这样做为什么会失败？所以我坐了下来。
down with John we had breakfast at a at
我们和约翰一起在一家餐厅吃了早餐。
a breakfast place in Silicon Valley I
硅谷的一家早餐店
said da and he said okay you you know
他说，然后他说，好吧，你知道的。
I'll I'm your friend you it's never
我会是你的朋友，你永远不会
going to work right and I said okay well
我要去上班，我说好的。
why do you think it's never going to
你为什么认为它永远不会发生
work said well look you never grow the
工作说，好吧，你看，你永远不会成长
network like the first person who comes
像第一个来的人一样建立人脉
in no one else in the network not
网络中没有其他人
valuable for me why should I invite
对我来说很有价值，我为什么要邀请
someone in until you have like you know
直到你感觉像你知道的那样，才有人在你身边
I don't know 500,000 people a million
我不认识五十万人，也不认识一百万个人。
people there's no value in the network
人们认为网络没有价值
so there's zero value so it's never
所以它没有价值，所以它永远不会有价值。
going to grow you're never going to get
你会成长的，你永远不会得到
anywhere right and it was a very smart
任何地方都行，而且这非常聪明
perspicacious thought that was probably
敏锐的想法，这很可能
the key thing for starting LinkedIn was
开始使用LinkedIn的关键在于
how do you get to millions of people in
如何才能接触到数百万人？
the network because that's the only
因为那是唯一的网络
place where the value proposition kicks
价值主张发挥作用的地方
in right I knew that if you had a
我知道，如果你有一个
thousand people come
成千上万的人来了
in 900 of those people would be exactly
这900人中正好有900人
like John they' go huh I don't see
就像约翰那样，他们说“嗯，我没看见”。
anyone else here in this network Etc but
这个网络中还有其他人吗？等等。
I knew that some of them somewhere
我知道他们中的一些人在某个地方
between 10 and a hundred of them would
其中10到100人之间
go oh I see what this could be and I
哦，我明白了这可能是什么，而且我
kind of want to play with it so you know
有点想玩玩，你知道的
I'll invite Stephen I'll invite you know
我会邀请斯蒂芬，我也会邀请你，你知道的。
I'll invite some people in and then as
我会邀请一些人进来，然后……
it very slowly starts going then all of
它开始非常缓慢地运转，然后一切就都开始了。
a sudden there's enough people in it's
突然间，里面的人就足够多了。
interesting it's curious and you could
有趣，这很奇特，而且你可以
grow to being valuable so I knew that
成长为有价值的人，所以我知道这一点。
that by persistence through those
通过坚持不懈
initial exploratory people people who
最初的探索性人员
are curious people who want to
他们是充满好奇心的人，想要
experiment with it people who got the
和那些得到它的人一起做实验
vision of it you know Etc ET but all of
你知道，关于它的愿景等等，但所有的一切
that I could grow to your initial
我可以成长为你的最初
critical mass and then it would kick in
达到临界质量后，它就会启动。
the model of LinkedIn obviously I know
我当然知道LinkedIn的模式。
LinkedIn more today than I did back then
如今我使用LinkedIn的频率比以前高得多。
in what 19 no so 2002 2003 200 2003 and
在什么 19 没有 所以 2002 2003 200 2003 和
then really got 2003 is when we turned
真正开始走红是在2003年，也就是我们转变的那一年。
it on Wow and back then was it a social
它在Wow上，那时候它算是一个社交平台吗？
network as it is now where there's a
目前的网络存在一个
news feed and people talking to each
新闻推送和人们彼此交谈
other or was it more of a a public CV
还是说更像是一份公开简历
was a public CV with a search capability
是一份具有搜索功能的公开简历
and ability to communicate with people
以及与人沟通的能力
okay interesting so the network effects
好的，很有意思，这就是网络效应。
were slightly less important than the
比……略微不重要
modeling is today because a lot of
如今的模特行业之所以如此盛行，是因为很多……
people today using it not to search for
如今人们使用它并不是为了搜索
a job or a professional but to talk
一份工作或一位专业人士，但要谈论
about themselves or to share their life
关于他们自己或分享他们的生活
Etc and we knew that we would get to
等等，我们知道我们会到达那里。
Growing Network fact like for example
不断增长的网络事实，例如
Again part of the you know Marines Army
再次强调，这是海军陆战队的一部分。
police is your network effects may very
警方是你的网络效应可能非常
much evolve you may start with no
很多事情都会发展，你可能一开始一无所有。
network effects that's fine yeah but you
网络效应，这没问题，但是你
have a plan yes yeah yeah yeah so am I
有计划吗？是啊是啊是啊，我也是。
right in thinking because around then
想法是对的，因为大约在那时
there were social networks emerging that
当时出现了一些社交网络。
were very FOC focused on people
他们非常注重人。
conversating with each other whereas
彼此交谈时
LinkedIn by design it didn't really
LinkedIn的设计初衷并非如此。
really matter if anybody was chatting to
如果有人在聊天，这真的重要吗？
you about what they ate for dinner that
你问他们晚饭吃了什么？
day so a new network could penetrate the
一天之内，一个新的网络就可以渗透进来。
market that was less dependent on the
较少依赖……的市场
like social networking component because
就像社交网络组件一样，因为
if I go on there and make a profile and
如果我登录网站并创建一个个人资料，
put my CV up it doesn't really matter if
把我的简历放上去其实无所谓
I don't come back for four days exactly
我整整四天后才回来。
because I can get an email that will
因为我可以收到一封电子邮件
bring me back in saying oh there's a job
让我回来，告诉我哦，这里有个工作机会
here but once my profile's up and ready
这里，但等我的个人资料准备就绪后就好了
yes I'm now giving value to the rest of
是的，我现在正在为其余部分赋予价值。
the network just by being there yes and
是的，只要存在，网络就能运作。
that that's a virtue not a bug because
那是一种优点而不是缺点，因为
it was part of how we solved the
这是我们解决问题的方式之一
critical mass problem yeah I I could
临界质量问题，是的，我可以
never understand how LinkedIn did that
我一直不明白LinkedIn是怎么做到的。
but now it makes sense to me yes because
但现在我明白了，因为
I always think God building a social
我一直认为上帝在构建一个社会
network is just asking for like hell in
网络简直就是在自找麻烦。
your life yeah well I'm kind of a
你的生活，嗯，我有点像个
specialist yeah right uh you know uh one
专家，对，你知道，一个
of the First Investors in Facebook one
Facebook 的首批投资者之一
of the First Investors in frenster oh
弗伦斯特的第一批投资者
right I didn't realize you were invest
对，我之前没意识到你也在投资。
in frenster as well yes you
在Frenster也是，是的，你
were part of what they call the PayPal
他们都是他们所谓的PayPal的一部分
Mafia I know you use a different term
我知道你们用的是另一个词——黑手党。
Network it's it it's less it has less
网络就是它，它更少，它拥有的更少
Pizzazz but we weren't really a criminal
皮扎格，但我们其实并非罪犯。
group but Mafia is cool as well yes yes
团体，但黑手党也很酷，是的，是的
people people love the term Mafia and
人们喜欢“黑手党”这个词，
through that time you worked with the
在那段时间里，你与……合作
likes of Elon you knew Peter the from
像埃隆·马斯克那样，你认识彼得·帕克
your days at University
你在大学的日子
um I mean everybody asked this question
嗯，我的意思是，每个人都问过这个问题。
about
关于
PayPal and why it was so successful but
PayPal及其成功的原因
also why so many of the alumni of PayPal
这也是为什么这么多PayPal校友都选择加入PayPal的原因。
went on to become multi-billionaires I
后来他们都成了亿万富翁。
think seven people that that were part
想想那七个人是其中的一部分
in that sort of part of that St sort of
在圣路易斯的那部分
early PayPal founding team went on to
PayPal早期创始团队继续……
create Tesla YouTube Reddit SpaceX
创建特斯拉 YouTube Reddit SpaceX
LinkedIn was it Talent density was it
LinkedIn是人才密度吗？
was that what made the PayPal mafio well
正是这一点让PayPal黑手党如此成功。
it certainly was a component and so it's
它当然是其中的一个组成部分，所以它是
it's it's it's a couple of things so one
这是几件事，所以一件事
um that high density Talent of folks who
嗯，那里聚集着大量人才，他们
are willing to take intensive risks
愿意承担巨大风险
want to do contrarian things believe in
想做反常的事，相信
what their contrarian thing is against
他们反对的正是这种反叛精神。
Common Sense wisdom that's one part
这是常识智慧的一部分。
another part is um when PayPal went
另一部分是，嗯，当PayPal……
public it was one of it was a it was a
公开的，它是其中之一，它是……
technology winter it was one of two
技术寒冬，它是两个之一
technology companies that went public
上市的科技公司
that year wow right so all of a sudden
那一年，哇，对，突然之间
and then got bought by eBay so all of a
然后被 eBay 收购了，所以一切都……
sudden you had this talent group of
突然间，你拥有了这样一群才华横溢的人
people that had a bunch of money in
那些拥有大量资金的人
their pockets and the Network within and
他们的口袋和内部网络
that believed in the consumer internet
相信消费互联网
so the network of Silicon Valley at that
所以，硅谷的网络当时就是这样。
point had thought the consumer internet
这一点曾被认为是消费者互联网
was played they were going into clean
他们播放着，准备进入清洁模式。
tech and Enterprise so if you asked if
科技和企业，所以如果你问是否
you try to Ping a venture capitalist but
你试图联系一位风险投资家，但
I have a new consumer idea they wouldn't
我有一个他们不会接受的全新消费理念
even take a meeting with you they would
他们甚至会和你见面
take a meeting if it was clean tech
如果是清洁技术，就开个会吧。
they' take a meeting if it was
如果需要，他们会开会。
Enterprise software right now then you
现在，企业软件就是你所需要的。
get all the the the PayPal people coming
让所有PayPal的人都过来
out going hey I can f my own initial
外向的嘿，我可以自己做我的初始
idea I've got this great idea YouTube
我有个好主意，我有个很棒的YouTube创意
Right LinkedIn and I can fund it and I
没错，LinkedIn，我可以资助它，而且我
can get it going and then and this is
可以启动它，然后，这就是
part of the web 20 movement this is a i
这是Web 20运动的一部分，这是一个i
i coined the term internet 20 and then
我创造了“互联网20”这个词，然后
Tim uh O'Reilly uh made the much better
蒂姆·奥莱利做得更好
term web to right and
术语网络向右和
so the uh these folks going no no the
所以这些人会说不不。
consumer internet is like that was just
消费互联网就像那样，简直就是这样。
the first wave on the beach the tsunami
海啸的第一波浪潮席卷海滩
is still coming right and so we were all
事情还在继续，所以我们都……
out investing and we were talking to
我们正在进行投资，并且正在与……交谈
each other because frankly we're like
彼此之间，因为坦白说，我们就像
well these these VCS don't get it like
这些VCS（版本控制系统）根本不懂。
this is coming and then of course you
这即将到来，当然，你
started seeing you know YouTube and you
开始在YouTube上看到你，还有你
started seeing LinkedIn and you started
开始浏览LinkedIn，然后你就开始了
seeing and it was like okay like we will
看到之后，感觉就像，好吧，就像我们会……
like these are important things that
这些都是很重要的事情。
we're going to invest in and that that's
我们将投资于此，那就是……
that's part of the reason why the that's
这就是部分原因所在。
the uh Because by the way remember you
呃，因为对了，记得你
know a bad competition
了解糟糕的竞争
right that's one of the reasons why not
对，这就是原因之一。
just Talent not just Capital but also
不仅是资本，还有人才。
competitive steering as part of the
作为竞争性转向的一部分
reason why the PayPal Network or PayPal
原因在于PayPal网络或PayPal
Mafia had such a massive uh Suite of
黑手党拥有如此庞大的……套房
success you know I often Hazard a guess
你知道，成功往往意味着冒险猜测。
that what the like the the fundamental
那就是基本的东西。
game of business is for a startup
商业游戏是为初创企业准备的。
founder and I've hazarded a guess before
创始人，我之前也做过猜测。
that it's recruiting the best group of
它正在招募最优秀的人才
people you possibly can binding them
你可能可以约束他们
with a culture that gets the best out of
拥有能够充分发挥自身优势的文化
them and setting them a vision that's
给他们设定一个愿景，
worthwhile but from reading your work
值得一读，但从阅读你的作品来看。
there's a couple of things just from
有几件事只是来自
hearing you today sales is so like all
今天听你这么说，销售就像所有事情一样。
whatever your go to market is and it can
无论你的目标市场是什么，它都可以。
be sales be to be Enterprise Etc but
销售人员应成为企业等，但
like for example in in social networks
例如在社交网络中
it's usually a viral you know a viral
它通常是一种病毒式传播的病毒，你知道，一种病毒式传播的病毒。
marketing or viral growth plan so when I
营销或病毒式增长计划，所以当我
say sales I actually mean like selling
我说的是销售，我其实是指像卖东西一样。
to oh yes employees 100% yes you must
哦，是的，员工们，100% 是的，你必须
you said like Partners investors yes cuz
你说像合伙人投资者一样，是的，因为
you have to come come on board my vision
你必须加入我的计划，实现我的愿景。
invest in my vision Because by the way a
投资我的愿景，因为顺便说一句……
partner when you're startup is also
当你的创业公司成立时，合作伙伴也是
investing in Your Vision yeah an
投资你的愿景，是的。
employee is investing your vision yeah
员工正在投资你的愿景，是的。
right how' you be good at
你如何才能擅长
that there's a limited set of skills
技能种类有限。
that you can actually teach to
你实际上可以教给别人
entrepreneurs versus the entrepreneurs
企业家对企业家
just learning by doing one of them is
边做边学就是其中之一
pitching right one of them is
投球位置靠前的是其中之一。
understanding the how do I communicate
了解如何沟通
my vision in a way that other people
我的愿景与其他人不同
cannot go that's really exciting I want
去不了，那真的太令人兴奋了，我想要
to join your vision with you and if I
将您的愿景与您结合起来，如果我
was a young entrepreneur telling you
一位年轻的创业者告诉你
right I want to be better at pitching my
对，我想提高我的推销技巧。
vision so I can get worldclass people to
愿景，以便我能吸引世界一流的人才
join me worldclass investors Partners is
加入我，成为世界一流的投资者合作伙伴！
there any advice you could give me on
您能给我一些建议吗？
things I should and shouldn't do uh yeah
我应该做和不应该做的事情，嗯，是的
absolutely and by the way there's we
当然，顺便说一句，我们
could spend the entire podcast only
整个播客节目可能只花这么点时间
doing this I mean there's there's a very
这样做，我的意思是，这非常……
deep well but here's some simple tips so
深井，但这里有一些简单的技巧
one is the mistaken lesson that most
其中之一是大多数人所受的错误教训。
people learn is to try to do reality
人们学习就是尝试去实践现实。
Distortion it's like no no no no no uh
失真就像不不不不不呃
silicon chips to make ice cream shakes
用硅芯片制作冰淇淋奶昔
it's the thing no one's thought of it
这是谁都没想到的事。
it's really big right and people like
它真的很大，对吧，而且人们喜欢
okay what you're convincing me is you're
好吧，你试图说服我的是……
crazy right like you're literally like
疯了吧，就像你真的……
please leave now yeah right so you have
请现在离开，好的，所以你有
to realize that all pitches are
意识到所有音调都是
dialogues right and you want to be
对话要正确，你想成为
listening to smart people and you like
听聪明人说话，你也喜欢
generally speaking everyone you want to
一般来说，你想让谁……
be recruiting you want to be recruiting
你想招聘吗？
smart people you want the absolute best
聪明人，你们想要最好的
talent working with you you want the
你想和你的人才一起工作
absolute best talent working in your
你公司里最优秀的人才
company you want the absolute best so
你想找一家绝对最好的公司，所以
you want people who are who are
你想要的是那些……
thoughtful and asking good questions
深思熟虑并提出好问题
like for
点赞
example I pitch insanely aspirational
举例来说，我提出了一个极具抱负的观点。
businesses but I don't pitch them saying
企业，但我不会向他们推销，说
Oh LinkedIn is guaranteed to succeed
哦，LinkedIn 绝对能让你成功
there's no Universe in which LinkedIn
不存在任何宇宙中的LinkedIn
won't be the Transformer of professional
不会成为专业人士的变形金刚
work and careers what I do is say it can
工作和事业方面，我的做法是说它可以。
get here like we have a real chance at
像我们真的有机会那样来到这里
this now we have to navigate these risks
现在我们必须应对这些风险
but if we navigate these risks we're
但如果我们能规避这些风险，我们就能
going to be here mhm right and then
会在这里，嗯，对，然后
people say ah you're credible you have a
人们说，啊，你很可信，你拥有……
huge Vision you're compelling I think
你的远见卓识令人信服，我认为。
you can do this right and then they come
你可以这样做，然后他们就会来了。
on board with you so one of it is to
同意你的观点，其中之一是……
pitch the huge Vision but show that
提出宏伟的愿景，但要证明这一点
you're aware of the difficulties of
你意识到其中的困难
getting there right now you don't have
现在到达那里你还没有
to go through all of them you just have
要把它们全部看完，你只需要……
to go through enough of them or a big
要经历足够多的考验，或者经历一个大的过程。
enough one that the person goes okay
足够让这个人安然无恙
great I get it you're seeing it right
太好了，我明白了，你看得对。
another part of it is to say this is
另一部分内容是说这是
part of the reason why competition is
竞争的部分原因在于……
important is like I understand what game
重要的是我理解这是什么游戏
I'm playing right here's my theory this
我正在玩游戏，这是我的理论。
is what competition plays in this is why
这就是竞争在其中扮演的角色，也是原因所在。
I think the market will favor me this is
我认为市场会对我有利。
why I think technology Trends will favor
为什么我认为科技趋势将有利于
me this is why I think I have a very
对我来说，这就是为什么我认为我非常
unique Edge and you know in blit scaling
独特的优势，而且你知道在批量扩展中
which I think is another book on your
我认为那是你写的另一本书。
thing uh most consumer internet plays
大多数消费者互联网游戏
are uh what we call Glen Gary Glenn Ross
呃，我们称他为格伦·加里·格伦·罗斯
markets which is first prize the
市场第一名
Cadillac second prize steak knives and
凯迪拉克二等奖牛排刀和
third prizes you're fired so you have to
获得第三名你就被解雇了，所以你必须
be pitching why you're possibly first
阐述你为何可能位居榜首
yeah right right because there's only
对啊对，因为只有
going to be a couple of winners yes and
是的，肯定会有几个赢家。
so like this is why we can win right and
所以这就是我们能赢的原因，对吧？
so um now there's also mechanics in
所以，现在也有一些机制了。
pitching which is you know how do you
投球，你知道该怎么做吗？
tell a story of it part of the thing I
讲述其中的一部分故事
tell entrepreneurs is to even if the
告诉创业者，即使
person doesn't ask you the risk tell
对方没有问你风险，就告诉你
them what the risks are and how you're
告诉他们风险是什么，以及你如何应对
navigating them because it'll establish
导航它们，因为它将建立
trust right so like for example in in
信任，比如在……
pitching Investments now this I didn't
现在推销投资项目，我没有。
know until I started learning it in
直到我开始学习它，我才知道。
terms of mechanic of pitching is and
投球机制方面是……
entrepreneurs tend to go oh when I need
创业者往往会在需要的时候说“哦”。
money is when I you know write up my
钱就是你知道我写下我的时候。
PowerPoint and I hit you know knock on
PowerPoint，然后我敲了敲门，你知道的。
the door like hey give me some money
门就像在说：嘿，给我点钱。
that's a foolish time to start the
现在开始真是个愚蠢的时机。
conversation much better to start the
对话这样更容易开始。
conversation when you're not saying give
当你不说“给”的时候，对话中的其他内容
me money so if you like as much as you
我给我钱，所以如果你喜欢，就像你一样。
can in all of these things start the
所有这些事情都可以开始
conversation well before you're getting
在你开始交谈之前，最好先进行一番对话。
to a
一个
potential contract of any sort a
任何类型的潜在合同
partnership or or a investment or even
合伙、投资，甚至
an employment contract like so for
类似这样的雇佣合同
example always be recruiting doesn't
例如，招聘并不总是如此。
mean oh I want to hire you right now
意思是，我现在就想雇佣你
it's like okay find great talent this is
这就好比是，找到优秀的人才。
one of the things I learned from social
我从社交中学到的一件事是
lent and brought into PayPal find great
借贷并存入PayPal，发现很棒
talent and start talking to them right
找到合适的人才，并立即开始与他们交谈。
even if today you don't have the right
即使今天你没有权利
position to hire them right now
现在正是聘用他们的最佳时机
obviously there's a whole bunch of great
显然，有很多很棒的
talent you could waste a whole bunch of
你可能会浪费一大堆天赋
time you want to be talking to people
你想和人交谈的时间
that
那
you know you either really would love
你知道你要么真的很喜欢
them to join at some point not too
他们迟早会加入。
distant future or they know other people
在遥远的未来，或者他们认识其他人
who would be like that because by the
谁会那样做呢？因为……
way part of when you um when you meet
当你……的时候，这其中一部分就是你遇到……的时候
great talent you realize how to like
伟大的天赋让你懂得如何欣赏
because because you're always you're
因为因为你总是你
always adding new great talent you're
你一直在吸纳新的优秀人才
like oh my God we need people like this
我的天哪，我们需要这样的人
how do we bring them in so for example
我们如何才能让他们进来呢？例如
one of the things that I learned that
我学到的其中一件事是
was you know from social net that I
你从社交网络上知道我
brought to PayPal was at Social at I was
我被带到PayPal时，我在社交媒体上。
trying to hire people who had 10 plus
试图招聘有10年以上工作经验的人
years experience doing the thing that we
多年来从事这项工作的经验
were hiring them to do before because
之前雇佣他们做这件事是因为
the classic kind of wisdom that you get
你所获得的那种经典智慧
from Business Schools is make sure they
商学院确保他们
have experience on their
他们在这方面有经验
CV look they have to be able to do the
简历上要看他们是否具备以下能力
job right no question but if you said
这份工作没错，毫无疑问，但如果你说
two years of experience and an insane
两年经验和一个疯子
learning curve that's much better an
学习曲线要​​好得多
insane learning curve by that you means
你指的是学习曲线极其陡峭吗？
someone that's rapidly learning self-
正在快速自学的人
teing yes okay and learning on the job
测试是的，好的，边工作边学习
and going and figuring it out and so
然后去弄清楚，就这样
when I went to PayPal and I was I when
当我访问PayPal时，我当时
the company was founded I was on the
公司成立时，我正处于公司运营阶段。
board of directors I was like this is
董事会，我当时就想，这是
what you're looking for not this okay
你要找的不是这个，好的
right and so back to your like PayPal
对，回到你的PayPal账户。
Mafia question that's because we hired
黑手党提出的问题是，因为我们雇佣了……
those kind of people right interesting
那种人真有意思。
there was a very limited set of people
人数非常有限。
in the company who had had more than a
公司里有一位员工的资历超过……
couple years experience working within
有几年相关工作经验
payments within banking within you know
您知道的银行支付流程。
because it was the no know learning
因为那是无知学习
curve when you look at your portfolio of
当你查看你的投资组合时，曲线
Investments and the entrepreneurs you
投资与企业家
meet do you think young entrepreneurs
你认为年轻的创业者们会如何与你见面？
realize how significant hiring is to
意识到招聘的重要性
their eventual outcome because they tend
因为它们往往会导致最终结果
to focus on like how good the product is
关注点在于产品有多好
or sometimes Capital but I just looking
或者有时是资本，但我只是在看
at my own portfolio I I often find
在我的个人作品集中，我经常发现
myself like feeling like an old man
我感觉自己像个老人
because I'm telling them that like spend
因为我告诉他们，就像花钱一样
more time hiring not just hiring your
花更多时间招聘，而不仅仅是招聘你的
friends because they're willing to come
朋友们，因为他们愿意来
work here yes aoxy for a Founder if
是的，如果能在这里工作，Aoxy 将成为创始人。
you're not spending a third of your time
你并没有把三分之一的时间都花在工作上
hiring
招聘
you're very much underd delivering this
你严重低估了这一点。
is the thing it's like look uh life is a
事情就是这样，你看，呃，生活就是这样
team sport companies are team sports
团队运动公司是团队运动公司
right if you could just do it yourself
如果可以自己动手就好了
you wouldn't hire anybody no you're
你不会雇用任何人，不，你是
hiring people so like you say well I've
招聘人员，就像你说的，嗯，我已经……
got a really good let's you know use a
有一个非常好的让你知道如何使用
European football analogy I've got a
我有一个关于欧洲足球的类比
really good Striker
非常优秀的射手
great well we don't need to worry about
太好了，我们不用担心了。
the halfbacks or defensive or you know
后卫或者防守队员，你知道的
goalkeeper no no you have to hire all
守门员不行不行，你得全部招进来。
things and you go well I'm a really good
事情就是这样，你做得很好。
halfback that's great you need the
半卫，太好了，你需要……
others too I think when I was young when
其他人，我想在我年轻的时候也是如此。
I was 18 19 years old I somewhere in my
我当时18、19岁，大概在我的某个时候
brain thought my outcomes were going to
大脑认为我的结果将会是
be determined by how hard I worked and
取决于我的努力程度；
how good my ideas were and it wasn't
我的想法有多好，结果却并非如此。
until I accidentally hired someone
直到我不小心雇了一个人
fantastic that I realized yes the
太好了，我意识到这一点，是的。
absolute tremendous impact that an a
绝对巨大的影响，这
player can have on everything yes and
是的，玩家可以拥有所有装备。
that was just such a mental shift for me
那对我来说真是一次巨大的心态转变。
yeah literally I think Zuckerberg puts
对，我猜扎克伯格确实这么说过。
us in a very good way he wants to hire
他想以一种非常好的方式雇用我们
people he would work for
他会为之工作的人
and why why is that because that's a
为什么会这样呢？因为那是一个……
demonstration of high Talent okay yeah
展现出高超的才能，好的。
yeah when you're a young found you're
是的，当你年轻的时候，你会发现自己
somewhat insecure though you think oh
虽然你有点缺乏安全感，但你觉得哦
God why would that person want to come
上帝啊，那个人为什么会想来？
work here or I can't afford them or you
在这里工作，否则我买不起，或者你
want to hire the best people you can and
想聘用最优秀的人才，
by the way if you can hire people better
顺便说一句，如果你能更好地招聘人才的话。
than you oh my God it makes you much
比你哦我的天哪，这让你很……
more likely to be successful yeah yeah
更有可能成功，是啊，是啊
it's my experience that young Founders
根据我的经验，年轻的创始人
don't really think about that because
别太在意这些，因为
they're also insecure so they think I
他们也缺乏安全感，所以他们觉得我
can't manage that person yeah well but
确实管不了那个人，好吧。
but your theory of management is look if
但你的管理理论是：看看……
you're if you can hire someone where
如果你能雇佣到合适的人，那就太好了。
your only management technique needs to
你唯一需要的管理技巧是
be let them
让他们去吧
loose that's that that's
松散，就是这样，就是这样
best like just
最好就像这样
go right and is there any pra anything
往右走，还有什么需要注意的吗？
practical about hiring you know people
务实地招聘你认识的人
say like hire slow Fire fast or uh other
比如说，雇佣速度慢，解雇速度快，或者其他什么
sort of like cliche advice around hiring
有点像老生常谈的招聘建议。
that matters like how important is it
那很重要，就像它到底有多重要一样。
that they're culturally aligned or so
他们在文化上是相通的，或者说……
culture can matter um I would say look
文化很重要，嗯，我想说的是，你看
in terms of and I hopefully it's not a
就此而言，我希望这不是一个
cliche but hopefully a puristic
老套但希望是纯粹主义
principle um uh references are more
原则方面，嗯，参考文献更多
important than
比
interviews right we get a lot of
采访进行得很顺利，我们收到了很多……
repetitive experience at being
重复的经历
compelling in an interview and if you
在面试中展现出令人信服的能力，并且如果你
can't and by the way some great people
不能，顺便说一句，还有一些很棒的人
aren't compelling in interviews right
在面试中缺乏说服力，对吧？
they're they're they're not really great
他们，他们，他们其实不太好。
at selling themselves but oh my God are
他们很会推销自己，但是我的天哪
they amazing in the field they're am
他们在各自领域都非常出色
like an engineer like an engineer might
就像工程师一样，就像工程师可能会……
be like you like okay but oh my God can
就像你喜欢的那种，好吧，但是我的天啊，可以
they do great things mhm in which case
他们做了很多很棒的事情，嗯，在这种情况下。
like like do whatever you can to hire
比如，尽你所能去招聘。
that person so if you if you ask me you
那个人，所以如果你问我的话
can only have references or only inter
只能有参考文献或只能有内部参考文献
interview 10 out of 10 times I'll take
十次面试中，十次我都会接受
the I'll hire the person on the
我会雇用这个人。
references you surely you're not talking
你肯定没在说你。
about the types of references where they
关于它们所处的参考文献类型
give you the references no no course not
不，当然不会给你参考资料。
no no and this is one of the features of
不不，这是其中一个特点
LinkedIn like you want to find
像你一样在LinkedIn上寻找
references that will give you um uh good
能给你带来好结果的推荐信
perspective now even if you can't go
即使你不能去，也要从现在的角度看待问题。
find someone that you know or you have a
找一个你认识的人或者你有的
tie to or as what we refer to frequently
与……有关，或者正如我们经常提到的那样
as an off-balance reference sheet e not
作为资产负债表外参考表 e 不
the one they give you to be a reference
他们给你的那份推荐信
so even if they say oh here's you know
所以即使他们说，哦，这是你知道的
I'm reading here's my reference you know
我正在阅读，这是我的参考资料，你知道的。
Bob or
鲍勃或
Susan you call Bob or Susan and you say
苏珊，你打电话给鲍勃或者苏珊，然后你说
this is a standard question I will use
这是一个我将使用的标准问题
all the time but especially if I'm
一直如此，尤其是当我……的时候
calling someone who's a given reference
打电话给指定的参考人
say look I believe every every person is
你说，我相信每个人都是
a combination of strengths and
优势的结合和
weaknesses and you don't give me a
弱点，你却不给我一个
weakness I will believe it's so bad that
弱点：我会相信它糟糕到这种程度。
I should not hire this
我不应该雇用这个人。
person right so if if you say there's no
对的人，所以如果你说没有
weakness I'll just go okay I understand
弱点：我只能走了，好吧，我明白了。
I shouldn't hire this person thank you
我不该雇用这个人，谢谢。
very much right in that they will always
他们说得非常对，他们总是会
almost always give you
几乎总是给你
something right and you can think
做对了，你就可以思考了
because we are all combinations of
因为我们都是各种组合的产物
strengths and weaknesses like I'm one of
优势和劣势，比如我是其中之一
the best people to have on your side for
最值得信赖的盟友
Creative strategic problem solving
创造性地解决问题
like one of my employees once told me
就像我的一位员工曾经告诉我的那样
he's like I would never hire you to run
他就像在说，我永远不会雇你来竞选。
a McDonald's I'm like I wouldn't hire me
麦当劳？我心想，我肯定不会雇我。
to run a McDonald's either I'd be
去经营一家麦当劳，我也会……
terrible at it right so that's
在这方面我做得非常糟糕，就是这样。
combinations of strengths and weaknesses
优势与劣势的组合
right and so everyone has them there is
对，所以每个人都有。
no one who is all strengths I mean
没有人是全能的，我的意思是。
people tell themselves that but that's
人们会这样告诉自己，但那只是……
self- delusion right and so so you have
自我欺骗，对吧？所以你才这样。
that conversation with a reference and
那次谈话有参考资料和
the reference will tell you something
参考资料会告诉你一些信息。
because because they're not used to
因为他们不习惯
saying it so they might say oh you know
这么说，他们可能会说，哦，你知道的
he um uh you know Susan or Bob they're a
他，嗯，你知道苏珊或者鲍勃，他们是……
perfectionist he like oh so they get
他是个完美主义者，哦，所以他们就……
their work done slowly because they you
他们工作进展缓慢是因为他们……
know like you know like you you push
你知道，就像你知道，就像你推动一样
them because they're trying to get the
因为他们试图得到
one that's actually like more oh they
一个实际上更像是……哦，他们
spend too much time working you're like
你花太多时间工作就像……
oh that means they're unintelligent
哦，那意味着他们很笨。
about how they do the work yeah right so
关于他们如何完成工作，是啊，没错。
you can push them into where they're
你可以把它们推到它们所在的地方
like yeah like they can get a little
就像，是啊，他们可能会有点
disorganized when they're stressed okay
压力大的时候会变得很混乱，没关系。
great right and then you could that giv
太好了，然后你就可以这么做了。
you by the way because when you get that
顺便提一下你，因为当你得到那个
from reference one then when you're
从参考资料一开始，当你……
calling reference two you say oh I heard
打电话给参考人二，你说哦，我听说了
that the person is disorganized like can
这个人像个无所事事的人一样。
you tell me a little bit about
你跟我说说关于
that right yeah got some ammo and they
没错，他们弄到了一些弹药。
can't then say Oh no I've never seen
那样就不能说“哦不，我从来没见过”了
that they'll probably give you a little
他们可能会给你一点
bit more context yes on all these great
是的，关于这些精彩内容，还需要一些背景信息。
people you've worked with specifically
你曾与之共事的人
you know you during that PayPal period
你知道你在PayPal时期的情况。
of your life one of the things I was
在你生命中，我曾是其中之一。
reflecting on is they're all
反思一下，它们都是
independently successful people but
独立成功的人，但
they're all very different people
他们都是性格迥异的人。
and that in and of itself is evidence
而这本身就是证据。
that there's not one version of success
成功并非只有一种定义。
there's many different types of success
成功有很多种类型。
presumably there's many different types
想必有很多不同类型的
of entrepreneur leader yes give me a
是的，企业家领导者，请给我一个
flavor of the different types of
不同类型口味
entrepreneurs you've worked with and and
你曾合作过的企业家以及
and what you know because I I sat with
你知道，因为我曾和……坐在一起
Walter isacson and he talked to me about
沃尔特·艾萨克森和我谈过这件事
Steve Jobs Elon Musk Etc and he was like
史蒂夫·乔布斯、埃隆·马斯克等人，他就像……
Steve's really great at hiring people
史蒂夫非常擅长招聘人员。
elon's not as good as at the people team
埃隆在人事团队方面不如其他团队。
building part but he's better at this
建造部分，但他更擅长这个。
part yes so no
部分是，所以否
entrepreneur wins at every
企业家在每件事上都取得了胜利
game generally
游戏总体
speaking as an entrepreneur you should
作为一名企业家，你应该
try to win to to play the games that you
努力赢下你玩的游戏
have a massive Competitive Edge on same
在同一领域拥有巨大的竞争优势
thing is true so some people for
事情是真的，所以有些人……
example um uh like take an Neil busri at
举个例子，嗯，就像拿尼尔·布斯里来说吧。
workday right he is thoughtful
工作日，他很体贴。
intentionally cultural building very
有意进行文化建设
professional so it's a HR uh product for
专业人士，所以这是一款人力资源产品。
work his contrarian idea was going the
他的逆向思维正在奏效
cloud and the people were going to do
云和人们打算做什么
Cloud software um for the first I think
云软件，嗯，首先我认为是云软件。
it was 500 people the workday hired he
工作日雇佣了500人。
would always do a cultural interview at
总会进行文化访谈。
the end because to make sure that the
最后是为了确保
first 500 people all kind of shared
前500人都共享了某种资源。
cultural things so once you get through
文化方面的事情，一旦你了解了这些，就明白了。
all the competence and all the rest of
所有能力以及其他一切
the stuff he would make sure that was a
他会确保那些东西是……
fit and that's part of how you get
保持健康，这是你获得健康的方式之一。
cultural coherence that's like one
文化连贯性就像……
example right um another example um Elon
举个例子，嗯，另一个例子，嗯，埃隆
is the um like I have a big idea and I
嗯，就像我有个很棒的想法，然后我
convince myself 100% that it's
百分之百地说服自己，这是真的
absolutely going to be the case like I
绝对会像我一样。
am going to settle Mars we're going to
我要去火星定居，我们要去
terraform Mars in our lifetimes which is
在我们有生之年改造火星，这
no it's
不，是的
impossible no no human being on the
不可能，没有人类在场。
planet including Elon is going to do
包括埃隆在内的整个星球将要做什么
that within elon's Lifetime right but
那在埃隆的有生之年，对吧？
I'm going to go all in I'm going to work
我要全力以赴，我要努力工作
really hard I'm going to be
我真的很难。
technologically sophisticated I'm going
我技术娴熟，我要走了
to work work against the odds right in
克服重重困难，努力工作
order to make that work that's a you
为了使之奏效，那就是你
know an Neil very professional
认识一位名叫尼尔的专业人士
understands the workplace Mark Elon like
了解职场的马克·埃隆
I think I was like the second person he
我觉得我当时应该是第二个跟他说话的人。
pitched SpaceX to and and his pitch
向SpaceX推介，以及他的推介
though to my defense was I'm gonna send
不过，为了为自己辩解，我打算发
a turtle to Mars and I'm like that's not
把一只乌龟送到火星上，我就想，这不可能
a business and you're competing with
一家企业，而你正在与……竞争
national governments and like Russian
各国政府，就像俄罗斯一样
subsidized rocket programs and so forth
补贴火箭计划等等
this is not a good E I was wrong he was
这不是一个好的E，我错了，他是
right
正确的
right but there not a good Equity you
没错，但是你没有好的股权。
know kind of play he pitch at you as an
知道他向你抛出的那套伎俩
investor yes yeah right at what point
投资者，是的，没错，在什么时候？
was SpaceX at when he pitched it it was
他提出这个想法时，SpaceX 的规模是多少？
before he started it so it was an idea
在他开始之前，这曾是一个想法。
yes and I'm GNA send a turtle to Mars
是的，我是GNA，我要送一只海龟去火星。
and then it became I'm going to send a
然后就变成了我要发送一个
gelatinous cube with plant seeds in it
含有植物种子的胶状立方体
to Mars because they'll grow I'll be the
去火星，因为它们会成长，我将成为……
first person will send life to Mars and
第一个将生命送上火星的人
you're like okay right what did you
你会想，好吧，你做了什么？
think genuinely when he said that to you
认真想想他当时是真心这么跟你说的。
I thought he'd gone off his rocker
我当时觉得他疯了。
really well yeah of course you would
当然，你肯定会这么做。
yeah like someone's my friends said that
对，就像我某个朋友说的那样。
to me I think I'd make a couple of calls
我觉得我会打几个电话。
just to check in you know what I mean
只是想确认一下，你知道我的意思。
like youon doing okay just told me about
就像你刚才跟我说的，你一切都好吗？
this Turtle he want yes it's like that's
这只乌龟，他想要，是的，就像那样。
not of
不是
business has your opinion of him changed
商业是否改变了你对他的看法
over time in terms of his potential and
随着时间的推移，就他的潜力而言，
ability as an entrepreneur no no I've
作为一名企业家，我的能力？不，我没有。
always thought of him as one of the
一直认为他是其中之一
world great entrepreneurs um always yeah
世界伟大的企业家，嗯，总是如此。
all all the way back to PayPal days
这一切都可以追溯到PayPal时代。
really yeah yeah yeah no look he has
真的吗？是啊是啊，你看他有
done repetitively amazing things now he
他现在反复做出令人惊叹的事情。
pitches everything with the same level
对所有事情都采取相同的态度
of
的
certainty right like you know I have
确定性，就像你知道的那样，我有
this idea for online banking I have this
我有一个关于网上银行的想法
idea for boring tunnels under cities I
城市地下隧道挖掘构想
have this idea for creating a pneumatic
我有个关于制造气动装置的想法
tube for hyperloop tube all of them he
超级高铁管道，他所有的管道
has the same level of I am 1,000% right
那种“我百分之百正确”的自信程度是一样的。
that this is like guaranteed to be part
这几乎可以肯定是其中的一部分。
of the future right and I you know and I
未来对吧，你知道，我
may be the unique person to make it
或许是唯一能做到这一点的人。
happen right so you have to have some
事情进展顺利，所以你必须要有一些
discernment but he's his you know on Bas
他很有洞察力，但他是他的，你知道，在巴斯
batting is pretty
击球相当
good for such major ideas but it's not
它对这类重大思想很有好处，但它并非如此。
it's not 100% yeah people kind of excuse
这并非百分之百是人们的借口
that though if of course if you get if
当然，如果你能得到……
you're if you get one that's big that's
如果你买到的是一个大的，那就是
fine right yeah on the hiring side has
是的，招聘方面一切正常。
he been is he up there with the best or
他一直都是最优秀的吗？
is he not a direct hirer of people like
他难道不是直接雇佣这类人的吗？
Steve Jobs was um he hires well um
史蒂夫·乔布斯……嗯，他很会招人……嗯
matter of fact you can't be a great
事实上，你不可能成为一个伟大的人。
entrepreneur and not ultimately hire
创业者，最终不会雇佣
well
出色地
mhm um I think some people are better
嗯，我觉得有些人更好。
hirers some people
雇佣者有些人
also
还
have like are the kind of people that
像他们这样的人
people would work for forever um
人们会永远工作下去。
Elon uh tends to burn people out a lot
埃隆·马斯克经常会把人累垮。
like there's lots of burnt out people in
感觉有很多筋疲力尽的人
his wake and when you go and talk to
他的守灵仪式，以及你去和他交谈的时候
those people what you hear is some
你听到的那些人的话是一些
people say that was the best work
人们说那是他最好的作品。
experience ever and I never want to work
我经历过的一切，我都不想再工作了。
for him again and other people say that
对他来说，还有其他人也这么说。
was the worst work work experience ever
这是我经历过的最糟糕的工作体验。
and I never want to work for him again
我再也不想为他工作了。
so they're all I never want to work for
所以，他们是我永远都不想为之工作的人。
him again right so you know as kind of a
他又来了，对吧？所以你知道，有点像……
a dynamic because he basically looks at
因为他基本上是在观察动态
them as disposable parts and you know go
把它们当作一次性零件，你知道的。
as hard as you can right and then
尽你所能地向右，然后
afterwards you're out don't care because
之后你就出去了，不在乎了，因为
he goes so hard yeah he goes hard but he
他确实很拼，他确实很拼，但是他
also thinks you're only relevance to me
也认为你只对我有用。
is your relevance your only relevance to
你的重要性就是你对……的唯一重要性吗？
me is can you help me with my mission
你能帮我完成我的任务吗？
and after you're done after you can no
做完之后，你就不能……
longer help me with my mission you're
你不再帮助我完成任务了
not relevant to me
与我无关
anymore what do you think of that
你现在对这个有什么看法？
approach that's not my Approach right L
那不是我的方法，对吧？
LinkedIn mirrors my Approach like
LinkedIn 与我的方法很相似
literally I am
我确实是
referenceable by every entrepreneur that
可供每位企业家参考
I've ever worked with right as a board
我曾经合作过的最好的董事会
member and as an investor right who you
会员和投资者，您有权……
know even ones that I've like fired as
甚至包括一些我曾经解雇过的人。
CEO and so forth those people people
首席执行官等等这些人
will say he was really good to work with
他会说和他一起工作真的很愉快。
on these things they may also have some
关于这些事情，他们可能也有一些看法。
critical things there's no problem with
关键事项没有问题
that right but like like literally like
没错，但就像字面上那样
when I'm pitching an entrepreneur I like
当我向我喜欢的创业者推介时
call anyone that I've worked
给我以前一起工作过的所有人打电话
with right because you I try to work
因为你，我才努力工作。
with people in a way that even when
与人相处的方式，即使当
we're at a at a at a difficult moment
我们正处于一个艰难的时刻
because I disagree with them intensely
因为我强烈反对他们的观点。
about how well they're doing or what
关于他们做得如何，或者什么
they're doing or something else that I'm
他们正在做或者做其他什么事，而我……
doing it in a collaborative constructive
以协作建设的方式去做
way
方式
and so my goal is to work with people
所以我的目标是与人合作。
like anyone I want to work with Brian
就像我想和布莱恩一起工作的任何人一样
chesy you know Mark Pinkus Etc I want to
chesy，你知道Mark Pinkus等人，我想
be able to work with them for you know
能够和他们一起工作，你知道的。
uh the rest of our
呃，我们其余的人
lives what's interesting
生活中有趣的事情
is I think these strategies
我认为这些策略
fundamentally come down to what you
归根结底，这取决于你
think matters in life yeah the most
是的，生活中最重要的事
because you could optimize even you
因为即使是你，你也可以优化自己。
could optimize more for um building more
可以针对构建更多内容进行更多优化
companies or something at the expense of
公司或其他类似机构，以牺牲……为代价
something else and it's a trade-off of
还有别的，这是一种权衡取舍
something else like you could go harder
比如你可以更努力一些。
yes but there's a trade-off happening
是的，但这其中存在权衡取舍。
here and we often because elon's done
在这里，我们经常这样做，因为埃隆已经这样做了。
these crazy things like the cars and the
这些疯狂的事情，比如汽车和……
neural links and there tunnels and the
神经连接及其隧道
now the AI and the X and the spaceships
现在是人工智能、X和宇宙飞船
and stuff we go oh my God that's so
然后我们就会说，哦我的天哪，这太……
amazing and I do that as well as an
太棒了，我也能做到。
entreprene one person can do that much
一个人就能做到这么多。
but we almost never talk about the
但我们几乎从不谈论这个
trade-off yes yep you're 100% right and
权衡取舍？是的，你说的完全正确。
we and and it's so this goes back to the
我们，而且，所以这要追溯到……
point about self-awareness it's like you
关于自我意识这一点，就像你
it's so tempting for the like the brain
这对于像大脑这样的人来说太有诱惑力了。
to go oh my God I want that that's what
去吧，我的天哪，我想要那个，就是那个
I want because you're not seeing the
我想要，因为你没看到
tradeoff you're not seeing the darkness
权衡之下，你看不到黑暗。
that is 100% correct and look I respect
完全正确，而且我很尊重你。
it I understand the burn people out like
我能理解那种筋疲力竭的人。
treat them as disposable assets that
将它们视为可处置资产。
when they burn out you just jettison
当它们烧毁时，你就抛弃它们。
them and you can be very elon's not the
他们，而你可能非常像埃隆，不是那样。
only entrepreneur who is very successful
唯一一位非常成功的企业家
doing that right but for example on the
这样做是对的，但例如在
other side um like if you go to uh Mark
另一边，嗯，就像如果你去马克那里。
Zuckerberg and you talk to the people
扎克伯格，你和人们交谈
who worked for him they're like that was
为他工作的人，他们都像这样。
great that was the best working
太好了，这是最好的工作方式。
experience of my life of course I work
当然，我的人生经历也与我的工作息息相关。
with him again
又和他在一起了
interesting because there's a lot of
有趣的是，有很多
entrepreneurs that are coming Rising
冉冉升起的企业家们
through the ranks at the moment that
目前，各级人员都在这样做。
have kind of been raised on the Elon
我从小就深受埃隆·马斯克的影响。
philosophy of do [__] tons of things do
做很多事的哲学
them intently do them with uh less of a
他们全神贯注地做着，呃，少了一些
regard for the I guess the human
我想，对人类的尊重
consequence do them with less of a
后果是，他们会减少对他们的惩罚。
regard for work life balance yeah well
对工作生活平衡的重视，嗯。
you have
你有
have the nature of this thing because
具有这种事物的本质，因为
it's it's you know you're by Nature dead
你知道，你天生就死了
as a startup work life balance is not
对于初创公司而言，工作与生活平衡并非易事。
the startup game right so like I like
启动游戏，对吧，就像我喜欢的那样
what when like when we started LinkedIn
比如我们刚开始使用LinkedIn的时候。
we started with people who had families
我们最初是从有家庭的人开始的。
so we said sure go home have dinner with
所以我们就说，当然可以回家一起吃晚饭。
your family then after your dinner with
晚饭后，和家人一起吃晚饭。
your family open up your laptop and get
你的家人打开你的笔记本电脑，然后……
back into the shared work experience and
重新融入共享的工作经验
keep working if you say that today
如果你今天这么说，那就继续努力吧。
though you're
虽然你是
toxic the people who think it's toxic
那些认为它有毒的人才是有毒的。
don't understand the the startup game
不了解创业游戏
and they're just
他们只是
wrong right that the game is intense and
错误，对，游戏很激烈，而且
by the way if you don't do that then
顺便说一句，如果你不那样做的话……
eventually you're out of a
最终你会摆脱困境
job I mean the people that say it's
我是说那些说这是工作的人
toxic are often those that have never
有毒的往往是那些从未……的人。
had to do it yes and and look that's
是的，我不得不这么做，你看，就是这样。
fine it's not that everyone has to work
好吧，并不是每个人都必须工作。
at startups working at startups is a
在初创公司工作是一种
voluntary
自愿
choice but that's the game for a startup
选择，但这就是创业公司的游戏规则。
and so that's how we try to balance in
所以这就是我们试图在以下方面取得平衡的方式：
the early days of LinkedIn we try to
LinkedIn早期我们尝试
balance how to to be human because we
平衡如何做人，因为我们
like a third of the company had kids
公司里大约三分之一的人都有孩子
right and so you're like okay like we
对，所以你就想，好吧，就像我们
all have to work this way so we can't
所有人都必须这样工作，所以我们不能
say oh you third you sure you guys can
哦，你是第三个，你确定你们可以吗？
go home and you're out of the office and
回家，你就离开办公室了。
then and then then call in or whatever
然后，然后，然后打电话什么的
no like we'll all go for dinner and then
不，我们不会一起去吃晚饭，然后
we'll all plan on getting back to work
我们都会计划复工。
after dinner so you get time with your
晚饭后，这样你就有时间陪伴你了
family you get to have dinner with your
你可以和家人一起吃晚饭
kids it's the right human thing right
孩子们，这是人之常情，对吧？
but we're working hard and Saturday
但我们正在努力工作，周六见。
morning we're working is there a way to
早上我们正在工作，有什么办法吗？
build a startup in your
在你的领域创建一个创业公司
opinion where you have work life balance
你认为工作与生活平衡是合理的。
and I Define work life balance maybe as
我对工作与生活平衡的定义或许是……
being able to see your friends often
能够经常见到你的朋友
spend time with your family often
多花时间陪伴家人
um only in two circumstances one it's a
嗯，只有两种情况，第一种是……
small startup it's both comp it's both
小型创业公司，它既是竞争对手，又是竞争对手
an absence of competition that's the
缺乏竞争，这就是原因。
general one is it's so small no one's
普遍的看法是，它太小了，没有人……
really competing with you that's fine
跟你竞争没问题
okay right right my screen b a village
好的，对，对，我的屏幕是一个村庄
yeah it's fine right on number two you
是的，没问题，第二个你
have some such intense competitive mode
具有某种激烈的竞争模式
that people can't compete with you like
别人无法与你竞争，就像
say for example you have
例如，假设你有
some like the only thing that matters in
有些人认为唯一重要的事情是……
this business is contracts with these
这家公司与这些公司签订了合同。
three companies and you have those three
三家公司，你就有这三家了。
contracts okay fine but absent that
合同没问题，但如果没有合同就好了。
that's reason because the the startups
这是因为初创公司
that you're if you're in a valuable
如果你身处一个有价值的地方，那么你就是如此。
space the startups that you're competing
缩小你竞争对手的创业公司之间的差距
with right like we had to make the
就像我们必须做的那样
deliberate decision like startups we're
像初创公司那样深思熟虑的决定
competing with aren't going home for
和他们竞争的人不会回家
dinner right they're serving dinner at
晚餐时间到了，他们正在供应晚餐。
the office that's what we did PayPal we
我们在办公室里用PayPal做了这件事。
sered dinner at the office at PayPal
在PayPal办公室享用晚餐
right right and that was a deliberate
对，对，那是故意的。
thing we were one of the first companies
我们是最早一批这样的公司之一
that started not only serving lunch but
那家公司最初只供应午餐，
serving dinner right and then other
晚餐上菜顺利，然后其他
because this The Learning Network you
因为这是学习网络，你
get with SL Valley other companies start
与SL Valley其他公司合作
looking oh yeah we're going to serve
看起来，哦，是的，我们要开始服务了。
dinner too so people don't go home yeah
晚饭也吃，这样大家就不用回家了，是的。
don't go home keep working right to some
别回家，继续工作，对吧？
people this does it sounds somewhat
人们确实会这样，听起来有点
toxic right sounds like oh God but
有毒的右翼听起来就像“哦，上帝啊”，但是
that's not what life's about this is
生活并非如此，这才是。
like capitalism this is people just
就像资本主义一样，这就是人们的现状。
wanting to make loads of money well
想赚很多钱
choose what your life's about that's
选择你的人生意义所在。
fine there's nothing that says you have
好吧，没有任何证据表明你有
to do that and and what gives you the
做到这一点，以及是什么让你……
right to tell other people that they
他们有权告诉其他人他们
can't do that I mean like what are you
不能那样做，我的意思是，你到底是什么人？
patronizing like people choose their own
居高临下，好像人们可以自己选择一样。
lives right so and and people can choose
生活就是这样，人们可以选择
that now you have to understand the game
现在你必须了解游戏规则。
it's like well I'd like to be a
就好像，嗯，我想成为一个
worldclass Olympic Athlete but I really
世界级奥运运动员，但我真的
only want to swim two hours a day well
只想每天游泳两小时
that's
那就是
nice right not gonna
不错，对吧，不会
happen right you have to understand the
如果事情进展顺利，你必须理解这一点。
game you're playing if if you're playing
如果你正在玩某个游戏，那么你正在玩的就是这个游戏。
an Olympics game like someone who's
就像参加奥运会一样，
trying to compete in the Olympics and
努力参加奥运会和
swimming they're swimming seven days a
他们游泳，他们游了七天。
week 12 hours a
每周 12 小时
day right so that that choose the game
今天就选这个游戏吧
and you say well that's toxic fine not
你说，那太有害了，好吧，不是吗？
for you I think the important thing
我认为对你来说最重要的是
which I see some companies doing well is
我看到一些公司做得不错。
just to be honest about that when you're
坦白地说，当你……
on boarding people and don't shy away
积极主动地帮助新员工入职，不要回避这个问题。
exactly no that's like in early days of
完全不是，那就像早期那样
LinkedIn when we were talking to people
当我们在LinkedIn上与人交谈时
we'd say by the way this is how we work
顺便说一下，这就是我们的工作方式。
right we work six and a half days a week
没错，我们每周工作六天半。
right we um do get people home for
没错，我们确实会把人们送回家。
dinner but everyone including Reed is
晚餐，但包括里德在内的所有人都……
expected you know you know you know
预料之中，你知道，你知道，你知道
online working after
在线工作
dinner and do you pay people more for
晚餐期间，你会给员工更高的报酬吗？
that than the average rate or so they
比平均水平高出很多，或者说，他们
get paid in equity and this is one of
以股权形式获得报酬，这是其中之一。
the things again um is you know the the
那些事情又来了，嗯，你知道的。
first I don't know some hundreds of
首先，我不知道几百个
people at LinkedIn all don't need to
LinkedIn 上的用户并非都需要
work anymore because their Equity is
不再工作了，因为他们的股权是
enough that if they choose not to work
如果他们选择不工作，那就足够了。
anymore that's totally fine which is a a
现在这样完全没问题了，这真是太好了。
trade-off that was clearly worth making
显然，这是一项值得做出的权衡。
yes you stepped back as CEO after four
是的，您在担任CEO四年后卸任了。
years when you're at LinkedIn right yes
当你在LinkedIn工作时，是的。
why did you do that
你为什么这么做？
so um I had
所以，嗯，我曾经
um awareness of strengths and weaknesses
对自身优势和劣势的认知
like I know how to do the CEO job right
好像我知道如何做好CEO的工作似的。
um uh and I think it kind
嗯，我觉得这有点……
of uh 150 people or less I'm as good as
在150人或以下的团队中，我的表现和……一样出色
anyone else right like that that that
还有谁像那样说吗？
scale of Co job um is a scale that I
Co 工作规模是一个规模，我
that operates within my strengths and
这符合我的优势，而且
weaknesses um when you start getting to
弱点，嗯，当你开始……
call it 500 people thousand people part
姑且称之为500人，一千人的一部分
of the CEO job ends up becoming like how
CEO的工作最终会变成这样：
do you govern the community of the
你是否管理着这个社区？
company now it's not the only thing but
公司现在不仅如此，
like okay like you know what the kinds
好吧，你知道这些种类
of things that Jeff weiner that I
杰夫·韦纳说的那些事，我
learned from him on was all right well
从他那里学到的东西都还不错。
you start thinking of recruiting not as
你开始不再把招聘看作是……
you going out and individually
你独自外出
recruiting people or helping your hiring
招聘人员或协助您招聘
manager recruiting people but you think
经理正在招聘员工，但你认为
about recruiting as a general strategy
关于招聘作为一项总体战略
for the company and how does that
对公司而言，这是如何的？
General strategy work and how do you
总体战略工作以及如何做
have like for example you get to this
比如，你到了这个阶段
point in the scale company where you
在规模公司中，你的位置
start having onboarding days so like for
开始安排入职培训日，比如……
example new employees start at one of
例如，新员工的入职点之一是……
the onboarding days and they start as a
入职培训日，他们从……开始
group together right so it's kind of
聚在一起，对吧？所以这有点像……
like okay we're going through kind of
好吧，我们正在经历某种……
how it works and we're integrating
它是如何运作的，以及我们正在如何整合它。
people into the different group like
人们分成不同的群体，比如
like you know the sales people the
就像你认识的那些销售人员一样
engineers they all start and they're
他们都是工程师，都是从基层做起的。
going into different groups we like
进入我们喜欢的不同群体
we're approaching it as as the engine of
我们将其视为引擎
the company and the things that I you
公司和我与你有关的一切
only world class but the things you're
不仅是世界一流的，但你拥有的东西
passionate about the things I'm
我热爱我所做的事情
passionate about like the technology
对科技充满热情
strategy the product strategy um the um
策略 产品策略 嗯 嗯
the kind of the big idea for what you're
你所做的事情的核心理念是什么？
doing there and I love working with
在那里工作，我很喜欢和他们一起工作。
super high-powered talent and one of the
超级高能人才，也是其中之一
things that I had kind of learned is
我学到的一些东西是：
well that's the reason I like working
这就是我喜欢工作的原因。
with Founders that's the reason I like
这就是我喜欢 Founders 的原因。
working with CEOs because the some
与首席执行官合作，因为有些
degree it's like okay you're the talent
学位就像是，好吧，你就是天才。
I'm working with on this company right
我正在和这家公司一起工作，对吧？
in order to do that and so I was like
为了做到这一点，所以我当时就想：
yeah I like doing more of being a board
是的，我更喜欢担任董事会成员。
member working with c
与 c 合作的成员
more than I like being the CEO once you
比起当CEO，我更喜欢当CEO。
get past you know 150 people so that's
你知道，先过150关，就是这样。
what I should be doing and what I need
我应该做什么以及我需要什么
to do is I need to get linked in to a
我需要做的就是接入一个
point where it's already you know it's
到了你知道这一点的时候
it's already kind of hit breakout
它已经有点突破性进展了。
velocity right and so you can recruit
速度要快，这样你才能招募到人才。
now a worldclass CEO that you can work
现在有一位世界级的CEO，你可以和他一起工作。
with right and that's what that's what I
没错，就是这样，就是这样。
should do and you know I like for
应该这么做，你知道我喜欢这样。
example the entire time time that Jeff
例如，杰夫的整个时期
weer was the CEO of Linkin my primary
韦尔是LinkedIn的首席执行官，我的主要
office was immediately next door to
办公室就在隔壁
his interesting so you stay close but
他很有趣，所以你要和他保持联系，但是
you yeah yeah again this is another
是的，是的，这又是另一个
point of self-awareness which a lot of
自我意识的这一点，很多人都……
Founders don't have but the great
创始人没有，但伟大
Founders that I've met and interviewed
我采访过的创始人
whether it's I don't know Brian chesky
我不知道布莱恩·切斯基是谁
or whether it was some Founders from the
或者是否是来自……的某些创始人
UK like Bennett Jim shark and Julian
英国人喜欢贝内特·吉姆·鲨鱼和朱利安
from hu one of the things that really
从胡那里，真正重要的事情之一
Define them was they did a low ego move
把他们定义为做了一件自尊心低落的事情
to move out of that CEO role which is
卸任CEO一职，即
typically associated with like the glitz
通常与浮华之类的东西联系在一起
and the Glam because they knew that
还有魅力四射的她们，因为她们知道这一点。
their skill set was in branding or
他们的技能在于品牌塑造或
marketing or something else or just
市场营销或其他什么，或者只是
vision for the the future of the company
对公司未来的愿景
a lot of CEOs don't do that because the
很多CEO不这样做，因为……
COO title comes with a certain yeah I
首席运营官这个头衔确实带有某种“是的”的意味。
understand esteem um and yes everybody
理解尊重，嗯，是的，每个人
myself included does have a big ego
包括我自己在内，我的自尊心都很强。
right but my ego is you you have to
没错，但我的自尊心让你不得不……
attach the right way my ego is attached
以正确的方式连接我的自我
to LinkedIn
在领英上
succeeding right yeah yeah yeah yeah
成功了，对吧，对吧，对吧，对吧，对吧
yeah it's a big difference yes
是的，差别很大。
LinkedIn went public in 2011 with a 4.3
LinkedIn于2011年上市，当时的信用评级为4.3。
billion valuation and then Microsoft
估值数十亿美元，然后是微软
later paid 26 billion to buy LinkedIn at
后来以260亿美元收购了LinkedIn。
the time it was reported you owned about
据报道，你当时拥有大约
11% of the company which made you a
让你成为公司的11%
multi-billionaire
亿万富翁
how does life change when one becomes a
当一个人成为……之后，生活会发生怎样的变化？
so it's funny I try to never like like
所以，有趣的是，我尽量不去喜欢它。
one of the funny things I never repost
我从不转发的搞笑内容之一
things that call me billionaire and so
那些称我为亿万富翁的事情，等等
forth because I try to not have that
因为我尽量避免这种情况。
identity I am aware that it's an
身份我知道这是一个
accurate descriptor yeah right um but
准确的描述？嗯，没错，但是……
it's not like the way I think of myself
这和我对自己的看法不一样。
I don't think of myself as Reed Hoffman
我不认为自己是里德·霍夫曼
billionaire I think of myself as Reed
亿万富翁里德
Hoffman technologist Reed Hoffman public
霍夫曼技术专家里德·霍夫曼公开
intellectual Reed Hoffman uh creative
知识分子里德·霍夫曼，呃，有创造力
you know strategist Reed Hoffman Etc so
你知道战略家里德·霍夫曼等等
I try
我试了
to um change my life as in those
改变我的生活，就像那些
directions not in the the wealth
财富的方向并非如此。
Direction now of course you know I
现在方向当然你知道我
travel around in a private plane you
乘坐私人飞机环游世界
know I own houses in several different
我知道我在好几个不同的地方都拥有房产。
areas of the world you know that kind of
你知道世界上的某些地区是这样的
stuff yeah right um but uh I try to live
是啊，没错，嗯，但是，呃，我努力生活。
a life within those you know high wealth
在那些你认识的高财富人群中生活
things as much of a as an upper middle
事情就像中上层阶级一样。
class person as I can so for example
我能做到像个有品位的人，例如
before I came here to do the interview I
在我来这里接受采访之前，
I got here a little early so I went to
我到得有点早，所以我就去了
the nearby Starbucks had a cup of coffee
附近的星巴克有一杯咖啡
pull up my laptop was working on it
我打开笔记本电脑，正在处理它。
interesting you know because because
你知道，这很有趣，因为……
that's the way that I want to live right
这就是我想要的生活方式，对吧？
uh and I want Human Relationships that
呃，我想要的是人际关系。
are like that I think human
我认为人类就是这样。
relationships are really important I
人际关系真的很重要。
feel lucky to have um relationships with
能和他们建立关系，我感到很幸运
some people who are these really really
有些人真的非常非常
amazing people but by the way there's
这些人都很棒，顺便提一下，还有……
amazing people who are like World
像世界一样了不起的人们
celebrities and there's amazing people
名人，还有很多很棒的人
who the world doesn't know about I just
世人皆不知晓的我
like I just like going through life with
我就像喜欢这样度过一生一样。
amazing people and that's part of what I
这些人都很棒，这也是我的一部分原因。
mean by that you've always been
意思是说，你一直都是
associated with the left side of
与左侧相关的
politics your parents were very uh left
你父母的政治立场非常左倾。
leaning to to to say the least I heard
至少可以说，我听说了倾向于……
that you got pepper sprayed when you
你被喷辣椒水的时候
were a kid because because I was I was a
因为我是孩子，所以我是
kid on my uh father's shoulder at a
孩子趴在我爸爸的肩膀上
demonstration against against the
反对示威游行
Vietnam War okay so that's it's in your
越南战争，好吧，这就是它在你的……
DNA yes the thing about being on the
是的，DNA，关于它的事情是……
left is it's typically the left that
左边通常是左边
have a opinion of billionaires that
对亿万富翁们有这样的看法
they're evil yes I'm aware of that but
是的，他们是邪恶的，我知道这一点，但是
not just billionair I've I've been
我不仅仅是亿万富翁，我一直都是
called Evil by a number of people on the
被许多人称为邪恶
left really yes of course look I they
真的走了，当然，你看，他们
are wrong
错误
that that is a necessary
这是必要的
correlation right um but I you look I I
相关性对吧，嗯，但是你看，我
try to understand people I understand
试着理解我理解的人
their
他们的
perspective I disagree with it but I
我不同意这种观点，但是
understand it it's I mean you you're one
明白了吗？我的意思是，你，你就是其中之一。
of the few people that's still a
少数仍然如此的人
billionaire and on the left it seems no
亿万富翁，而且在左派看来似乎并非如此
I'm not I actually in the valley
我不在山谷里。
especially in the selection cycle uh
尤其是在选拔周期中
well it's the public facing people that
嗯，主要是那些面向公众的人员。
we see on the podcast and stuff and look
我们在播客之类的节目里看到了，也看到了。
so part of the reason why I think less
所以，我思考得较少的部分原因也在于此。
people were public about about it this
人们对此公开谈论过这件事。
cycle was
周期是
because uh you know president Trump was
因为你知道，特朗普总统是
threatening you know personal and
威胁你知道个人和
political
政治的
retaliation and so you had to have a
所以你必须进行报复。
certain degree of courage to stand up
需要一定的勇气才能站出来
right and so en courage in the public
没错，因此公众也需要勇气。
area not just courage in taking risks
这不仅仅意味着承担风险的勇气
and so forth but in the public arena for
等等，但在公共领域……
doing that and so I literally had
这样做，所以我实际上就有了
conversations with billionaires who were
与亿万富翁的对话
like oh look I really applaud what
比如，哦，你看，我真的很赞赏什么
you're doing and I think what you're
你正在做的事情，我认为你正在做的事情
doing exact right thing and that's for
做完全正确的事，就是这样。
you not for me right I mean trying to
你不适合我，对吧？我是说，试着……
get people into it and so um so I was
让人们参与进来，所以，嗯，所以我当时
aware and because they kind of did the
意识到这一点，而且他们确实这么做了
simple Mini Max and they said well if if
简单的Mini Max，他们说，如果如果
Harris is elected I won't get penalized
哈里斯当选，我不会受到惩罚
for not having supported and if Trump is
因为没有得到支持，如果特朗普是
elected I will get penalized so I'm just
如果我当选，我会受到惩罚，所以我只是
gonna stand out of it and do you think
你会脱颖而出吗？你觉得呢？
you'll be penalized uh I think that uh I
你会受到处罚的，嗯，我想……
think that there's a greater than 50%
认为超过50%
chance that there will be um uh
有可能……嗯……
repercussions uh from a misdirection and
误导的后果
Corruption of the institutions of State
国家机构的腐败
uh to uh respond to my having tried to
呃，呃，回应我之前尝试过
help Harris get elected you must spend
你必须帮助哈里斯当选
time at night thinking about what that
夜里想着这件事
might be because if I would yeah well
可能是因为如果我……嗯
look it's a range and look I hope that
你看，这是一个系列，我希望如此。
it's only in the soft end of the range
它只属于该系列的软性范畴。
like IRS audits or phone calls like you
比如国税局的审计或者像你这样的电话
know Trump made saying you know deny
特朗普说过，你知道否认
Bezos that that DOD contract because you
贝佐斯之所以能拿到国防部的合同，是因为你
know he owns the Washington Post and I
我知道他拥有《华盛顿邮报》，而且我
don't like him you know that kind of
不喜欢他，你知道那种感觉。
stuff I hope it's in that Arena right
我希望它就在那个竞技场里，对吧？
could get much worse but I don't really
情况可能会更糟，但我并不太担心。
want to speculate on it because I don't
我不想妄加猜测，因为我不
want to give anybody any
想给任何人任何
ideas right but like I think it's like I
想法是对的，但我觉得就像……
think I would safely win a bet that
我觉得我肯定能赢这场赌局。
there will be political repercussions
这将产生政治影响。
that are that are essentially
那些本质上
undemocratic
不民主的
American um and Direct on you and direct
美国嗯，直接对你和直接
to me yes um I I think I'd safely win
对我来说，是的，嗯，我想我应该能稳赢。
that bet um I'm hoping it's in the what
那场赌局，嗯，我希望它在什么里面？
I'm terming the soft Arena you're not
我把这个软竞技场称为你不是的
planning on leaving the US are you no no
你打算离开美国吗？不，不
no oh my resident's outside of Seattle
不，哦，我的居民在西雅图以外的地方。
and you know we have a constitution you
你知道我们有宪法。
know that kind of thing because Mark
知道这种事是因为马克
cubin was the same right Mark cubin was
库宾和马克·库宾是同一个人
very public and vocal he's a billionaire
他非常高调，也很爱公开露面，他是一位亿万富翁。
he was very Pro KL Harris very anti
他非常支持KL Harris，非常反对
Trump through the cycle he took a lot of
特朗普在整个竞选周期中采取了很多措施
flack as well yes I mean I follow
是的，我也关注了。
everybody on Twitter so I watch it play
推特上每个人都在看，所以我就看它播放
out and it was kind of like he was stood
他走了出去，感觉就像他站在那里一样。
in no man's land just taking shots from
在无人区里，只是随意开枪射击
everywhere and you were kind of in the
到处都是你，你好像身处其中。
same category yes exactly would have
是的，属于同一类别，完全正确。
been much easier for you to just shut
对你来说，直接关上门要容易得多。
the [__] up or fall in line or something
滚蛋，或者乖乖听话，或者别的什么
exct well but that's the problem you
很好，但这就是问题所在。
can't allow that form of Neo fascism
绝不能允许这种形式的新法西斯主义存在。
right is precisely when you feel fear I
正确的时机恰恰是你感到恐惧的时候。
have huge respect for Mark Cuban when
我非常尊重马克·库班
you feel fear stand up because that fear
你感到恐惧，但因为这种恐惧而站起来。
that you're feeling that's you're
你感觉到的就是你
feeling as a powerful wealthy
感觉自己像个有权有势的富人
person right and if you're not not going
对的人，如果你不去，那就别去了。
to stand up who is right can you see any
站出来表明谁对谁错，你能看到什么？
redeeming qualities in Trump I know
我知道特朗普身上也有一些可取之处。
you're Pro K Harris oh yeah well I think
你是 Pro K Harris 吗？哦，是的，我想是的
he's going to bring a wrecking ball and
他要来个大破坏球，
some of the places a wrecking ball are
一些需要用到拆迁球的地方是
useful like so for example if you say
例如，如果你说这样就很有用：
hey on regulation you want a new
嘿，关于监管，你想要一个新的
regulation replace to that kind of
法规替换为那种类型的
refactoring is a good thing um hey we
重构是件好事，嗯，嘿，我们
going to need a bunch of energy in the
需要大量的能量
future and we're going to need good
未来，我们需要好
clean energy I understand everyone
清洁能源，我理解大家
doesn't like nuclear I don't care we're
不喜欢核武器？我不在乎，我们是
going to do nuclear like I can see a
就像我能看到的那样，要搞核能了
number of things that could come out
可能会出现很多问题
that'd be very positive and I want those
那将是非常好的结果，我想要这些。
things to happen and a matter of fact
将会发生的事情以及事实
you know part of being an American you
你知道，作为美国人的一部分……
know I'm going to try to make the next
我知道我会努力制作下一个
four years as great for America as I can
在我看来，这四年对美国来说非常美好。
right my
没错，我的
precise complaint with some of the
对某些人的确切投诉
people I'm in political opposition for
我政治上的反对派人士
is don't ever try to break the country
永远不要试图破坏国家
try to always be building the country it
努力始终致力于国家建设。
doesn't matter if the person you agree
即使你同意，对方也无所谓。
with is in power or not be working
无论是否在位，他都在工作。
towards a good Collective future and so
为了一个美好的集体未来等等
I'll be doing all all of that and I I'm
我会做所有这些事，而且我是
hopeful for some of that from this
希望从中能得到一些好处。
Administration do you think think it's a
管理层，你认为这是一个……
good time for
好时机
entrepreneurs to be building companies
企业家们正在创建公司
with Trump coming into
随着特朗普的到来
Power um fundamentally I think it's
权力，嗯，从根本上来说，我认为是
always a good time as entrepreneurs to
对于创业者来说，任何时候都是好时机
be building companies so one is like you
建立公司，这样就有一家像你一样的公司。
have a good idea the time's now go do it
有了好主意，现在就是行动的时候了，去做吧！
yeah Capital markets harder fine
是的，资本市场更难了。
actually if you can get Capital you get
实际上，如果你能获得资本，你就能
competitive differentiation from the
与竞争对手的差异化
people who couldn't I mean it's like so
那些做不到的人，我的意思是，就像这样
you have to it's always like trying to
你必须这样做，这总是像试图……
figure out how to turn the negatives
想办法把负片翻转过来
into positives in terms of what you're
把你所拥有的积极方面转化为积极的方面
doing now I think Trump will be broadly
我认为特朗普现在的做法大致会如此。
um very good for entrepreneurship
嗯，对创业非常有利。
because I think he's going to reduce a
因为我认为他会减少a
lot of Regulation some of that
很多监管措施，其中一些
regulation will have very negative
监管将产生非常负面的影响。
consequences on the society which you
你对社会造成的影响
know as a society person I'll be
作为一名社会人士，我将……
concerned about like climate like you
像你一样关心气候问题
know you get the new EPA person coming
你知道新的环保署人员要来了。
in Environmental Protection Agency you
在环境保护署，你
ask him what the job is and he says we
问他这份工作是什么，他说我们
need to drill more oil wells right
需要钻更多油井，对吧？
you're like that's not the EPA that
你会说，那不是美国环保署（EPA）。
might be the Commerce Secretary or
可能是商务部长，或者
something else the energy secretary
能源部长还有其他一些事。
that's not the EPA so there will be a
那不是美国环保署（EPA），所以会有……
reduction of Regulation because we do
减少监管，因为我们这样做
have climate change we're living in it
我们生活在气候变化之中。
and it's going to get worse so those
而且情况还会变得更糟，所以那些
will be places where there'll be real
将会有一些地方真正存在。
damage from the Wrecking Ball but for
破坏球造成的破坏，但
entrepreneurs building new businesses
企业家们正在创建新企业
like for example I've invested in a
例如，我投资了一家公司
number of fusion and fision businesses
聚变和裂变企业的数量
because nuclear because that's the clean
因为核能是清洁能源。
energy that we're going to need to you
我们将需要的能量给你
know just to bring more PE more of the
知道只需带来更多私募股权即可
billions of people into the middle class
数十亿人跻身中产阶级
and and to and to try to remove carbon
并且，并且，尝试去除碳
from the environment on so forth so and
从环境等等方面来看，
I've known the regulatory stuff is is
我知道监管方面的事情是……
ferociously bad for that well actually
实际上，那真是糟糕透了。
in fact I have hoped that that they are
事实上，我一直希望他们是……
going to they're going to reset the that
他们要去重置那个
thing and so all of a sudden that
事情就这样突然发生了。
entrepreneurship turns out to be in
创业原来在于
retrospect wise U but I think they're
事后看来，U，但我认为他们是
going to reduce regulation across the
减少各方面的监管
board for all entrepreneurs right so I
董事会面向所有创业者，对吧？
think ENT like that's helpful on
想想耳鼻喉科医生会怎么想，这对他们有帮助吗？
entrepreneurship now they're going to be
现在他们要创业了
probably much more closed at the border
边境可能更加封闭。
and immigration is an important part of
移民是……的重要组成部分
Entrepreneurship you want to you want to
你想要的创业精神
be able to to get the best talent from
能够从……获得最优秀的人才
anywhere in the world it's one of the
无论在世界任何地方，它都是其中之一。
advantages that's helped buil the US
帮助美国发展的优势
that I think is going to be more uneven
我认为这种情况会更加不均衡。
anyway so it's like Goods goods and bads
总之，这就好比是好东西和坏东西一样。
one of the things that is very different
其中一件非常不同的事情
I think in this Administration with the
我认为在本届政府中
people he's appointed is there seems to
他任命的人似乎都在那里
be quite a few entrepreneurs being
有不少企业家
appointed to fairly important High roles
被任命担任相当重要的高级职务
well by entrepreneurs you mean zero
你说的企业家是指零个吗？
experience ever doing the thing they
他们是否有过做过这件事的经验
were doing
我们正在做
before potentially I was referring
之前我可能指的是
particularly to um Elon Musk David saaks
特别是给埃隆·马斯克和大卫·萨克斯
doing I think he's doing Ai and
我认为他正在做人工智能。
Technology I think there's another guy
我觉得还有另一个人。
who's looks like he's built a business
他看起来像是已经建立了自己的事业。
before yeah so uh David Elon obviously
之前，嗯，所以，大卫·埃隆显然
super smart very accomplished you work
你非常聪明，非常有成就，你的工作很出色。
with both at PayPal right yes yeah right
两者都支持PayPal，对吧？是的，没错。
um and now David knows crypto very well
嗯，现在大卫对加密货币非常了解。
so he's the AI and crypto are and the
所以他是人工智能和加密货币领域的专家，而且
pcast person he knows crypto very well
pcast 人，他非常了解加密货币。
he hasn't yet done anything in AI like
他在人工智能领域还没有做出任何成就。
he hasn't been mentioned as an investor
他并未被提及为投资者。
or a like when I talk to all the a
或者就像我跟所有人说话时那样
entrepreneurs you know as a desired
你所认识的那些令人向往的企业家
person for them to work with and so so
让他们和某人一起工作等等
you know he's very smart so I presume he
你知道他很聪明，所以我推测他
knows something but you know AI I think
知道一些事情，但我认为你了解人工智能。
yet TBD what he knows and what he tweets
目前还不清楚他知道些什么，以及他在推特上发了些什么。
about is anti-woke AI is the most
关于反觉醒人工智能是最
important thing you're like that is not
重要的是你就是这样的人，而不是……
that is not even even the top 100 of the
那甚至连前100名都进不了。
issues around how to you know promote
关于如何推广的问题
and build and navigate AI um but he's
构建和驾驭人工智能，嗯，但他……
very good at crypto he done a bunch of
他非常擅长加密货币，做了很多……
good stuff there so that'll be and Elon
那边有不少好东西，所以就到此为止吧，还有埃隆·马斯克。
obviously understands AI quite well on
显然，他对人工智能的理解相当透彻。
this point of speech as well obviously
这一点显然也适用于演讲。
there's quite a big shift in speech
说话方式发生了相当大的变化。
that's happened in the last last I'd say
我觉得这事儿最近确实发生过。
two years really from Elon buying
从埃隆·马斯克购买之日起，两年后才真正开始。
twitters where I I saw a drastic shift
我在推特上看到了剧烈的变化
in globally yes and what we think is
在全球范围内，是的，我们认为是
okay and not okay what's your thoughts
感觉还好，但又不太好，你觉得呢？
on the the change in spee speech good
关于语速变化的良好
bad positive negative um so I you know
坏的，阳性，阴性，嗯，所以你知道
gave a couple days ago here in London
几天前在伦敦举办的
the sir Isaiah Berlin speech and one of
以赛亚·伯林爵士的演讲和其中之一
the lines that I used in the speech was
我在演讲中使用的台词是：
um there there's competing freedoms you
嗯，那里存在着相互竞争的自由。
could say there's the freedom of speech
可以说，这里有言论自由。
to say whatever I want to say and then
我想说什么就说什么，然后
there's a freedom to try to offer
有一种自由可以尝试提供。
something in civil discourse where I'm
在文明对话中，我遇到了一些问题。
not going to get harassed by a whole
不会被一群人骚扰
bunch of
一堆
antagonists right um and obviously
反派对吧，嗯，显然
they're both good virtues and what you
它们都是美德，而且是你
want is the right blend right from them
他们想要的就是合适的混合物。
I think that a lot of folks like for
我认为很多人喜欢……
example what's happening on you know
例如，你知道现在发生了什么事吗？
Twitter and and X right is um just
Twitter 和 X 就是嗯，只是
virulent right it's just toxic it's
剧毒，对吧？它就是有毒的。
terrible like when I tweet anything
糟糕透了，就像我发推特时一样。
including hey you know um I think the
包括嘿，你知道，嗯，我认为
following thing is great
以下这件事很棒
entrepreneurship I get a oh you evil
我对创业的印象是“哦，你这个恶魔”。
liberal you know I hope you you know
自由主义者，你知道，我希望你知道
kind of uh fail terribly and you know
有点……呃，搞砸了，你知道的
blah blah blah blah okay I was tweeting
巴拉巴拉巴拉，好吧，我刚才在发推特。
about this great entrepreneurship thing
关于这种伟大的创业精神
right and that's the kind of theme in
对，这就是这类主题。
you know Twitter
你知道推特
x.com um I prefer what you kind of thing
x.com 嗯，我更喜欢你说的这种东西。
you see on Linkin is like look you can
你在LinkedIn上看到的就像这样，你可以
say critical things but you try to say
说些批评的话，但你试图说
critical things within the theme of oh
哦，这个主题中的关键事项
well that entrepreneurial thing I
嗯，就是那种创业精神。
actually don't think it's going to be as
其实我觉得不会那么严重。
good as you think and this is why what's
就像你想象的那样好，这就是为什么……
the difference in the in the design of
设计上的差异
the platform that results in two
导致两个结果的平台
different types of behavior there uh
那里有不同类型的行为。
well uh uh Twitter is anonymous it
嗯，推特是匿名的。
allows a lot of bots um it
允许很多机器人……嗯……
encourages um like it says freedom of
鼓励……就像它所说的自由
speech like if if you're tweeting a rape
比如，如果你在推特上发布强奸言论，那就相当于在说强奸。
threat that's fine it's freedom of
威胁没关系，这是自由。
speech you're allowed to do whatever you
言论自由允许你做任何你想做的事
want right uh uh LinkedIn is you're tied
想要什么？呃，LinkedIn 就是你绑定的那个。
to a named profile that's tied to your
关联到一个与您的个人资料关联的命名配置文件
identity uh if you're reported for
身份信息，呃，如果你被举报的话
saying something that's frankly uncivil
说了一些非常不礼貌的话。
doesn't even have to be as bad as a rape
甚至不必像强奸那样恶劣。
threat right it's just unil like you're
威胁没错，就像你一样
you're you're cautioned right it's
你被警告过了，对吧？
removed and you're saying hey by the way
删除了，你顺便说一句：嘿
that's not for for the platform and if
那不适用于该平台，而且如果
you keep doing that we remove your
你继续这样做，我们就移除你的账号。
ability to post right so on the Twitter
能够在推特上直接发布内容
example what Elon said is that if it's
例如，埃隆说过，如果是……
legal then it's fine
如果合法，那就没问题。
but is there an upside to having an
但是拥有一个
environment where people can anonymously
人们可以匿名的环境
say what they want within the constraint
在限制范围内，畅所欲言
of the
的
law um look I think there
法律，嗯，你看，我想那里
are it's important to allow one of the
允许其中之一很重要
things I think that online platforms
我认为在线平台的一些事情
give us the difference between freedom
请告诉我们自由与自由之间的区别。
of speech and freedom of reach like I
言论自由和获取自由，就像我一样
think it's okay for people to say such
认为人们这样说是可以的。
thing as vaccines are evil plots to put
把疫苗说成是邪恶的阴谋，目的是为了……
chips in people and they give us
人们身上的芯片，以及他们给予我们的
autism it's
自闭症是
100% wrong right and every credible
100% 错误，对，而且每个可信的
medical Authority goes vaccines are good
医疗权威机构认为疫苗是好的
and so you go okay a thousand people get
所以，你就会想，好吧，一千人会怎样？
vaccinated or call it you know a 100,00
接种疫苗，或者你知道的，100,000
people get vaccinated and 50 of them
人们接种了疫苗，其中50人
have adverse conditions to the vaccine
对疫苗有不利影响
right that happens out of 100,000 right
对，这种情况发生的概率是十万分之一。
but a thousand people or 10,000 people
但一千人或一万人
might have died otherwise right
否则可能就死了，对吧？
that your lottery for everyone being
你的彩票对每个人来说都是如此
vaccinated is a very good Lottery
接种疫苗的人中彩票非常好
everyone should do it right uh Because
每个人都应该这样做，因为
by the way you were more likely to have
顺便说一句，你更有可能拥有
died in the lottery than have an adverse
死于彩票比遭遇不幸更糟糕
condition that doesn't mean there aren't
这种情况并不意味着没有
people who have adverse conditions so
那些身处逆境的人
all quality medical professionals
所有高素质的医疗专业人员
medical researchers agree I am allowed
医学研究人员一致认为我被允许
legally on x.com to say vaccines are
在 x.com 上合法地宣称疫苗是
evil plots right to control
邪恶阴谋，控制权
the American people to sell drugs and
美国人民贩卖毒品
make drug companies profitable and blah
让制药公司盈利等等
blah and I can say all that and you see
等等，我可以把这些都说出来，你看
all that ramping on Twitter rampant you
推特上那些疯狂的言论真是让人抓狂。
know in talk radio and you know and all
在广播谈话节目里，你也知道这一切。
the things you can say that that's a
你可以说，那是一种
problem right I'm okay with people
问题是，我和人相处没问题。
saying it what I'm not okay with is
说出这句话，我最不能接受的是……
promoting it and having it have broad
推广它并使其拥有广泛的影响力
reach so on this point of the vaccine so
就目前疫苗的情况而言，已经达到这个程度了。
just to clarify my position I think
为了澄清我的立场，我认为
vaccines are a wonderful invention that
疫苗是一项伟大的发明，
have saved a lot of people's lives so
已经拯救了很多人的生命
that's my position but I want to I want
那是我的立场，但我想要，我想要
to interrogate a little bit with the
稍微询问一下
with the vaccine roll out in particular
尤其是在疫苗推广方面。
there's a lot of things that we didn't
有很多事情我们没有做到。
know at the time right the lab leap
当时就知道实验室的飞跃
thing I had Boris Johnson sat here and
我当时想，鲍里斯·约翰逊应该坐在这里。
he said oh yeah we think it's a lab Lab
他说，哦，是的，我们认为这是一个实验室。
leak if if if I had said that on this
如果我说过那样的话，就会泄露出去。
podcast a couple of years ago I would
几年前我做播客的时候会
have been kicked off YouTube uhuh yes
被 YouTube 封号了，嗯哼，是的
and so having a forum where you can even
因此，拥有一个可以让你畅所欲言的论坛，甚至
entertain ideas that are contrarian yes
是的，要乐于接受与主流观点相悖的想法。
I also think is important and I exist in
我也认为这很重要，而我存在于……
the the sort of dichotomy of like speech
这种二分法类似于言语的差异。
is important but at the same
很重要，但同时
time you know yeah look I am um I was on
你知道，时间到了，嗯，你看，我当时在……
the support people being able to say lab
支持人员能够说实验室
leak yeah category Because by the way I
泄露类别 因为顺便说一句，我
do think freedom of speech is a good
我确实认为言论自由是一件好事。
thing and part of the reason I have
这件事，也是我拥有的部分原因。
freedom of speech is sometimes you have
言论自由有时意味着你有
a contrarian idea that should have
一个本应如此的逆向思维
freedom of reach yeah but there should
行动自由是的，但是应该
be and look how do we make decisions as
看看我们如何做出决定
a society of what expertise like how
一个拥有专业知识的社会，例如如何
what truth is as we convene groups of
当我们召集各方人士时，真理是什么？
experts MH like in a science we have a
专家MH就像在科学领域一样，我们拥有
group of scientists review a paper
一组科学家审阅一篇论文
before it's published we have scientists
在发表之前，我们有科学家
able to reproduce things in a jury we
能够在陪审团中重现事物我们
have 12 people who listen to the case
有12个人听取此案
and make a decision so we use groups of
并做出决定，以便我们使用小组
people as experts and different kinds of
人们作为专家和不同类型的
expertise for different kinds of things
不同领域的专业知识
to make a judgment and we should also
做出判断，我们也应该这样做。
bring in expertise right right now that
立即引入这方面的专业知识
doesn't mean that even when all the
但这并不意味着即使所有……
experts say that's completely wrong you
专家说你的说法完全错误。
should say you can't post it like I
应该说你不能像这样发布它
loved what Twitter did pre Elon which is
我喜欢埃隆·马斯克之前推特的风格。
they said hey you can post vaccines or
他们说，嘿，你可以发布疫苗信息或
this evil plot by the government to
政府的这个邪恶阴谋
control you but we're going to put a
控制你，但我们会放一个
little box around it that says oh and by
周围有个小方框，上面写着“哦，还有”。
the way experts disagree here's where
专家们分歧之处就在这里。
you can go get the facts so you can say
你可以去了解事实，这样你就可以说了。
it right but we'll also put in in
没错，但我们也会把它放进去
selective cases expert opinion and I
选择性案例专家意见和我
think that's like for example a balance
想想这就像平衡一样。
of how to do freedom of speech and
关于如何行使言论自由和
freedom of reach because I do think look
自由触及，因为我确实认为看
I should be a to say the World is Flat I
我应该说“世界是平的”才对。
should be able to go on and say the
应该能够继续说下去
world is flat and by the way LinkedIn
世界是平的，顺便提一下LinkedIn。
wouldn't take that post off because it's
不会删除那篇帖子，因为它……
like well it's civil I'm just saying the
嗯，这很文明，我只是说说而已。
world flat I'm out of my mind right but
世界是平的？我疯了吧？
I'm being civil so the LinkedIn
我态度客气，所以LinkedIn
principles are not you must say
原则不是你必须说的。
something that's scientific truly true
一些真正符合科学事实的事情
it's you must say something that's civil
你必须说些文明的话。
I also think people shouldn't be
我也认为人们不应该
deplatformed or canceled because of
因以下原因被封禁或取消：
their speech even if you disagree with
即使你不同意他们的观点，他们也应该接受他们的言论。
it providing it's in the constraint like
它前提是它符合约束条件，例如
constrains of the law I sat with a well
法律的约束，我与一位井
by the way I generally think agree on
顺便说一句，我总体上同意……
the constrains of the law but I also
法律的限制，但我也
agree on I also think importantly civil
同意，我也认为文明很重要。
and civil means well like no threat of
而文明意味着没有威胁
violence okay yeah I agree with that you
暴力？好吧，我同意你的观点。
shouldn't be threatening anybody with
不应该用这种方式威胁任何人
violence yes um I sat with a I'm GNA say
暴力，是的，嗯，我和GNA坐在一起说
astrologist I don't even know if that's
我甚至不知道那是不是占星家
the right word it's not astrology was it
用词恰当，但这不是占星术，对吧？
who's BR what's cosmetologist and he
BR是谁？美容师是什么？还有他
told me the story of Galileo discovering
他给我讲了伽利略发现地球的故事。
that the world was round and Galileo
世界是圆的，以及伽利略
basically being threatened by everybody
基本上受到所有人的威胁
um because it threatened the I think the
嗯，因为它威胁到了我认为的
Catholic institution at the time and
当时的天主教机构
then well because the preach the
那么，因为他们宣扬……
preaching of the church was as was that
教会的布道就是这样。
yeah and so that's a cautionary tale
是的，所以这是一个警示故事。
although it's a long time ago in there
虽然那是很久以前的事了。
are always going to be strong forces
它们始终都会是强大的力量。
that are heavily incentivized around
围绕这些方面有大量的激励措施
some kind of ideology yes and that I
是的，某种意识形态，而且我
mean that does happen today yes 100% And
意思是说，今天这种情况确实会发生，百分之百会发生。
and these forces are powerful forces um
而且这些力量非常强大。
so allowing dissent even if it's coming
所以即使异议即将到来，也要允许它存在。
from someone who is not credible yes
来自一个不可信的人，是的。
100% by way strongly in defense of that
百分之百强烈捍卫这一点
yeah right I just think that and like so
对啊，我就是这么想的，而且……
you know I don't
你知道我不知道
mind um people criticizing me I don't
我不介意别人批评我。
mind them criticizing my arguments I
别在意他们批评我的论点
don't mind them criticizing my choices
别在意他们批评我的选择
of who I'm going to support
我将支持谁
politically right what I'm going to do
我将要做的事情在政治上是正确的。
philanthropically I strongly prefer that
从慈善角度来说，我强烈倾向于这样做。
those cred those those criticisms be
那些信誉，那些批评，
backed
支持的
with uh some knowledge and intelligence
具备一定的知识和智力
and some argu good argument point of
有些人认为这是一个很好的论点。
view and I really want it to be a civil
观点，我真的希望它是一种文明的
discourse it's interesting because the
讨论之所以有趣，是因为……
human brain when we think about it from
当我们思考人脑时
an evolutionary standpoint wasn't
从进化论的角度来看，并非如此。
designed to deal with a thousand people
旨在应对一千人
tweeting at you that you're you're an
发推文告诉你，你是一个
[__] and as a podcaster as someone
混蛋，而且作为一名播客主播，他
who's in the public high yourself who is
谁在公众视野中处于高位？你自己是谁？
a podcaster but also a famous
一位播客主播，也是一位知名人士
entrepreneur you have to deal with that
企业家，你必须面对这个问题。
like you you have to deal with that in a
就像你一样，你也必须处理这件事。
way that's just we weren't designed to
我们生来就不是为了这样而存在的。
yeah and I struggle with it I struggle
是的，我在这方面很挣扎，我很难做到。
with when I first came into the public
当我第一次进入公众视野时
spot like when I started doing Dragon's
就像我开始做龙的时候一样
Den Shar tank in the US um opening my
Den Shar 坦克在美国嗯打开我的
phone and being exposed to just a
手机以及仅仅接触到
barrage of like noise on the brain yes
是的，就像大脑被噪音轰炸一样。
now whose responsibility is that is it
现在，这究竟是谁的责任呢？
my responsibility to like delete the app
我有责任删除这个应用。
or is it the platform's responsibility
或者这是平台的责任？
to moderate people expressing their
缓和人们表达他们的
innate human jealous whatever it is you
人类与生俱来的嫉妒，无论它是什么。
know so so the classic thing that humans
知道这一点，所以人类的经典之事
make in reasoning is they go A or B
推理过程是他们选择A还是B
right okay and you answer is both okay
好的，你的答案都是好的
right so there's responsibility on both
对，所以双方都有责任。
sides like it's like oh no it's a
就像是“哦不，这是……”
responsibility of the individuals like
个人的责任
well like are you kind of saying I have
嗯，你的意思是说我有
zero responsibility there's zero I can
零责任，我什么都做不了。
do to be positively contributory here of
务必在此做出积极贡献
course you can right so for example like
当然你可以对，例如像这样
it's totally possible to say I have a
完全可以说我有一个
freedom of speech Network and if you
言论自由网络，以及如果您
were engaging in threats like for
参与诸如此类的威胁
example your Trump and you're tweeting
举个例子，你和特朗普在推特上
that Mark Millie should be executed when
马克·米利应该被处决
he is the joint chief of staff's General
他是联合参谋长的将军
that's a threat of violence that should
那是暴力威胁，应该予以制止。
be removed right you know so it's
会被移除，你知道的，就是这样。
totally doable to say violence has no
完全可以说暴力没有
place on this platform or threats of
在本平台上放置或威胁
violence now violence is illegal threats
暴力，现在的暴力是非法的威胁
of violence is not right one of the
暴力是不对的，其中之一
theories I had many years ago and I I
我多年前的一些理论，以及我
don't actually think this theory was
我并不认为这个理论是真的
based on anything other than I read it
除了我读过之外的任何其他依据
and it sounded good so I used to say it
听起来不错，所以我以前常这么说。
was that over the next 10 years and I
接下来的十年里，我
used to say this about six seven years
大约六七年前我经常这么说。
ago on stage social network working
很久以前在舞台上参与社交网络工作
would become more and more siloed into
会变得越来越孤立
these smaller interest based networks I
这些较小的基于兴趣的网络
was thinking the other day in the taxi I
前几天在出租车上，我一直在想这件事。
was like oh my God that's actually
当时我就想，我的天哪，这竟然是真的
happening now you're having like blue
现在你感觉像在做蓝梦
sky and threads and you've got your
天空和线，你就拥有了你的
Instagrams and your rumbles and we've
Instagram 和你的抱怨，还有我们……
got more and more social networks that
越来越多的社交网络
are more like centered around different
更像是围绕不同的
pockets of people what is your theory of
你对这群人的理论是什么？
social networking over the next decade
未来十年社交网络的发展
two decades I'm always open as an
二十年来，我一直保持开放的态度
investor to interesting ideas yeah right
投资者对有趣的想法？是吗？
here we are in a business podcast so I'm
我们现在正在录制商业播客，所以我……
always looking at stuff um look I think
总是看着一些东西，嗯，你看，我想
uh they will grow to be an increasingly
呃，它们会逐渐发展成越来越……
just as they've grown massively in the
正如它们在……方面已经大幅增长一样
last 20 years they will continue to grow
未来20年它们将继续增长
to be an important part of life I think
我认为，这将成为生活中重要的一部分。
there will be different social networks
将会有不同的社交网络
that fit different parts of our Lives um
适合我们生活的不同方面
that's part of the reason like for
那是部分原因，比如……
example like back when I started
举个例子，就像我刚开始的时候那样
LinkedIn it was also thought to be oh no
LinkedIn也被认为是糟糕的选择。
no no one's ever going to do a business
不，没人会做生意。
Network it's only going to be social
网络只会是社交的
networks right it was only going to be
网络是正确的，它只会是
at the time it was like Friendster then
当时它就像是Friendster。
it was Myspace then it was Facebook like
先是Myspace，然后是Facebook，就像……
look there's only going to be that
你看，就只有这些了。
there's never going to be those and then
永远不会有那种情况，然后
people say well there's only going to
人们说，好吧，只会……
ever be one social network and you're
你曾经是某个社交网络的一员吗？
like well actually in fact we do have
实际上，我们确实有
like Twitter we do have snap and we do
就像Twitter一样，我们也有Snapchat，而且我们确实
have right there's there is multiple
就在那里，有多个
ones and I think there will be more um
一个，而且我认为还会有更多。
so I think they're going to have more
所以我认为他们会有更多。
social networks and they're going to fit
社交网络，它们将会契合
into different people's lives they're
他们进入了不同人的生活
going to have different Community
将会有不同的社区
cultures
文化
um for them and so and I think not only
嗯，对他们来说，所以，而且我认为不仅如此。
will they get multimodal but they'll use
他们会采用多模态模式吗？但他们会使用
AI in different ways and so and part of
人工智能以不同的方式发挥作用，并且是其中的一部分
that invention like one of the things I
那项发明就像我拥有的​​东西之一。
tend to think people say well what ideas
人们往往会说，嗯，有什么想法？
are you looking at as an investor and
您是以投资者的身份来看待这个问题的吗？
I'm like look I'm looking for that great
我心想，你看，我正在寻找那个伟大的
idea that I haven't thought of that
我之前没想到的这个想法
someone out there amongst the millions
在茫茫人海中，总会有人存在。
of entrepreneurs has got that great
企业家们拥有那种伟大的特质。
thing and can possibly make it work
这件事或许能成真。
that's what I'm looking for so when I
这就是我想要的，所以当我
look to future of social networks now to
现在就展望社交网络的未来
give a little bit more of a specific
再具体一点
answer like I tend to think social
回答就像我倾向于思考社交问题一样
networks need to both have individuals
网络既需要个人
as customers and societies as customers
作为顾客和社会作为顾客
so you need to think about like that
所以你需要这样想。
balance of you need to think about both
你需要权衡两者。
in how you're designing them right so
你设计它们的方式对吧？
it's and that doesn't mean no freedom of
确实如此，但这并不意味着没有自由。
speech and you know autocratic because I
演讲，你知道独裁，因为我
actually think more or less she should
实际上，我认为她应该或多或少应该
allow people to post whatever they want
允许人们发布任何他们想发布的内容
as long as it's civil right and if you
只要这是公民权利，而且如果你
want to choose to have an anonymous
想选择匿名
social network that's fine like there's
社交网络还不错，就像……
a definite rule for especially when you
尤其是在以下情况下，这是一条明确的规则：
get to places where the government is
到达政府所在地
oppressed
受压迫者
you know go to in Iran or or or Russia
你知道去伊朗或者俄罗斯吗？
or something else he like well anonymity
或者他喜欢的其他东西，比如匿名。
is important for saving your life right
这对于挽救你的生命至关重要。
but on the other hand you should also be
但另一方面，你也应该
thinking about like okay what do this
想着，好吧，接下来该怎么做
means as society and part of what we
这意味着作为社会的一部分，也是我们的一部分
want in media networks is we want to be
我们希望在媒体网络中成为……
collectively learning so if I'm posting
集体学习，所以如果我发帖
that you know vaccines are an evil plot
你知道疫苗是邪恶的阴谋
for corporations to try to kill our
企业试图扼杀我们
children you're like well you're trying
孩子们，你们就像在说，好吧，你们正在努力
to persuade people to do something
说服人们做某事
that's bad for them and bad for society
这对他们不利，对社会也不利。
so we should respond in some way we may
所以我们应该以某种方式回应。
still allow you to post but we may put a
我们仍然允许您发帖，但可能会添加一个
little box around it saying you know
周围有个小方框，上面写着“你知道”
here's what experts you know here's what
以下是专家们所了解的：
all of the doctors at all the elite
所有精英医生
hospitals you know survey says
调查显示，您了解的医院
99.999% of them you know there's only
你知道，其中99.999%的人只有
one out of all the doctors that lead
在所有领导的医生中，有一位是
hospitals who don't think like these
有些医院的想法与此不同。
vaccines are a good idea and do you
接种疫苗是个好主意，你呢？
think social networks have been a net
认为社交网络一直是一张网
positive for society I think broadly
我认为从整体上看，这对社会是有益的。
look it doesn't mean that they're that
你看，这并不意味着他们就是这样。
they don't have some challenges mhm
他们没有遇到一些挑战，嗯。
like people
像人
criticize Facebook for example um but
例如批评Facebook，嗯，但是
actually in fact a billion people get on
实际上，有十亿人上
it every day they share their
他们每天都分享他们的
experiences pictures lives with loved
与爱人一起经历、照片和生活
ones friends Etc all of that's very very
朋友等等，所有这些都非常非常
positive um I think Twitter
积极的，嗯，我认为推特
unfortunately is taking a turn for the
不幸的是，情况正在朝着……的方向发展。
worst I think if you go you know where's
我觉得最糟糕的情况是，如果你去了，你知道在哪里……
the largest site which has the most
最大的网站，拥有最多
untruths on it I think it's Twitter
我觉得推特上有很多不实信息。
right um but you know that doesn't mean
对，嗯，但你知道那并不意味着
it can't also be improved and fixed over
它也无法通过其他方式进行改进和修复。
time
时间
what's worked well in your business this
在你的业务中，哪些方面做得好？
year where did you need more help we
您在哪一年需要更多帮助？
should all be asking ourselves these
我们都应该扪心自问这些问题
types of questions as we close out the
在结束之际，我们提出以下类型的问题
year Q4 is a time for reflecting but
第四季度是反思的时期，但
it's also a time to look ahead and start
这也是展望未来并开始行动的时候。
planning could your team increase
规划可以增加你的团队
productivity and set more ambitious
提高生产力并设定更远大的目标
goals if you had more resource if so my
如果你有更多资源，我的目标就是……
show sponsor Fiverr could be the
节目赞助商 Fiverr 可能是
resource you need to ramp up in 2025
您需要在2025年加大资源投入
Fiverr is the Online Marketplace where
Fiverr 是一个在线市场，
you can connect with skilled Freelancers
您可以联系到技能娴熟的自由职业者
specializing in almost every area of
几乎在所有领域都拥有专长
business whether you need need coders
无论您的业务是否需要程序员
digital marketeers AI experts or
数字营销人员、人工智能专家或
designers they're all there ready to
设计师们都已就位，准备就绪。
help you can browse portfolios and
您可以浏览作品集并
reviews and if their Creator's work
评论以及他们创作者的作品
doesn't meet your standards fiverr's
不符合 Fiverr 的标准
refund policy has you covered set your
退款政策保障您的权益，请设置您的退款政策。
2025 up for success and explore fiverr's
2025年，迈向成功，探索Fiverr的无限可能
creative Network visit fiver.com diary
创意网络访问 fiver.com 日记
and use code diary for 10% off your
使用代码 diary 可享 10% 折扣
first order whenever I speak to
每次我跟他们说话，首要顺序都是
entrepreneurs like today's guest Reed
像今天的嘉宾里德这样的企业家
Hoffman the co-founder of LinkedIn
霍夫曼是领英的联合创始人。
there's one problem that always comes up
有一个问题总是会冒出来。
but today's sponsor LinkedIn has a
但今天的赞助商 LinkedIn 却拥有
solution that I think you'll want to
我认为你会想要的解决方案是
hear connecting your business with the
了解如何将您的企业与
right people can be tough you can spend
找到合适的人可能很难，你可能会花很多钱。
a lot of time in money trying to get it
花费大量时间和金钱试图得到它
right and still nonetheless fall short
没错，但仍然有所欠缺
especially when it comes to btb
尤其是在btb方面
marketing where you're not doing
在你没有开展营销活动的地方进行营销
business with one person you're dealing
与你交易的那个人做生意
with teams making decisions together
团队共同做出决策
through Linkedin ads you can get access
通过 LinkedIn 广告，您可以获得访问权限
to the Right audience so you can build
找到合适的受众，这样你才能建立
relationships with their one billion
与他们十亿人的关系
members 130 million decision makers and
成员包括1.3亿决策者
10 million SE Executives you can also
1000万SE高管，你也可以
Target specific spefically by job
针对特定职位
industry company and more it's no
行业公司等等，它不是
surprise that LinkedIn is the highest
令人惊讶的是，LinkedIn 排名第一
returning paid social platform to help
回归付费社交平台以帮助
you get started LinkedIn is offering a
入门 LinkedIn 提供了一项服务
$100 credit to launch your first
100 美元信用额度，助您开启您的第一个项目
campaign just go to linkedin.com doac 24
活动详情请访问 linkedin.com doac 24
to claim your credit now that's
现在就去领取你的信用额度吧！
linkedin.com
linkedin.com
doac c24 terms and conditions apply
doac c24 条款及细则适用
there's so many different takes that
有很多不同的解读。
I've heard on AI I've spoken to Mustafa
我听说人工智能方面的事情，我和穆斯塔法谈过。
Solomon I've spoken to lots of different
所罗门，我和很多不同的人谈过。
I you know Mustafa because you invested
我知道穆斯塔法，因为你投资了。
in his company yeah we co-founded
是的，在他的公司里，我们共同创立了
inflection ah he co-founded inflection
屈折变化啊，他是屈折变化的联合创始人。
which then sold to Microsoft well it's
后来卖给了微软，嗯，就是这样。
it did a commercial deal with him it's
它和他达成了一项商业协议。
still going as a company oh okay all
公司还在运营哦，好的
right cuz my stuff moved over yeah he
对，因为我的东西搬过去了，是的，他
moved over because he wanted to do a
挪动了一下，因为他想做一件事
consumer agent and inflection is doing
消费者代理和转折正在发生
B2B uh software sales now what is your
B2B 软件销售，现在你的是什么？
take on AI and how should we be thinking
我们如何看待人工智能？我们应该如何思考？
about it how should Dave and Jenny the
关于这件事，戴夫和珍妮应该怎么做？
average person with you know working in
你知道，一个普通人，在……工作
a company or building a small startup
一家公司或正在打造一家小型初创公司
think about AI so I think AI is in a
想想人工智能，所以我认为人工智能正处于……
look so I last year I published a book
你看，我去年出版了一本书。
called impromptu which is the first book
名为《即兴曲》的第一本书
on AI co-written with AI right yeah to
关于人工智能，与人工智能共同撰写，没错。
show as well as tell that AI is not just
展示并说明人工智能不仅仅是
artificial intelligence it's
人工智能就是
amplification intelligence it gives us
它赋予我们的增强智能
superpowers right as part of that I'm
超能力，作为其中的一部分，我是
publishing a book in January called
一月份出版一本名为《
super agency which is our human agency
超级机构，也就是我们的人类机构
even with this agentic technology can
即使有了这种智能体技术也能
and will be magnified we will get these
并且会被放大，我们会得到这些
superpowers and super agency is the time
超级大国和超级机构的时代已经来临。
where um when a lot of people get access
嗯，当很多人获得访问权限的时候
to a new general purpose technology um
迈向一种新的通用技术
the transformation of society that comes
社会转型即将到来
and it's like printing press or
它就像印刷机一样，或者
electricity or cars or mobile phones
电力、汽车或手机
it's it's this
就是这个
amazing uh uh transformation of all of
令人惊叹的转变
our Lives because not only do I get the
我们的生活，因为我不仅得到了
superpower by having AI the fact that
拥有人工智能的超级大国……
you have a superpower with AI also
你也拥有人工智能方面的超能力。
increase my agency so for example you're
增强我的自主性，例如，你是
a doctor who now has access to AI your
一位现在可以使用人工智能的医生
ability to help tend to lots of people's
有能力照顾很多人
heals now just get Amplified and it's
现在治疗效果会得到增强，而且是
the same thing like when a car was
就像汽车一样
created a doctor could now do have a
一位医生现在可以做到这一点
broader range of places they could visit
他们可以参观的地点范围更广
to go help that part of his cars have
去帮忙，他车上的那部分零件已经……
that super agencies not just I can drive
那些超级机构不仅仅是我能开车
places now because the doctor can drive
现在很多地方都去不了了，因为医生可以开车。
places that also
也
increases her his agency and also my
增强了她的自主权，也增强了我的自主权。
agency through super agency and that
通过超级代理机构进行代理，以及
book's coming out in January there's a
这本书一月份就要出版了。
little around AI as well there's fear
人们对人工智能知之甚少，也存在恐惧。
all the time with new technologies is
一直以来，新技术都在不断涌现。
any of that Gloom
任何那些阴郁
warranted yes but with an asterisk which
确实有理，但需加个星号，
is every time a new general purpose
每次都是一个新的通用
technology comes out the discourse when
当技术从讨论中脱颖而出时
the printing press came out the
印刷机问世了
discourse was very similar to the
论述与此非常相似
current discourse on AI it's going to
当前关于人工智能的讨论将会是……
destroy Society um it's going to destroy
摧毁社会，嗯，它将会摧毁
human learning and knowledge you know
人类学习和知识你所知道的
it's going to disable the current people
这将使现有人员无法工作。
who are the who are the the custodians
谁是保管人？
of knowledge which mostly priests you
知识主要来自牧师们
know in Society from from from being
在社会中，通过存在而了解。
able to control the flow of information
能够控制信息流
we're going to have all this
我们将拥有这一切
misinformation etc etc now by the way
顺便一提，现在还有错误信息等等。
you don't have a scientific revolution
你们没有经历科学革命
without the printing press right so um
如果没有印刷机，对吧？嗯……
now so there's always this fear but and
所以现在总会有这种恐惧，但是……
you say is the fear completely
你说恐惧完全
unwarranted well look human societies
毫无根据地审视人类社会
are bad at new general purpose
不擅长新的通用用途
Technologies right so um with the
技术方面，嗯，所以……
printing press we had nearly a century
我们拥有印刷机将近一个世纪了。
of religious War because of it so the
宗教战争就是因为这个。
transitions are very difficult because
转型非常困难，因为
we as human beings are difficult at new
我们人类很难接受新事物。
general purpose Technologies and so the
通用技术，以及
transition look the transition is going
过渡部分，过渡正在进行中。
to have pain there's going to be
疼痛是必然的。
challenges and reordering and so
挑战和重新排序等等
disruption because of it no question
由此造成的干扰毋庸置疑。
what I'm hoping and part of the reason I
我希望如此，这也是我部分原因所在。
write these books is say look let's
写这些书就等于说，看，我们来……
manage this transition better than we've
我们比以往任何时候都更能妥善地管理这一过渡时期。
managed the previous transitions right
之前的过渡管理得当
let's I have one 100% confidence that
让我百分之百确信这一点
the other side this will be enormously
另一方面，这将产生巨大的影响。
amazing super agency what I wanted to do
超棒的超级代理公司，正是我想要的。
is manage the transition as best we can
尽我们所能管理好过渡期
now people say well shouldn't you manage
现在人们会说，难道你不应该管理好吗？
the transition by being really slow and
过渡过程非常缓慢，而且
being really regulated well the
监管非常完善
challenge is is that these new
挑战在于这些新的
technologies are developed competitively
技术发展是竞争性的
across the entire Globe different
遍布全球的不同
countries different Industries different
不同国家的不同行业也不同
companies Etc and we don't set the clock
公司等等，我们不设定时间
like there's no one group that sets the
好像没有哪个团体可以设定……
clock and if you don't like go with it
时钟，如果你不喜欢就随它去吧。
like take the industrial Evolution which
以工业革命为例
also had a bunch of things why did
还有很多其他事情，为什么会这样
Europe basically set the the the the
欧洲基本上设定了……
drum beat for the globe for centuries
几个世纪以来，鼓声响彻全球
the answer is Europe embraced the
答案是欧洲接受了
Industrial Revolution robustly and early
工业革命蓬勃发展，早期
right the um you know it's part of what
对，嗯，你知道，这是其中的一部分，
you know made uh the British Empire
你知道，它缔造了大英帝国。
right and so that clock is set by
对，所以时钟是由……设定的
different human beings all running at it
不同的人都在朝着它奔跑。
and by the way they have different
顺便说一句，他们有不同的
theories of the good they have different
他们关于善的理论各不相同
theories of how technology should be in
关于技术应如何发展的理论
society they have different theories of
社会对他们有不同的理论
what the risks are Technologies like you
像您这样的技术有哪些风险？
know when these people published this
知道这些人是什么时候发表这篇文章的
pause letter that was like that's a
暂停信就像那样
mistake like other people aren't going
犯了和其他人一样的错误，他们不会去
to PA like it's a simple thing you look
对宾夕法尼亚州来说，这就像一件很简单的事情，你看看
at the people who care about Humanity if
那些关心人类的人们
they all pause and the people don't care
他们都停了下来，而人们却毫不在意。
about Humanity don't pause your letter
关于人性，请不要在信中停顿。
if you if you achieve your success will
如果你成功了，你会
cause a bad impact on Humanity so you
对人类造成不良影响，所以你
have to be developing it you have to be
你必须开发它，你必须是
going with the CL that's set by the
按照设定的CL值执行
world right when I think about AI in
当我想到人工智能时，我感觉世界正处于变革之中。
simple terms the the way that I've I've
简单来说，我一直以来都是这样。
been thinking about it and this is not a
我一直在考虑这件事，这不是一个
Perfect Analogy or whatever but it's
完美的比喻也好，或者别的什么也好，但事实就是如此。
just a simple way to think about it is
简单来说就是：
if there was one Steven Bartlet here
如果这里有史蒂文·巴特利特的话
that has an IQ of 100 and there was
他的智商是100，而且……
another one sat next to me that had the
我旁边坐着另一个人，他有
IQ of a
智商
thousand what would this Steve do and
一千个，史蒂夫会怎么做？
what would that Steve do that's a good
史蒂夫会怎么做？那才叫好
question is that an apt analogy is that
问题是，一个恰当的类比是……
somewhat well it depends this is part of
情况有点好，这取决于具体情况，这是其中的一部分
the thing is we human beings are very
问题在于我们人类非常
bad at imagining future technology mhm
不擅长想象未来科技，嗯。
so I can tell you stories about where we
所以我可以给你讲讲我们去过的地方的故事
have created AIS with IQ of a
已经创建了具有高智商的AIS
thousand I can tell you stories where
我可以给你讲一千个故事，其中
we've created AIS with IQs of uh 200 of
我们创造了智商高达 200 的人工智能系统 (AIS)。
150 and I can also tell you stories of
150，我还可以给你讲讲……的故事
AIS where we' created that are kind of
AIS，我们创建了某种类型的
the equivalent because today we have
相当于今天我们有
this is a form of like idiot seant like
这是一种类似白痴席位的形式
today's AI are super intelligent I'll
如今的人工智能非常智能，我会
give you an example so if I go to a
举个例子，如果我去一个
human being I try to look human say
我努力让自己看起来像个人，说
explain to
解释
me mixture of experts creation of AI
我与专家们共同创造了人工智能
with an AI what does that mean uh it's a
有了人工智能，那意味着什么？呃，它是一种……
it's a technique by which modern AIS are
这是现代AIS所使用的一种技术。
created that have um different kind of
创造出了具有不同种类的
expertise roles in the combination like
组合中的专业角色，例如
chat gbt is created this way that create
聊天 gbt 就是这样创建的
their output it's a it's a particular
他们的输出是一个，这是一个特定的
technical definition for the way of
方法的技术定义
creating a a worldclass AI model then I
创建一个世界级的人工智能模型，然后我
say okay compare a mixture of experts uh
比如说，比较一下不同领域专家的意见。
so it's only thousands of people who
所以只有几千人
understand how to do that I say okay
我明白了该怎么做，我说好的。
compare that to uh modern economic Game
将其与现代经济博弈进行比较
Theory well there's probably some humans
理论上来说，可能有一些人类
that can do that too we're probably now
它也能做到这一点，我们现在可能就是
down to like 50 to 100 right then I say
我说，大概降到50到100左右吧。
okay compare those two to Modern
好的，比较一下这两种现代风格。
oceanography right okay now we're at
海洋学，好的，我们现在在……
zero human beings there's no human
零个人，没有人类
beings who can do this but I can go to
能做到这一点的人，但我可以去
gbd4 and I can run this gbd4 because
gbd4，我可以运行这个gbd4，因为
it's ingested a mill a trillion words of
它吞下了100万亿个单词
knowledge can write the comparisons
知识可以用于进行比较。
between these three things because it
介于这三件事之间，因为它
knows all three because it knows all
它知道这三者，因为它知道一切。
three that's a superpower that no human
三，那是一种人类无法企及的超能力
being has we have ai superpower today
因为我们今天拥有人工智能超能力
right but of course no one's alarmed
没错，但当然没人感到恐慌。
about that because like oh that's a
关于那件事，因为就像，哦，那是一个
great amplification intelligence that
强大的放大智能
really helps me I think there's a very
我觉得这真的对我有帮助。
good chance that what happens is is that
很有可能发生的事情是这样的
what we're creating with all of every
我们正在用所有的一切创造什么
current e AI technique that's under
当前人工智能技术处于……之下
development is these amazing savants
发展就是这些惊人的学者
that are these great co-pilots right and
这些就是优秀的副驾驶，对吧？
that's what we're creating not
这就是我们正在创造的东西，不是吗？
Terminator robots not super
终结者机器人并非超级机器人
intelligences there's a possibility of
智能方面存在一种可能性
that and I can address the existential
而且我还可以探讨存在主义问题。
risk questions around the possibility of
围绕可能性的风险问题
that because people think about that
因为人们会想到这一点。
poorly but um but the I think the
虽然不太好，但是嗯，但是我觉得
likelihood is that we're going to be
我们很可能会……
having these kind of co-pilots that give
拥有这类副驾驶会……
us these
我们这些
informational GPS's these cognitive
信息GPS的这些认知
superpowers that make us as human beings
使我们成为人类的超能力
a lot
很多
better B Act is are G to yes that too
更好的 B Act 是 G 也一样
yes that's the bigger worry so you say
是的，你说，那才是更大的担忧。
one worry is transition and another
一个担忧是过渡，另一个担忧是
worry is whenever you're you're creating
担忧在于，无论何时你都在创造。
this new technology you want to say I
你想说的这项新技术是……
want to empower all these people who are
想要赋予所有这些人力量
building Better Lives for themselves in
他们为自己创造更美好的生活
society and I want to not Empower
社会，我不想赋予权力。
criminals terrorists Rogue States and
罪犯、恐怖分子、流氓国家和
also you think
你也这么认为
I also need weapons that are
我还需要一些武器。
sufficiently uh Advanced attacking my my
足够高级的攻击我的我的
enemies and everybody globally is
全球的敌人都是
thinking that yes China might be
认为中国可能
thinking about the the west and the West
思考西方和西方
are thinking about China Russia are
正在思考中国和俄罗斯的关系
thinking about this person this person
想着这个人，这个人
the Middle East are probably thinking
中东方面可能正在考虑
about a couple of people yes so with
大概有几个人，是的，所以和
with all developing weapons or defense
所有正在研发的武器或防御
systems they're going to probably make
他们可能会制造的系统
those robots you talked about the
你提到的那些机器人
Terminator robot that can go to the
终结者机器人可以去
battlefield yes and that's super smart
战场上，没错，这真是太聪明了。
they're going to probably make some
他们可能会做一些
cyber weapons as well yes so those
网络武器也是，没错，那些
things end up existing and then they're
事物最终会存在，然后它们就会
in the wrong hands the mistake happens
如果落入不法之徒手中，错误就会发生。
so you want to build them in the right
所以你想把它们建在正确的位置。
hands first that's all I mean look there
先看手，我的意思是，看那里。
will be cost to it there's never look
这将付出代价，而且永远不会考虑。
electricity essential for Human Society
电力对人类社会至关重要
it does electrocute people right it does
它确实会电死人，对吧？
two things in the wrong hands too right
两样东西落入了错误的人手中，也同样正确。
is this technology different though
这项技术有何不同？
because there's been comparisons to the
因为有人将其与……进行比较
printing press electricity but is this
印刷机用电，但这真的如此吗？
no no it's new but by the way each
不不，这是新的，不过顺便说一下，每个
technology the printing press was
印刷机这项技术是
different when it was created
不同之处在于它创建之时。
electricity was different when it was
当时的电力与现在截然不同。
created cars were different when they
当时制造的汽车与现在制造的汽车有所不同
were created is this the most profound
被创造出来，这是最深刻的吗？
well in terms of impact it C it might be
就影响而言，它可能是C。
right that's that's that's possibility
没错，这就是可能性。
um I think there is I always think in
嗯，我觉得有，我总是这么想。
probability distributions I think
我认为概率分布
there's a good probability of it but to
很有可能，但是
some
一些
degree like it doesn't matter if it is
学位似乎无关紧要，如果它是
or isn't the most it is a Prof found new
或者说，这并非最主要的原因，而是一位教授发现了新的
technology it's as important at least as
技术的重要性至少不亚于……
these other ones that's the only thing
其他的那些，就只有这些了。
that matters whether it definitely is or
这很重要，它究竟是不是真的。
not doesn't really matter and look what
其实没关系，看看这是什么情况
is different it's the fact it's a gentic
不同之处在于，它是一种基因疾病。
technology which means it it's creating
这意味着它正在创造技术。
agents that can operate on their
能够操作它们的代理人
own right we already have that by the
我们理所当然地已经拥有了这一点。
way like the agent you can be running an
就像你运行的代理一样
agent with a connection to the internet
具有互联网连接的代理
on your computer and it can go buy stuff
在你的电脑上，它可以去买东西。
for you right you can do that today it's
对你来说，今天就可以做到。
doable
可行
you have agent just a question of what
你有代理人，现在的问题是：什么
the shape is right so it's agentic it's
形状正确，所以它是主动的。
cognitive like like it's very strange
认知方面，这很奇怪
that we have a technology now that we
我们现在拥有这样一种技术：
can talk to in various ways and so you
可以用各种方式交谈，所以你
have people mistaken going oh it must be
人们误以为“哦，那一定是……”
conscious because they asked if who was
因为他们问是谁，所以才意识到这一点
conscious and it said it was conscious
它有意识，并且说它是有意识的。
and I was like no but by the way before
我当时就想，不，不过顺便说一下，之前
this technology existed that was a good
这项技术已经存在，而且很好。
test does by the way there are conscious
顺便说一下，测试确实存在意识层面的问题。
things that can't there's there's mute
不能做的事情是静音
people and the fact that they can't tell
人们以及他们无法分辨的事实
you their conscious so conscious not
你他们的意识如此有意识，所以没有意识
perfectly they tell you they're
他们完美地告诉你他们是
conscious but you tell me your conscious
有意识，但你告诉我你的意识
that was a pretty good test before now
那之前是一次相当不错的测试。
it's a little bit more complicated
情况稍微复杂一些。
because I don't think any of the current
因为我认为目前没有任何一个……
AIS are conscious and we can go in depth
AIS是有意识的，我们可以深入探讨。
of reason of Neuroscience and other
神经科学及其他领域的理性
kinds of things about why that is it's
诸如此类的原因
not a just a human species parist view
不仅仅是人类物种的视角
um and figur out under what circumstance
嗯，还要弄清楚在什么情况下
it would be conscious is a very
有意识地这样做是非常
interesting question that we need to we
我们需要探讨一个有趣的问题。
need to figure out because it won't be
需要想办法解决，因为这不会是
that it has gray matter it'll be
它有灰质，它会是
something else or you know maybe we'll
其他的，或者你知道，也许我们会
figure this
想想这个
out so so that's new the cognitive
所以，这就是新的认知
superpowers are new the fact that the
超级大国是新出现的，这一事实是……
speed of deployment is going to be
部署速度将会是
unusual because now we have the mobile
不寻常的是，现在我们有了手机
phone internet so I create a new agent
我用电话和网络创建了一个新的代理
and tomorrow a billion people can use
明天，十亿人就可以使用
it right that's new right so so all of
对，那是新的，对吧，所以所有这些
these things are new and by the way new
这些东西都是新的，而且是新的。
is anxiety producing and new is
会引起焦虑，而且是新的
difficult to navigate and new can make
难以导航，而且新手可能会遇到问题。
transition's very difficult right but by
转型非常困难，对吧？
the way the fact that we're facing a new
我们正面临着一个新的局面。
challenge is not itself a new
挑战本身并非新鲜事。
challenge right for the average person
对普通人来说，这是一项挑战。
out there that's I know they might be
我知道他们可能就在那里。
working in a hospital or might be a
在医院工作或者可能是
lawyer or or a doctor whatever just
律师或者医生什么的，随便什么都行。
someone with a a job that's heard this
一个有相关工作的人听到了这句话
term Ai and they're saying chat GPT is
术语“人工智能”，他们说聊天 GPT 是
there anything that they should be doing
他们应该做些什么呢？
on an individual level to make sure that
在个人层面上，确保
they can capitalize on the opportunity
他们可以抓住这个机会
that AI
人工智能
presents the basic answer is absolutely
给出的基本答案是绝对的。
yes and that's part of the reason why
是的，这也是部分原因。
like like I do my podcast possible I do
就像我做播客那样，我可能会这样做。
super agency I do impromptu because the
超级代理机构，我即兴发挥，因为
strong advice I give everyone and
我给每个人的强烈建议
literally I was sitting with the
我当时就坐在那里
governors of the bank of England
英格兰银行行长
yesterday and my advice to them among
昨天，我给他们的建议是……
other things was personally go use AI
其他事情是我个人去使用人工智能。
right don't just use it to make a Sonet
对，别只是用它来制作 Sonet。
for your kids's birthday that's great
送给孩子当生日礼物真是太棒了！
don't just use it for a recipe for what
不要仅仅把它用作食谱，比如做什么菜。
happens to be refrigerator that's great
碰巧是一台很棒的冰箱
for something that matters to you that
为了对你来说重要的事情
part of your expertise and soth start
你的部分专业知识和一些开始
using it and by the way you'll find that
使用它，顺便说一句，你会发现
uh some of the things are still not
呃，有些事情仍然没有解决。
useful for it all like when I sat down
对所有事情都很有用，比如当我坐下来的时候
to ask gbd4 how would Reed Hoffman make
问gbd4，里德·霍夫曼会怎么做？
money investing in AI it gave me an
投资人工智能给我带来了……
answer that was the smart business
那才是明智的商业策略。
school Professor answer who didn't
学校教授回答了谁没有回答
understand Venture Capital it was like
了解风险投资就像……
well study which areas have the largest
仔细研究哪些地区拥有最大的
total addressable Market it then look at
然后查看总潜在市场
what the possibilities for competitive
竞争的可能性有哪些
disruption are then you know market
市场颠覆，你就知道了。
research test that it's like it's no way
研究测试表明，这根本不可能。
like go find a great entrepreneur with a
比如去找一位优秀的创业者
great idea right you know and and it's
好主意，对吧？而且它是
best when the idea is something you
最好是当这个想法是你……的时候。
haven't thought of and few other people
没想过这个问题，也没想到其他人。
have thought of too right is a way of
考虑得太对了，这是一种方式
doing so it got it completely wrong from
这样做完全错了。
how I how Reed Hoffman how I invest in
我如何像里德·霍夫曼那样投资
Ai and what I do very successfully now
人工智能以及我现在非常成功所做的一切
you say well then it's useless for
你说，那它就没用了。
Venture Capital it's like no no cuz I
风险投资？不行不行，因为我
kept experimenting with it and I said
我一直在尝试，然后我说
okay I fed in a uh an entrepreneurs plan
好的，我提交了一份创业者计划。
and I said how would I do due diligence
我问，我该如何进行尽职调查？
on this plan and it came back with a
根据这个方案，结果出来了。
pretty good list was like yeah yeah one
相当不错的列表，就像是“是啊是啊”一样。
that was I was absolutely planning on
那是我绝对计划好的。
doing that two I was absolutely three
做那件事的时候，我绝对是三个
yeah I could see why you'd think I was
是的，我能理解你为什么会这么想。
doing it that's not important oh four I
做这件事并不重要，哦，四，我
would have gotten to it would would have
本来可以到达那里，本来可以
gotten to it like four days down the
大概过了四天就搞定了。
road of doing the work and now I know it
走过这条路，现在我明白了。
now so it's useful there so it is today
所以现在在那里很有用，今天也是如此。
useful to everybody you can use it for
对每个人都有用，你可以用它来……
things that you care about today so go
今天你关心的事情，去做吧
start playing with it and I love Ethan
开始玩它，我爱上了伊森
mik's line which is the worst AI you're
mik 的台词是“你是最差的人工智能”。
ever going to use in your life is the AI
你一生中真正会用到的就是人工智能。
you're using today so one of the reasons
你今天正在使用它，原因之一就是……
to start using it is to start getting
开始使用它就是开始获得
familiar with it because like it is a
熟悉它，因为它就像一个
stunning tool and I'll give one since
这是一款非常棒的工具，我会给它打一分。
you're talking about Everyday People
你指的是普通人。
I'll give one kind of tip that I give
我会给出我给出的一种建议。
everybody at the beginning it's part of
一开始，每个人都是其中的一部分
the reason I wrote impromptu Etc which
我写“即兴等等”的原因是
is um what what is ai ai is great at
嗯……人工智能是什么？人工智能的优势是什么？
adopting a role that you tell it to
扮演你赋予它的角色
adopt right so here's a very simple one
领养是件好事，所以这里有一个非常简单的例子。
you have an argument for something you
你对某件事有论点
can paste it into an AI um and you can
可以把它粘贴到人工智能程序里，然后你就可以……
say uh counter this argument take the
比如说，反驳这个论点，采取……
role of critic argue against me and you
评论家的角色在于反驳我和你
can see it it will immediately give you
你可以看到它会立即给你
an you know a a a capable argument
你知道，这是一个有力的论证。
against your position that is very
这与你的立场非常相悖。
helpful it's helpful for cognitive
有帮助，对认知能力有帮助
development it's helpful for learning
发展对学习很有帮助
it's for our understanding you know what
这是为了方便我们理解，你知道吗？
are the strengths and weaknesses but by
优势和劣势都在于此，但通过
the way you can also say take my side
你也可以用这种方式表达“站在我这边”。
give me another argument for the thing
请给我另一个支持这件事的理由。
I'm arguing for like make that argument
我赞同这种观点，请提出这个论点。
but that's just the beginning you can
但这仅仅是个开始，你可以……
also say like for example if I go okay
也可以说，比如如果我说“好的”
I'm making this argument
我提出这个论点
for uh um how general purpose
呃，通用
technologies always have initial strong
技术总是具有初期优势。
fear by people and how they're described
人们的恐惧以及他们如何被描述
as the end of society the end of
社会的终结，终结
humanity Etc it's happened a number of
人类等等，这种情况已经发生过很多次了。
different
不同的
times um how would a historian of
时代，嗯，一位历史学家会怎么想？
Technology analyze my argument how would
技术分析我的论点会如何进行？
they criticize my argument and then you
他们批评我的论点，然后你
get it so you can get to like it's
买它，这样你就能喜欢上它了。
literally it's only your own creativity
实际上，这完全取决于你自己的创造力。
and your own inspiration of who what
以及你自己的灵感来源
role should I be talking to and once you
我应该和谁交谈，以及一旦你
start realizing that you can start using
开始意识到你可以开始使用
AI very powerfully for whatever you're
人工智能非常强大，无论你做什么
trying to do should entrepreneurs be
尝试做企业家应该做什么
thinking about building companies in the
考虑在业内建立公司
field of AI at the moment you know as a
目前你所了解的人工智能领域是一个
entrepreneur who's like roughly 30 years
一位大约30岁的企业家
old I look back and go gosh I wish I was
老了以后，我回首往事，不禁感叹：唉，真希望我年轻的时候……
of entrepreneurial age when the.com boom
在互联网泡沫兴起之时，我正值创业年龄。
came around because everyone became
之所以会这样，是因为每个人都变成了
billionaires and and is is that is this
亿万富翁们，而且这就是……
that moment in time yes so short answer
是的，就是那一刻，所以简短回答
is yes okay so what so I'm an
好的，所以呢？我是一个
entrepreneur I'm I'm 30 OD years old um
我是一名企业家，今年30岁，嗯。
I've got disposable income I'm
我有可支配收入，我是
financially free m i' I'd love to take
财务自由，我，我很乐意接受
part in the next Revolution yeah should
是的，应该参与下一场革命。
I be fing out to San Francisco and build
我要去旧金山，然后建造
building an AI joining an AI start about
构建人工智能加入人工智能的开始
there yes why
是的，为什么？
so so one of the things is Silicon
所以其中一点就是硅。
Valley so Silicon Valley has built
硅谷已经建成
itself up of multiple the reason it's
它本身就是多种原因造成的。
called Silicon Valley is because it
之所以被称为硅谷，是因为它
started with silicon right it's now
最初是用硅做的，现在……
software Valley Silicon Valley almost
软件谷硅谷几乎
never invested in Silicon anymore
再也没有投资硅谷了
silicon being the chips yes Bing the
是的，硅就是芯片，Bing。
chips yes um so now really it's much
薯片，嗯，所以现在真的很多了。
more software Valley it's like we invest
更像是我们在硅谷投资。
billions and billions of dollar every
每家每户都损失数十亿美元。
year into new software companies
进入新软件公司的第一年
right so we went from Silicon through
对，所以我们从硅谷开始……
you know networking equipment like Cisco
你知道像思科这样的网络设备吗？
through like just stacks of different
就像堆叠起来的不同东西一样
things getting to where we are now ai is
事情发展到我们现在所处的阶段，人工智能是……
the new one by the way we did the thing
顺便说一下，我们把新版本做完了。
with internet we did it with mobile
我们利用互联网和手机做到了这一点。
phones we did it with web
手机，我们用网页完成了这项工作
2 now it's AI right and so you know the
2 现在是人工智能了，对吧，所以你知道
principal thing is when you get this new
最重要的是当你得到这个新东西的时候
like uh new general uh purpose
比如新的通用
technology uh it opens up massive
科技，嗯，它开启了巨大的机遇。
amounts of entrepreneurial space because
创业空间的数量，因为
one is's all the new things that can be
其中之一是所有可能的新事物
built that were never possible before
以前从未实现过的建造
Airbnb couldn't be done before the
Airbnb 在……之前是不可能实现的
internet there's just no way right so it
互联网上根本没有办法，对吧？
opens up these things that weren't
它开启了那些原本不存在的事物。
possible before um and so like the
可能之前，嗯，所以就像
internet's a good proxy to the to the
互联网是通往……的一个很好的代理
wave we have now with AI then it also by
我们现在正经历着人工智能浪潮，它也将如此。
the way uh makes a mass massive
这种方式使质量巨大
transformative force on all existing
对所有现有事物的变革力量
businesses so you say well I had a
所以你说，我曾经有过一家企业
business of of selling you know kind of
你知道，就是那种销售业务。
um of e-commerce and doing you know mail
嗯，电子商务和邮件
order cataloges well now there's
订购目录，现在有……
e-commerce right so it it it transforms
电子商务就是这样，它改变了一切。
all of these businesses and so by the
所有这些企业，因此，通过
way for example the internet is part of
例如，互联网就是其中的一部分
what makes the cloud Revolution so now
是什么让云计算革命在当下如此重要
it's like well actually in fact it's not
其实，实际上并非如此
software on your desktop it's not
它不是你桌面上的软件。
software on your your phone it's in the
你手机上的软件就在……
cloud and of course it bounces back and
云层，当然它会反弹回来。
forth a little bit then you have well no
向前走一点，然后你就没事了。
actually in fact you've got this really
实际上，你真的做到了。
great app on your phone and soth but
手机上有个很棒的应用程序，等等
these kinds of things AI is the next one
这类事情，人工智能是下一个。
that affects all of them so you have
这会影响到他们所有人，所以你……
Green Field you have potentially
您拥有的绿地潜力
revolutionized any particular place
彻底改变了任何特定的地方
where there's a product or service
有产品或服务的地方
especially that intelligence could be
尤其是情报可能
added to it right there's a possibility
再加上这一点，就存在一种可能性。
of a great startup idea there so so yes
这是一个很棒的创业想法，所以，是的。
now
现在
should you go try to build your own
你应该尝试自己建造一个
Frontier Model which is a 10 billion
前沿模型是一个100亿美元的
doll computer it's a hard thing that's a
娃娃电脑，这可不是件容易的事。
hard amount of capital for startups no
初创企业所需的硬性资金量为零
no no try to figure out like degrees you
不不，试着弄清楚比如你的度数
use Frontier models from you know open
使用 Frontier 模型，您知道开放
AI or Microsoft or Google or you know
人工智能、微软、谷歌，或者你知道的
others as ways of doing this but you
其他人也用其他方法做到这一点，但你
still May build your own model right um
或许你还是可以自己搭建一个模型，对吧？
that a lots of lots of startup companies
很多很多初创公司
are building their own models I invested
他们正在构建自己的模型，我投资了
in this customer service company called
这家客户服务公司叫做
Sierra that Brett Taylor is doing and
布雷特·泰勒正在做的Sierra
their thing is we're not building our
他们的观点是我们没有建设我们的
own models we're just deploying other
我们拥有自己的模型，只是在部署其他模型。
models so we have best of readed for
因此，我们已经阅读了最佳模型。
what models are available to us you
你们有哪些型号可供选择？
could do that as an AI startup there's a
人工智能初创公司可以做到这一点。
whole range and part of what I love
涵盖所有方面，也是我所热爱的一部分
about entrepreneurship and invention is
关于创业和发明
like I have a whole set of theories
我好像有一整套理论
about what kinds of things will be
关于将会是什么样的事情
really big and some of my theories will
非常大，我的一些理论将会
be right and I will also discover some
如果我说的没错，我也会发现一些
other people who have amazing theories
其他拥有惊人理论的人
that's one of the things I really I and
那是我真正想说的事情之一。
we at Greylock love to invest in
我们Greylock公司喜欢投资……
interesting oh what's the best way for
有趣，那么最好的方法是什么？
someone to go and learn about AI right
应该有人去学习人工智能。
now because like going to University
现在就像上大学一样
feels like it would be start using it
感觉应该开始用它了
start building it if you want to if you
如果你想的话，就可以开始建造了。
can if you're technical uh download an
如果你懂技术，可以下载一个
open source model uh llama mraw other
开源模型 uh llama mraw 其他
start playing with it what if you not
开始玩它，如果你不玩呢？
technical well then well generally
技术上不错，总体上也不错。
speaking like you can't do a technology
说话的口气好像你完全不懂技术似的。
it's very hard to do a technology
开发一项技术非常困难
startup without a technology co-founder
没有技术联合创始人的创业公司
so then go find a technology co-founder
所以，那就去找一位技术联合创始人吧。
so for someone like me who's built my my
所以对于像我这样白手起家的人来说……
career in building teams marketing
团队建设营销方面的职业生涯
social media content media those kinds
社交媒体内容媒体之类的
of things who is really interested in AI
谁真正对人工智能感兴趣？
should I go and do you think I should go
我该去吗？你觉得我应该去吗？
learn AI now and start trying to be a
现在就开始学习人工智能，并尝试成为一名人工智能工程师吧！
technical person or too slow okay yeah
技术人员或者速度太慢，好吧。
too slow no no speed matters speed
太慢了，速度不重要，速度很重要。
matters and startups but by the way uh
关于事务和创业公司，但顺便说一句，呃
like gen because we tend to so much
就像基因一样，因为我们往往太……
lionize what is usually the man versus
将通常被视为男性的事物奉为圭臬
the person most of these people are men
这些人大多数是男性。
um the
嗯
individual startups succeed because
个别创业公司之所以成功，是因为
their initial team that's part of the
他们的初始团队是以下部分的一部分
hiring point we were talking about
我们之前讨论过的招聘点
earlier and so generally speaking if you
早些时候，所以一般来说，如果你
ask me would I rather invest in an
问问我，我更愿意投资哪个？
individual uh founder or two to three
个人创始人，或者两到三位
co-founders I'd rather invest in two to
我宁愿投资两位联合创始人。
three co-founders right so going and
三位联合创始人，对吧，就这样继续下去
finding a co-founder is a great thing
找到联合创始人是一件很棒的事。
because by the way your your throw
因为顺便说一句，你的投掷
weight your capability weight is so much
你的能力重量如此之大
better when you do that and so you know
这样做更好，所以你知道
um uh Mark Zuckerberg had Dustin
嗯……马克·扎克伯格有达斯汀
muskovitz Adam
马斯科维茨·亚当
D'Angelo right you know Chris Hughes
D'Angelo，你知道克里斯·休斯
that's a really important part of how
这是其中非常重要的一部分，它说明了如何
things get created you invested in open
你投资的东西会被创造出来，开放
aai almost a decade ago yes before
差不多十年前，是的，之前
everybody was talking about it what did
大家都在谈论这件事，到底发生了什么？
you see in that company so Sam Alman
你在那家公司里看到了，比如山姆·阿尔曼
Greg Brockman Ilia
格雷格·布罗克曼·伊利亚
suser um
suser um
amazing um and uh they had a focused
太棒了，嗯，他们非常专注。
bold vision
大胆的愿景
which is yes Google has invented the
是的，谷歌发明了
Baseline of the attention based
基于注意力的基线
Transformer but they don't realize that
变形金刚，但他们没有意识到这一点
it's just scale like apply scale to this
这只是缩放，就像将缩放应用于此一样。
we are going to bet the entire company
我们将把整个公司都押上。
everything we're doing on scale on it
我们正在大规模地做这一切
and we're gonna be very focused on doing
我们将非常专注于做这件事。
it that's that's
就是它，就是它
great but people had said the we AI for
很好，但人们说过，我们人工智能是为了
a long time and it had never manifested
很久了，却从未显现出来。
in it and I had passed on a lot of AI
其中，我传递了很多人工智能信息。
Investments but the thing that people
投资，但人们真正关心的是……
need to understand about AI is it's a
需要了解人工智能的一点是，它是一种
transformation to scale Computing
向规模化计算转型
Learning Systems so as opposed to we
与此相反，我们学习系统
program it like we program the AI we
它就像我们编写人工智能程序一样被编写程序。
program a scale Computing Learning
程序规模计算学习
System so it
系统就是这样
learns right and that only becomes
学会了正确的方法，而这只会成为
available once you have scale compute so
一旦拥有规模化计算能力，即可使用。
you need the Internet you need the cloud
你需要互联网，你需要云。
you need massive data centers and you
你需要庞大的数据中心，而你
need access to massive amounts of data
需要获取海量数据
which you get from the internet and
你从互联网上获取的
other things and then you need a scale
其他东西，然后你还需要一个秤。
team to build
组建团队
it on that point of people how important
这一点对人们来说有多么重要
if you're trying to be successful as a
如果你想在以下方面取得成功：
young entrepreneur is
年轻的创业者是
networking uh almost always critical
网络几乎总是至关重要的。
because you need that initial team now
因为你现在就需要那个初始团队。
you don't need networking of I should
你不需要建立人脉，我应该
spend 12 hours a day seven days a week
每周七天，每天花费 12 小时。
going to every party that I can possibly
尽可能参加每一个派对
go of and shaking people's hand and
出去和人们握手
giving my them my business card that's
把我的名片递给他们。
not particularly
并不特别
useful what you need to be is just like
你需要做的就是像
you have a strategy
你有一个策略
for your business you need to have a
你的企业需要拥有一个
strategy for how you're building your
你构建策略的方式
network around your business and your
围绕您的业务和您的网络
network around you like who are the
你周围的人脉网络，比如你认识哪些人
people that I should be talking to who
我应该和哪些人谈谈
are the people that I should be learning
我应该向这些人学习
from who are the people I should be
我应该来自哪些人？
trying to bring into my network that the
试图将这一点引入我的关系网
project that I'm creating and how do I
我正在创建的项目，我该如何做？
meet those people there's so many
去见见这些人，他们太多了。
obvious things that people talk about
人们谈论的那些显而易见的事情
when they're describing what makes an
当他们描述是什么使……
entrepreneur successful they say hard
他们说，企业家成功很难。
work they say have a big Vision but is
他们说他们的工作有远大的愿景，但实际上
there anything that's
有什么东西是
really underappreciated
真的被低估了
like when I say this I'm talking about
就像我说的这个，我指的是……
being a nice person or being etiquette
做一个好人或讲礼貌
or politeness or manners are there any
或者礼貌或礼节，是否存在？
things like that that you think make a
你认为诸如此类的事情会造成……
big difference but people don't
差别很大，但人们却不这么认为。
appreciate well I don't think politeness
我很欣赏，但我认为礼貌并不重要。
and etiquette are s are really
礼仪确实很重要。
particularly good competitive advantages
特别好的竞争优势
I'm not saying the one should be rude
我并不是说对方应该无礼。
but like an emphasis like if an
但就像强调一样，如果
entrepreneur is like I'm reading my
企业家就像我在读我的书一样
etiquette manual it's like don't spend
礼仪手册就像是“不要浪费时间”
your time like sure be nice be I think
你的时间安排肯定会很愉快，我想
building a network like entrepreneurship
建立类似创业的网络
is a team sport it is not an individual
这是一项团队运动，而不是个人运动。
sport it's a team sport so you need to
这项运动是一项团队运动，所以你需要……
be building your team right but you've
组建团队的方式不对，但是你已经
seen entrepreneurs be successful that
看到企业家取得成功
were bad at that right uh not ultimately
我们在这方面做得不好，对吧？呃，最终不是。
at scale oh
规模上哦
interesting right because it is a team
对吧，这很有意思，因为它是一个团队。
sport right like you know it requires
运动就像你知道的那样，这需要
High Talent people around you doing it
你身边有高素质人才在做这件事
now for example you can get enough
例如，现在你可以获得足够的
initial success going and capital that
初步成功和资金
even though you're bad with your team
即使你和你的团队配合不好
people people will come on board because
人们会加入进来，因为
they'll go oh I believe this is going to
他们会说，哦，我相信这会……
go somewhere and I can make a bunch of
去某个地方，我可以做很多
money doing it I'll come do it and so
有钱做这件事，我会来做，就这样。
like for example a classic Trope within
例如，一个经典的套路
Silicon Valley which is broadly correct
硅谷的说法大致正确。
and that's part of the reason you have
这就是你拥有这些能力的部分原因。
the tropes is I want missionary not
套路是“我想要传教士式”，而不是
mercenary cultures right because the
雇佣兵文化是对的，因为
missionaries I believe we're going to
我相信我们将要去传教。
change the world we're going to do it
改变世界，我们一定会做到！
this way and by the way mostly of the
这种方式，顺便说一句，大部分是
big successful companies most of them
大多数都是大型成功企业。
are missionary cultures they say oh
他们说，这是传教士文化吗？哦
they're all missionary cultur no no no
他们都是传教士文化，不不不
there's mercenary cultures that have
存在着雇佣兵文化，它们有
gotten big tooo I'm how do you define
变得很大，我该如何定义它
mercenary in this all I care about is
我只是个雇佣兵，我只关心这个。
making money like all like the only
赚钱就像所有人一样，只有
thing that matters is I'm selling
重要的是我在卖东西
something I'm gonna make money that's
我要做点能赚钱的事。
all that matters do you sometimes think
你有时会想，所有重要的事都重要吗？
the mission's [__] though just like
这任务简直就是扯淡，就像……
[__] to get people to feel something
胡说八道，目的是让人们产生某种感觉。
there are there are [__] missions
有一些很扯淡的任务。
that that are like the I'm just telling
就像我刚才说的那些一样
a story I don't really care right I'm
我其实不太在意这个故事，对吧？
telling a story that's incorrect right
讲一个错误的故事，对吧？
there are like like like um the Silicon
那里有类似硅谷的东西。
Valley TV show uh on HBO
HBO的Valley TV节目
kind of you know um uh you know
你知道，嗯，你知道
satiredaily
讽刺日报
because that's what people want to do
因为那是人们想要做的。
people want to be in things that
人们想要参与到……之中
changing the world so you have to say
改变世界，所以你不得不这么说
like I'm LinkedIn this is how I'm going
就像我在领英上一样，这就是我的发展方向
to change the world I'm open AI this is
为了改变世界，我是 OpenAI，这是
how I'm going to change the world I'm
我将如何改变世界？
married baby be this is how I'm going to
结婚宝贝，这就是我要做的
change the world because humans are
改变世界，因为人类是
emotional story animals exactly so yes
感人的故事，动物，正是如此，是的
you need it but of course it's much
你需要它，但当然，它要贵得多。
better if it happens to be that you
如果碰巧是你，那就更好了。
actually are trying to do that you are
实际上，你正在尝试这样做。
actually in fact you have a good plan
实际上，你的计划很不错。
for how you might succeed in doing that
以及你如何才能成功做到这一点。
because you know a fiz like a I know
因为你知道菲兹就像我知道一样
fizzy drinks company yeah conglomerate
汽水公司，没错，集团
even they try and end they like value
即使他们尝试结束，他们也喜欢价值
proposition with we're going to change
提议我们将改变
the world yes exactly and you know it's
没错，世界就是这样，你知道的。
[__] it's a public company they got
胡扯，那是一家上市公司，他们搞砸了。
shareholders who want to return Yes but
想要回归的股东是的，但是
even they I guess have to do it on the
我想他们也必须这样做。
mindset front what is the mindset the
心态前瞻：什么是心态？
factors of a great entrepreneur's
伟大企业家的要素
mindset what are the key things that you
心态方面，你认为关键是什么？
look for when you're investing in one
投资时要注意这一点
insanely great ambition right I'm I'm
真是异想天开，对吧？
shooting for the moon and you know
目标是月亮，你知道的
sometimes literally but most often like
有时是字面意义上的，但大多数时候是这样的
like if I'm successful I will transform
如果我成功了，我就会改变。
the industry
行业
okay an awareness
好的，一种意识
of like a good plan for how you might do
就像制定一个好的计划，说明你可能会怎么做
that right an awareness that that
那种意识是正确的。
entrepreneurship is a team sport not an
创业是一项团队运动，而不是一项个人运动。
individual Sport and I have a plan for
个人运动方面，我有一个计划。
how I'm bringing in like all of
我是如何把所有东西都带进来的
different elements Capital Talent Etc um
不同要素 资本 人才 等等
like for example one of the ways that I
例如，我采用的方法之一就是
interview Executives
采访高管
is um I say who are the three to five
嗯，我说，那三到五个人是谁？
they five I love it but minimum three
他们五个我都喜欢，但至少三个
worldclass people who worked for you
曾为你工作的世界一流人才
before and I'm going to call them and
之前，我要给他们打电话。
ask them what it's like working for you
问问他们为你工作是什么感觉。
right because and by the way if I if it
对，因为，顺便说一句，如果我如果它
really matters I will then reference
我之后会提到这一点，这很重要。
check those three people on are they
检查一下那三个人是否在场。
actually world class mhm right because
实际上，世界一流，嗯，对吧？
only hire people who are going to hire
只雇用那些会雇用别人的人。
worldclass people who who who play it
世界级的球员，他们玩这个游戏
now similarly like who are the world
现在，就像世界是谁一样。
class people who think you're world
那些自以为是的人，他们觉得自己是世界级的。
class as an entrepreneur and like this
作为一名企业家，我喜欢这样
is one of the things that actually
这是其中一件真正重要的事情。
entrepreneur first that we actually in
首先，我们实际上是企业家。
fact Learned was it isn't necessarily
事实上，学到的东西并不一定如此。
who everybody thinks it's who some
大家都认为是谁，有些人
worldclass people think that this person
世界级人士认为这个人
world class because they're edgy yeah so
世界一流，因为他们很前卫，没错。
you look for that it isn't that you look
你寻找的不是你寻找的东西。
for people that everybody loves them
对于那些人人都喜欢的人来说
everybody says oh I'd love to have a
每个人都说，哦，我真想拥有一个
drink with that person no no no like
和那个人喝酒？不不不，喜欢
having someone say uh that person's hard
有人说“呃，那个人很难搞定”
driving they're difficult that can be a
驾驶它们很困难，这可能是一个
very strong positive I've invested a
非常积极的一面，我投资了
number of entrepreneurs that way what
以这种方式创业的企业家数量是多少？
about resilience well resilience also
关于韧性，韧性也
very important almost every startup goes
非常重要的一点是，几乎所有初创公司都会这样做。
through what I call a valley the shadow
穿过我称之为山谷的阴影
moment which is like why did we think
那一刻，就像我们当时为什么会这么想。
this was a good idea oh my God we're
这真是个好主意，我的天哪，我们
like when when I started social net one
就像我刚开始使用社交网络的时候一样
of my connections from
我的人脉关系
Apple dropped me who had started doing
苹果公司解雇了我，我之前一直在做
startups two years before dropped me a
两年前，我被几家初创公司解雇了。
um
嗯
uh a on line email that said welcome to
呃，一封在线邮件，内容是欢迎来到
where 15 minutes is the difference
其中15分钟是差值
between exultation and Terror I'm Gonna
在狂喜与恐惧之间，我将
Change the World oh [__] I'm gonna
改变世界，哦，天哪，我要
die right so resilience is super
死得其所，所以韧性超级强
important because it is a dog fight um
很重要，因为这是一场恶战。
and multiple times PayPal LinkedIn
以及多次通过 PayPal 和 LinkedIn 付款
Airbnb oh God we're going to die this is
Airbnb，我的天哪，我们要死了，这……
going to be worth zero Can you spot
价值将归零，你能发现吗？
resilience in
韧性
someone um you can have a high
有人，嗯，你可以有很高的
probability guess based on well it's
根据概率猜测，嗯，它是
kind of like so you push them on things
有点像这样，所以你推动他们去做某些事。
and see what they've done have they
看看他们都做了些什么！
taken risk how do they respond to risk
他们承担风险，他们如何应对风险
are they trying to persuade themselves
他们是在试图说服自己吗？
that the thing that they're doing is
他们正在做的是
zero risk no no no I'm guaranteed to
零风险，绝对没问题，我保证。
succeed no one is does it m does it help
没有人成功，这样做有用吗？
if they've been through some difficult
如果他们经历过一些困难
things in their life oh yeah because
他们生活中的事情，哦，是的，因为
then if they've gone through the
那么如果他们已经经历过
difficult things and they've been
困难的事情，而且一直如此。
resilient in there that's likely not
那里的韧性可能不强
100% that gives a good probability
100% 这给出了很高的概率
they'll be resilient in the traumatize
他们会在创伤中保持韧性
people well it depends on how they
这取决于人们如何看待他们
respond to the trauma right what did you
如何正确应对创伤？你做了什么？
learn from it like how did you respond
从中吸取教训，比如你是如何应对的。
to it like because generally speaking
就像这样，因为总的来说
you need to be able to convert negatives
你需要能够转换负数。
into positives right on the
直接进入正题
entrepreneurial Journey so it's like
创业之旅，就像
look that was that was really bad and I
你看，那真的太糟糕了，我
learned from it if you were advising a
如果你是顾问，就应该从中吸取教训。
young person on how to build wealth in
年轻人如何积累财富
2025 huh and when I say young I mean 18
2025年？嗯，我说年轻是指18岁。
years old yeah what would you and you
几岁了，是啊，你会怎么样？
had to to plan out the road map of their
他们必须制定路线图。
life can you walk me through how you'd
人生，你能带我走一走，告诉我你会怎么做吗？
be thinking about those seasons of life
思考人生中的那些阶段
like 18 to 30 30 onwards Etc
比如18到30岁，30岁及以上等等
so part of the reason I wrote startup
所以我写《创业公司》这本书的部分原因就是这个。
review was that the advice that
审查结果是，建议是
universities frequently give is you know
大学经常提供的就是你知道的
Follow Your Passion first do the things
首先追随你的热情，去做那些事。
that you're really passion about oh you
你真的对你充满热情
want to go volunteer in Bhutan do it now
想去不丹做志愿者？现在就去！
is tends to be and it's terrible advice
这种情况往往如此，而且这是个糟糕的建议。
right they that that actually is the the
没错，他们说那确实是
wrong end for the advice the right thing
给错误方向的建议才是正确的做法
and it doesn't mean don't follow your
但这并不意味着不要遵循你的
passion but the right thing is to start
热情固然重要，但正确的做法是开始。
with how do I get to a place where I
我该如何到达我所在的地方？
have establish myself and have like the
我已经站稳脚跟，并且喜欢……
ability to like economically the
经济上喜欢的能力
platform and maneuver could be enough
平台和机动性可能就足够了。
wealth to be you know uh to no longer
财富，你知道，不再是了。
need a salary that was my own personal
我需要一份完全属于我自己的薪水
goal um but it also could be the I'm
目标嗯，但也可能是我
well known and have a network of
知名度高，并且拥有广泛的人脉网络
contacts of people who would want to
想要联系的人的联系方式
hire me and so forth and now I'm going
雇我之类的，现在我要走了
to go spend a year volunteering in
去那里做一年的志愿者
Bhutan because I really want to do that
不丹，因为我真的很想去那里。
right so the answer is go be vigorous
所以答案是：要充满活力。
about the thing that matters for your
关于对你来说重要的事情
entire life early and take the big risks
早早地过完了人生，并且承担了很大的风险。
outly yeah take the big risk early right
没错，要尽早承担大风险，对吧？
now you might say I want to be a doctor
现在你可能会说，我想成为一名医生
it's not particularly risky it's fine
没什么特别的风险，没问题。
but then go to medical school establish
但之后要去医学院深造
yourself as as as as a medical
你自己就像一名医生
professional and so before you do that
专业人士，所以在你这样做之前……
so whatever thing that is the thing that
所以，不管那是什么，那就是
you think gives you the platform for
你认为这能为你提供平台
resilience in your later life go esta
晚年韧性
Lish that now and by the way that's part
现在就是这样，顺便说一句，那是一部分
of the thing of like wealthy but Wealthy
就像富有一样，但富有
by the way could be measured in I have a
顺便说一下，可以用我有一个来衡量
bank balance right or on stock Equity
银行存款余额或股票权益
portfolio but wealthy can also be the I
投资组合，但富有也可以是 I
have a great network of people who want
拥有一个庞大的人脉网络，这些人都渴望……
to work with me who want to hire me who
想和我一起工作的人，谁想雇佣我？
value my talents right so this whole
重视我的才能，对吧？所以这一切
range uh for things but go establish
范围呃，为了事情，但要建立
that first and that can be take big RIS
首先，这可以成为一项重要的战略举措。
if you if by the way some people say I
如果你，顺便说一句，有些人说我
want to take as few big risks as
尽量减少承担重大风险
possible possible in my whole life
我一生中所有可能的事情
because that's who I am fine but go
因为我就是这样的人，没关系，但走吧
establish yourself first now if you're
如果你是，那就先从现在开始站稳脚跟。
going to be entrepreneur you want to be
你想成为企业家吗？
an entrepreneur then like for example
例如，一位企业家
like okay maybe you shouldn't start a
好吧，也许你不应该开始
business at 18 but maybe you should go
18岁就开始做生意，但也许你应该去
join a
加入
startup right start learning it start
创业之道，从学习开始
building the network and it's roughly
构建网络，大致如此
build the network is the broad thing and
构建网络是件大事，
by the way build the skills and you know
顺便说一句，培养技能，你就会明白
get like frequently doing a startup is
经常做创业工作就像……
very difficult economically usually you
经济上通常非常困难
start with no salary Etc like having
一开始没有薪水等等，比如……
some reserves is a good thing to have I
留点积蓄是件好事。
read a book and in the first chapter I
我读了一本书，在第一章里……
was trying to figure out what this
试图弄清楚这是什么
platform is for young people and the way
平台面向年轻人，以及他们的方式
that I kind of described it is these
我刚才描述的就是这些。
five buckets the first one being
五个桶，第一个是
knowledge and then when knowledge is
知识，以及当知识是
applied it becomes a skill and the good
运用它就成为一种技能，而且是好事。
thing about these first two buckets is
前两个桶的特点是
they're the only two that no one can
他们是唯二无人能及的人。
ever really um empty of what you put in
永远无法真正清空你投入的东西
there yes the next one I posited was me
是的，我提出的下一个人就是我。
trying to remember my own book was um
努力回忆我自己的书是……
your I'm gonna say Network y then your
你的，我要说的是网络y，然后是你的
resources and your reputation now anyone
资源和你的声誉现在任何人都可以拥有
can take these last three like life can
可以像生活一样接受这最后三个。
happen you can get five you can lose
碰巧你得了五分，你可能会输。
your friends whatever um Well network is
你的朋友，嗯，网络是
hard to
很难
lose if youve really authentically built
如果你真的用心打造了一切，即使失败也是值得的。
it right it can be lost there it can be
它对，它可能在那里丢失，它可能
but it's very hard it's kind of like a
但这非常难，有点像……
nuclear bomb kind of thing I mean it's
就像核弹那种东西，我的意思是，它是
like like you may like one particular
就像你可能喜欢某个特定的人一样
person on you may have a real difference
你身边的人可能会有真正的不同之处。
of opinion um you know you may move and
关于意见，嗯，你知道你可能会搬家，
then fired get fired and a lot of your
然后被解雇，还有很多你的
network is but by the way even if you've
网络是，但顺便说一句，即使你已经
gotten fired if you've got a couple
如果你有几个
people at that company that you had good
那家公司里的人，你认识的那些人都很好。
relationship with they may still be part
与他们的关系可能仍然是其中的一部分
of your
你的
network so am I right in thinking that
网络，所以我的想法对吗？
the Knowledge and Skills part is really
知识和技能部分真的
the critical thing to uh prioritize when
最关键的事情是……需要优先考虑的
you yeah well sof this is part of what
是的，嗯，所以这是其中的一部分。
we did in SAR view soft assets are very
我们在 SAR 视图中所做的软资产非常
important people under prioritize them
重要人物往往忽视它们
they tend to say oh I should take the
他们往往会说，哦，我应该带上
job that offers me a 5% higher salary
一份薪水比之前高5%的工作
and the answer is almost always that's
答案几乎总是如此。
not the criteria that you should be
这不是你应该遵循的标准。
looking at even 30% higher SI salary is
即使考虑比SI高出30%的薪资也是
not the criteria you should be looking
这不是你应该考虑的标准。
at you should be looking at where are my
你应该看看我的在哪里
soft assets where's my knowledge where's
软资产方面，我的知识在哪里？
my skills where's my network
我的技能在哪里？我的人脉在哪里？
interesting because the soft assets are
有趣的是，软资产是
what compound generally to the much
通常情况下，哪些化合物与大量
larger like the fact that you took a job
比你找到工作这件事本身更重要
with a 30% higher salary is not
薪水高出30%并非如此。
necessarily the predictor that you're
未必是你的预测指标
going to get the job with a 300% higher
即将获得这份工作，薪水比之前高出300%。
salary it's the soft assets that are
薪资待遇中，软资产才是关键。
likely to get to the 300% economic
很可能达到300%的经济增长率。
outcome so shortterm versus longterm So
所以，短期与长期的结果如何？
Soft assets are longevity yes and the
软资产具有持久性，是的，而且
and the hard assets I guess are short
我猜想，硬资产短缺。
term yes immediate is there a different
期限是立即生效，还有其他选择吗？
game you play when you hit your 30s do
你30岁以后玩的游戏
you think well you have to evolve it so
你觉得你需要让它进化，所以
for example you can when you're in your
例如，当你在……的时候，你可以……
20s you can say well I'm gonna I'm gonna
20多岁的时候你可以说，好吧，我要，我要
take more risk like the economics take
像经济学那样承担更多风险
the the the jobs that have zero salary
那些没有薪水的工作
or lower salary because I'm going to
或者因为我要去其他地方而降低薪水
live in the house with five of my
和我的五个孩子一起住在房子里
friends you know we're to have beans and
朋友们，你们知道我们要吃豆子，
toast for dinner you know d d d da as
你知道晚餐吃吐司吗？
ways of doing it CU I can take those
做这件事的方法，我可以接受。
risks now and then when you're 30 it's
30岁的时候，偶尔冒点险也是正常的。
like well maybe I'm planning on having a
比如，我可能正计划……
life partner and being in an apartment
生活伴侣和住在公寓里
or a house with them and soth so so it
或者和他们一起住的房子之类的，就这样
changes as you go through and then you
随着你的经历而改变，然后你
have kids yes did you have kids no um
有孩子吗？有。你有孩子吗？没有。嗯……
because I'm I'm in that region now where
因为我现在就在那个地区
I'm thinking about having kids and I'm
我正在考虑要不要孩子，而且我
just I'm wondering how dis disruptive
我只是想知道干扰程度如何。
it's going to be it's another startup
它将会是另一家初创公司。
like it's fine you can do startups and
比如，你可以创办初创公司，这没问题。
have it but it's a complete startup
我有，但它完全是一家初创公司。
which do you think low is your chance of
你认为你最不可能的概率是多少？
being successful at a startup because
在创业公司取得成功的原因是
doing two startups is more difficult
同时创办两家公司更难
than doing one probably a little yeah
比做一件事可能稍微有点儿是的
but maybe worth it on balance okay yeah
但权衡之下或许值得，好吧。
what is happiness to you because you've
对你来说，幸福是什么？因为你已经
got the money you've got the success
有了钱，你就成功了。
you've got the reputation you've got the
你已经有了声誉，你已经有了
the CV what is happiness for me is going
简历中提到的幸福对我来说就是……
through life with people I love and
与我爱的人一起度过一生
building great things but like by the
创造伟大的事物，但就像……
way if I failed at everything I built
如果我建造的所有东西都失败了怎么办？
and I was still going through life with
我依然在经历着这一切。
people people I loved
我爱的人，我爱的人。
great why is that so
太好了，为什么会这样？
important because I think part of the
很重要，因为我认为部分
meaning of life is how you contribute to
生命的意义在于你如何为……做出贡献
the to the people around you it it's
对周围的人来说，这是
like again I sorry I keep referring the
再次抱歉，我总是提到……
startup of you but it was my first book
你的创业故事，但那是我第一本书。
Is advice the young people right it's
给年轻人的建议是对的
the I and the Wii like like like do
我和 Wii 就像喜欢一样
things for yourself do things for the
为自己做事，为他人做事。
for for me do things for we right and I
对我来说，做事是为了我们自己，而我
I learn from people I get Delight from
我从那些让我感到快乐的人身上学习。
people um I feel meaningful as I
人们，嗯，我觉得这很有意义，因为我
contribute to people's lives and
为人们的生活做出贡献
obviously you know there's people
显然你知道那里有人
immediately around me there's people in
我周围都有人
the whole world I mean like you know
我的意思是，全世界，你知道的
LinkedIn billion people have signed up
LinkedIn已有10亿人注册
for it like like there's there is there
就像那里有它一样
is um like that's part of what I think
嗯，这大概就是我的想法之一吧。
is essential in the in the meaning of
在意义上是至关重要的
life and for me
生活，对我来说
especially how did you have happiness
尤其是，你是如何获得幸福的？
wrong when you were
当你犯错的时候
younger if in any way
更年轻（如果以任何方式）
um I probably
嗯，我可能
thought like it was important to be top
我觉得成为顶尖人物很重要。
of your
你的
class not that it was important to just
阶级并不是说它很重要，只是
do well but it's important to be top
做得好，但更重要的是名列前茅。
right and what I've come to realize is
没错，我逐渐意识到的是……
you know there 8 billion people right
你知道世界上有80亿人口吧？
nobody is the best at
没有人是这方面最好的
everything right some people delude
一切都对，有些人却自欺欺人
themselves that they are but but nobody
他们自己是，但是没有人
is you could be the best at something
你有可能成为某个领域的佼佼者。
and by the the way being the best at
顺便说一句，他是最棒的
something that's good thing but by the
这是件好事，但是……
way to really be obsessive about the
真正痴迷于此的方式
being the be the absolute best at that
成为那方面的绝对佼佼者
thing well maybe you're
或许你是……
actually uh being you're you're less
实际上，呃，因为你是你，你更少
investing in other things it's a little
投资其他东西有点
bit like your earlier question about
有点像你之前问的那个问题
managing like you say you'll be I I'm an
像你说的那样管理，我是一个
Oracle and I'll tell you you'll be four
Oracle 和我都会告诉你，你会是四个
times as economically successful if
经济上取得巨大成功，如果
you're a [__] to the people you work
你对你同事来说就是个混蛋
with n no uh not okay for
不，呃，不行。
me and love how does love come into all
我和爱，爱是如何融入这一切的？
of this you're you're in you have a
在这其中，你身处其中，你拥有一个
long-term life partner yes yeah uh in
长期伴侣 是的，嗯，在
Seattle what role has that played in in
西雅图在其中扮演了什么角色？
your happiness and your professional
你的幸福和你的职业
success for me all the people around me
我的成功就是我身边所有人的成功。
are people I learn from and that
他们是我能学习的人，而且
includes Michelle like I learn all kinds
包括米歇尔，就像我学习各种东西一样
of things from Michelle Michelle are
米歇尔·米歇尔的东西
actually both in some ways very similar
实际上，两者在某些方面非常相似。
people deep belief in ethics deep belief
人们对伦理道德有着深厚的信念
in The Importance of Being a good person
在《做一个好人的重要性》
and in some ways very different she like
在某些方面，她非常与众不同
I'm Mr scale she's anti- scale right she
我是称重先生，她是反称重的，对吧？
she she thinks she's fine with my doing
她觉得我这么做她没意见。
the scale things but like she wants to
规模的事情，但就像她想要的那样
go connect with local people in the
去和当地人交流。
community right like she's like look I'm
社区权利就像她会说的那样：看，我是
volunteering in the senior center will
在老年中心做义工将
you come volunteer with me no no no I
你来跟我一起做志愿者？不不不，我
don't do that I'm happy to give money to
别那样做，我很乐意捐钱。
the senior center but that's not what I
老年中心，但那不是我
do but that that's that's her life and I
没错，但那是她的人生，而我
learn from that because by the way life
从中吸取教训，因为顺便说一句，人生就是如此。
is both life is both here and here so so
生命既在这里，也在这儿，就是这样。
it's it's one of the balance of
这是平衡之一
different people she she is intensely
她和不同的人，她非常……
going in she's taking this kind of call
她进去的时候正在接这种电话
it Quaker Buddhist approach to creating
这是贵格会佛教式的创造方法
art right and and that's just amazing
对吧，这真是太棒了！
like I love being on that Journey with
我喜欢和他们一起踏上这段旅程。
her right um and that's her journey
她的右手，嗯，这就是她的旅程
right um but I learned from it and those
对，嗯，但我从中吸取了教训，还有那些
are the kinds of things that are that
就是那种类型的事情。
are um you know part of what I think the
嗯，你知道，这是我想法的一部分
meaning of life is is how we learn from
生命的意义在于我们如何从中学习
each other when if two entrepreneurs
如果两个企业家互相……
come to you and they the exact same
来到你身边，他们也一模一样
thing but one of them is in a long-term
但其中一件是长期的。
marriage what is the difference between
婚姻与……有什么区别
those two entrepreneurs in terms of how
就这两位企业家而言，他们是如何
they'll show up in business in your
他们会在你的企业中出现。
view interesting I've never been asked
我觉得这很有意思，我从来没被问过这个问题。
that question uh it depends
这个问题……嗯，这要看情况。
um I do
嗯，我愿意。
think like one of the things that I
我觉得这就像我做过的其中一件事。
treat as a very relevant fact is how
将其视为一个非常重要的事实，就是如何做到这一点。
someone treats the people around them
有人对待周围的人
okay so it's somewhat evidenced that
好的，所以这在某种程度上证明了……
there yes yes so like if a person is
是的，是的，所以就像如果一个人是
good to the people around them then
然后他们就对周围的人很好。
that's a person I am more likely to much
那是我更有可能喜欢的人。
more much much more likely to want to go
更有可能想去
through because like a startup is like
因为就像创业公司一样
10 years like I have passed on
就像我一样，已经过去了10年。
investments that I've literally referred
我曾亲自推荐过的投资项目
to and I won't name them because it's
还有，我就不点名了，因为……
uncivil but I've literally passed on
虽然不礼貌，但我真的已经放弃了。
investments that I thought this is going
我当时认为这些投资会……
to make a ton of money and I've told my
为了赚很多钱，我已经告诉我的
partners at Greylock hey look this
Greylock 的合伙人，嘿，看看这个
entrepreneur and this business this is
企业家和这家企业
going to make a lot of money if any of
如果其中任何一项……就能赚很多钱
you want to do it great and I will
你想把它做好，我会的。
support you but I don't want to invest
我支持你，但我不想投资。
because I don't want to spend the 10
因为我不想花这10
years with this
多年来一直如此
entrepreneur right because it's just you
对，创业者是对的，因为只有你一个人。
know Life's Too Short right uh and I was
我知道“人生苦短”，对吧？嗯，我当时
right those businesses made a ton of
没错，那些企业赚了很多钱。
money right but it was yeah no no thanks
钱对，但是，不，谢谢。
not worth a headache yes when I was
不值得为此头疼，是的，当我
reading Blitz scaling and I was watching
阅读闪电战的规模调整，我当时正在观看
the videos that you did you've done
你制作的那些视频
several talks on it I've seen pretty
我看过好几个关于这个主题的演讲。
much all of them over the years um one
多年来，他们中的许多人……嗯，一个
of the questions I had as an investor
作为投资者，我曾有过一些疑问。
myself is my early stage companies that
我自己就是我早期阶段的公司。
aren't in cons the consumer Internet
并非消费者互联网的骗局
space they're selling I don't know they
我不知道他们卖的是什么空间
might be selling a a drink in a
可能正在卖饮料
supermarket or something should should
超市之类的应该应该
they all be pursu pursuing this idea of
他们都会追求这个想法
blit Blitz scaling where you go
闪电战规模化，随你而行
lightning fast to building a mass
闪电般迅速地积累质量
massively valuable
价值连城
company not necessarily okay uh Blitz
公司未必没问题，呃，闪电战
scaling is a strategic response to
规模化是应对……的战略性措施
Global competition okay right and so now
全球竞争，好的，就是这样。
there are certain industries where
在某些行业，
Global competition is the norm not the
全球竞争是常态，而不是……
exception You're Building an Internet
例外情况：您正在构建互联网
Property right MH right or mostly like
财产权 MH 权 或类似
much software not all software but most
很多软件，并非所有软件，但大多数都是如此。
like many software companies in which
就像许多软件公司一样，
case and by the way if you can get away
顺便说一句，如果你能逃脱的话
with not Blitz scaling it's much better
不考虑闪电战的成长性，效果要好得多。
because Blitz scaling is spending
因为闪电战的规模扩张需要花费资金。
resources
资源
inefficiently to get to Market size
以低效的方式达到市场规模
ahead of your competition right so like
领先于你的竞争对手，对吧？
a classic example is like you know uh
一个经典的例子就是你知道的……
Uber
优步
would interview somebody offer them a
会面试某人并向他们提供……
job and then say who are the three best
先做这份工作，然后说说哪三个人最好。
people at your company that that that
你公司里有人说……
you worked with and send job offers to
你曾与以下人员合作并向他们发送工作邀请
those three people without even
那三个人甚至都没有
interview them them right because that's
对他们进行正确的采访，因为那才是最重要的。
Blitz scaling right that's I'm going
闪电战的规模调整是对的，我就要走了
super super
超级超级
fast and uh and that that was a blitz
速度很快，而且，那是一场闪电战
scaling technique I learned from Uber I
我从 Uber 学到的扩展技术
was like oh yep put that one in the tool
当时我就想，哦，对，把那个放进工具里。
chest for when you need to do that right
当你需要正确执行该操作时，可以使用胸罩。
because outpacing the competition when
因为超越竞争对手
you're in Glen Gary Glenn Ross markets
您位于格伦加里格伦罗斯市场
which is first prize Cadillac second
第一名是凯迪拉克，第二名是
prize steak knives third prize you're
奖品是牛排刀，三等奖是……
fired it's the
被解雇了
game right and it's one of the things
游戏玩得对，这是其中之一。
like when you know you and I were
就像你知道你和我曾经是
chatting a little bit before we started
开始前我们聊了一会儿。
the podcast like one of the places that
播客就像是某个地方……
things that places like you know London
你知道伦敦这样的地方会发生的事情
and the UK and Europe need to learn is
英国和欧洲需要学习的是
when the competition is global it's not
当竞争是全球性的，情况就不同了。
the people down the street it's the
街上的人们，就是
fiercest competitors around the world
全世界最激烈的竞争对手
and Silicon Valley has Fierce
硅谷拥有强大的实力
competitors China has Fierce compe you
中国竞争对手实力雄厚，竞争激烈。
have to have a theory of how you're
你必须对你如何……有一个理论
playing that game against those the
和那些人玩那场比赛
fiercest competitors in the world and so
世界上最激烈的竞争对手，因此
um Blitz scaling is in part like this is
嗯，闪电战的规模调整在某种程度上就是这样的。
stuff I've learned from Silicon Valley
我从硅谷学到的东西
and from the stuff I've done in China to
以及我在中国所做的事情
say like when you're in a global
比如当你身处全球环境时
competitive business and you're trying
竞争激烈的商业环境，而你正在努力
to establish it and you have competitors
要建立它，你还有竞争对手。
who are doing this this is some of the
参与这项工作的人包括以下几人：
techniques that you need to do if AI is
如果人工智能是……，你需要掌握的技术
going to be so transformative when you
当你……的时候，这将会带来巨大的改变。
think about a country like the UK where
想想像英国这样的国家，
you know we don't have the blitz scaling
你知道我们没有闪电战那种规模优势。
advantages as entrepreneurs and Founders
作为企业家和创始人的优势
that you guys have in Silicon
你们硅谷的那些人
Valley if you were the prime minister of
如果你是总理，Valley
the
这
UK what would you do to give us a shot
英国，你们会怎么做才能给我们一次机会？
at getting some of the value that's
获取其中一些价值
going to acrw because of this air
因为这种空气，我要去acrw。
opportunity so I think there's two
机会，所以我认为有两个。
things one is you need to enable some of
第一件事是你需要启用一些功能
your company's ability to Blitz scale as
贵公司快速扩展的能力
much as you can right okay so because if
尽可能多地写，好的，因为如果
if if a company if company one is not
如果一家公司不是
Blitz scaling and is competing against
Blitz 正在迅速扩张，并与……竞争
Company 2 that is Blitz scaling company
第二家公司，即 Blitz 规模化公司
one's going to lose I don't think we've
肯定会有一方输，我觉得我们还没输过。
got any AI companies that are blit
有没有哪家人工智能公司正在快速发展？
scaling in company one is going to lose
公司一的规模扩张将会失败
right company two might lose too right
正确的公司二也可能输掉比赛
but company one is guaranteed to lose
但第一家公司注定会输
and Company two is not guaranteed to
第二家公司不能保证
lose right so if you're competing
如果你在比赛中输了，那就对了。
against companies that are Blitz scaling
对抗那些正在闪电式扩张的公司
you must also be Blitz scaling it's part
你也必须参与闪电战的规模扩张。
of the the reason I wrote the book it's
这就是我写这本书的原因。
part of the reason I give talks it's
我做演讲的部分原因在于……
part of the reason I help uh Sher kou
我帮助雪儿的部分原因在于……
standup the scale the scaling Institute
建立规模化研究所
here in London you know etc etc now you
你知道，在伦敦等等等等，现在你
say we can't we're not going to be able
说我们不能，我们做不到
to well then choose areas where the
然后选择合适的区域
competitors are not blit scaling I've
竞争对手并没有进行闪电式扩张，我已经……
got a example I want to give you I
我有个例子想给你举。
invest in a matcha company they make
投资他们生产的抹茶公司
matcha like the you know green tea and
抹茶，就像你知道的绿茶一样。
they've they've grown very very quickly
它们生长得非常非常快。
they call perfect T hash ad I'm an
他们称之为完美T哈希广告，我是一个
investor Etc new investor in the company
投资者 Etc 公司新投资者
I think um and I was wondering they've G
我想嗯，我在想他们有没有G
so quickly so they've gone from I don't
这么快，他们就从“我不”变成了“我不”。
know zero to they'll probably do maybe
他们可能一无所知，也许会这么做
30 million pounds next year and they've
明年预算为3000万英镑，他们已经
done it in
完成了
a could be measured in months really and
确实可以用几个月来衡量。
I wondered I was like match is this
我当时就在想，这到底是怎么回事？
trend that's coming into Shore
海岸地区正在兴起的趋势
everyone's drinking match now every
现在每个人都在进行饮酒比赛
coffee shop you go to has
你去的那家咖啡店有
matcha should they be Blitz scaling to
抹茶应该在闪电战中达到什么程度？
capture the opportunity globally so it
抓住全球机遇，因此
depends on two things one most centrally
取决于两件事，其中一件最为重要
comp competition do they need to be
竞争是否需要他们参与
outpacing their compet
超越竞争对手
ition could argue yes yeah but if yes
有人可能会说是的，但如果是的话
then and especially if their competitors
然后，尤其是当他们的竞争对手
are Blitz scaling then absolutely yes if
Blitz 的强度是否足够？如果 Blitz 的强度足够高，那么答案绝对是肯定的。
the commits are not Blitz scaling it's
提交记录并非闪电战式扩展，而是
all will Blitz scaling enable us to
所有这些都将使闪电战规模化使我们能够
outpace them because by the way it does
超越他们，因为顺便说一句，它确实如此。
involve moving so fast you're taking
移动速度如此之快，以至于你……
risks and hiring and capital raise and
风险、招聘和融资
expenditures you're doing marketing that
你在市场营销方面的支出
you would like you're uber you're you're
你会喜欢你，你是优步，你是，你是
launching in 20 cities at the same time
同时在20个城市推出
it's whoa you know
哇，你知道吗？
Etc because that does add risks right
等等，因为这确实会增加风险，对吧？
but you're saying those risks that it
但你的意思是，这些风险……
adds are less of a risk than not spit
吐痰的风险比不吐痰要小。
scaling that's kind of the tradeoff so
规模化就是这种权衡取舍。
competition is a central reason for
竞争是其核心原因之一
doing it and by the way most of the
这样做，顺便说一句，大部分
compan most of the times where you can
大多数情况下，你可以和公司一起合作。
raise Capital bit scaling is because if
提高资本金位规模是因为如果
you if it's a Glen Gary Glenn Ross
如果你是格伦·加里·格伦·罗斯的话
Market where first prizes Cadillac
凯迪拉克赢得头奖的市场
second priz steak knives well then
二等奖牛排刀，嗯。
generally speaking investors are willing
一般来说，投资者愿意
to invest
投资
at premium prices give a lot of capital
以溢价出售可获得大量资金
etc etc because they'll go we agree that
等等等等，因为他们会去，我们同意这一点。
you're going to get a great Market
你将迎来一个绝佳的市场。
position if you Blitz
如果你闪电战
scale and by the way part of the problem
规模，顺便说一句，这也是问题的一部分。
is investors are not always right but if
投资者并非总是正确的，但如果
some investors are willing to do it then
当时有些投资者愿意这样做。
and they're going to do it in your
他们会在你的……中这样做。
competitors then you absolutely have to
那么，如果你有竞争对手，你就绝对必须这样做。
do it if your competitor is going to do
如果你的竞争对手打算这样做，你也应该这样做。
it so competition is the first thing the
因此，竞争是首要的。
second thing is do you need to get to
第二件事是，你需要到达
critical mass scale so like your
临界质量尺度，就像你的
payments industry and this is one of the
支付行业，这是其中之一
things I learned to PayPal which is
我在PayPal上学到的东西是
basically payments businesses are dead
支付业务基本上已经消亡了。
unless they have at least a billion you
除非他们至少有十亿你
know dollars of you know transactional
了解美元交易
volume through them per year and that
它们每年的交易量以及
was back in 2002 what I was looking I'm
那是2002年的时候，我一直在寻找的东西。
sure it's higher now right maybe it's 10
现在肯定更高了，可能到10了。
billion whatever but it's like if you
亿万什么的，但就像如果你
don't get to that scale you're dead
别达到那种程度，你就死定了。
you're irrelevant right so getting to
你无关紧要，对吧？所以，开始
that scale and getting through the
达到那种规模并克服它
highly unprofitable getting the scale as
获得规模化生产效率极低，利润微薄。
fast as possible really matters and so
速度越快越好，这一点至关重要。
that's one of the places where you say
这是你说的其中一个例子。
well we're none of our competitors are
嗯，我们和我们的竞争对手都不是。
doing it but we should still do it
我们正在做这件事，但我们仍然应该做这件事。
because getting that critical mass and
因为要达到临界规模和
scale really matters um and so that's
规模真的很重要，嗯，就是这样。
another time and and so that would be I
另一次，所以那就是我
don't think that's probably the the
别以为那就是……
matcha company right that that's
抹茶公司说得对，那就是
probably like doesn't need so but those
可能不需要，但是那些
are the the lessons you look at but it's
这些都是你所看到的教训，但它是
not Blitz scaling for its own sake
并非为了闪电战本身而进行规模调整
that's one of the mistakes that people
这是人们常犯的错误之一。
make when they go Blitz scaling oh we're
当他们进行闪电战时，哦，我们
doing it two Blitz scales no no you
用两个闪电战等级？不不，你
Blitz scale as a set of strategic
闪电战规模作为一套战略
techniques in response to a market and
为应对市场而采取的技术
response to competition mhm and in the
对竞争的回应嗯，在
case of
案例
matcher there is a role of brand being
匹配器中品牌扮演着重要角色
the mo a little bit yes and so that may
有点儿，是的，所以那可能
be irrelevant that may be the relevant
无关紧要的，但可能相关的
thing of why it's a glen gar in the I
想想为什么它是格伦加尔（Glen Gar）
haven't looked at the market at all but
我根本没关注过市场，但是
a glen gar Gad Ross Market a first prize
格伦加尔·加德·罗斯市场一等奖
Cadillac second prize steak guys maybe
凯迪拉克二等奖牛排伙计们，也许
that's because of brand establishment
这是因为品牌建立的缘故。
which case you have to be number one and
哪种情况下你必须成为第一？
on that point that I asked earlier about
关于我之前问的那点……
if you're the prime minister of the UK
如果你是英国首相
you'd start enabling some of our
你会开始启用我们的一些功能
companies in the UK to like have more
英国公司更喜欢拥有更多
Capital give them access to Capital do
资本使他们能够获得资本。
you think
您认为
one of my fears is that AI is such a big
我担心的一点是，人工智能的影响如此之大
opportunity it's going to revolutionize
这将是一次变革的机遇
everything and it's basically going to
一切，基本上都会是
be owned by America and China it's one
它由美国和中国共同拥有。
of my fears it's like fears of someone
我的恐惧就像是对某人的恐惧一样。
that lives in the UK that we're gonna
住在英国的那个人，我们将
your economy is gonna in the US is gonna
你们的经济将会怎样？在美国将会怎样？
have such a huge upswing in productivity
生产力出现了如此巨大的提升。
so good news for you is I happen to know
好消息是，我碰巧认识你
that t ding street is paying attention
那条丁街正在关注
to this issue because I had meetings
因为我开会，所以才讨论这个问题。
with him this week on that there's
本周他将就此事发表意见。
things that they will be announcing
他们将要宣布的事情
which I can't pre-announce okay right
我不能提前宣布，好吗？
but they know this is important and
但他们知道这很重要，
they're working on it
他们正在努力。
okay and they're Consulting you know
好的，他们是咨询公司，你知道的。
people good yeah yeah that's what gives
人们很好，是啊，就是这样。
me hope yes okay what's the most
我希望是的，好的，最重要的是什么
important thing we haven't talked about
一件我们还没谈到的重要事情
for entrepreneurs that we should have
对于我们应该拥有的企业家来说
talked about I'll give two
谈到我会给两个
um the first
嗯，第一个
is and they're related the first is look
是，而且它们相关，第一个是看
just because you don't have a 100%
仅仅因为你没有100%
chance of succeeding doesn't mean that
成功的机会并不意味着
you shouldn't do it right so like when I
你不应该这样做，对吧？就像当我……
said earlier when we were talking about
之前我们谈到的时候说过
like look when I started LinkedIn I
就像你看，当我开始使用LinkedIn的时候
thought we had a most 20 25% chance of
我们认为最多有20%到25%的几率
being
存在
successful that's
成功就是成功。
fine right so and a matter of fact what
很好，对吧？事实上，什么？
you should be doing is aligning the fact
你应该做的是核实事实
that there's risks on what you're doing
你所做的事情是有风险的。
with the reason why you'll have less
原因在于你会减少
competition while you have a higher
虽然竞争激烈，但你的优势依然存在。
Runway before the com competition
比赛前的T台
intensifies because part of it is if you
加剧是因为其中一部分原因是如果你
have a theory like we talked about this
就像我们之前讨论的那样，有一个理论
in LinkedIn about why other people see
在领英上讨论为什么其他人会看到
that there is like they think there's a
就像他们认为存在某种东西一样
0% chance you succeed and you think
你成功的几率为0%，而你却认为
there's a 20 25% chance you succeed
你成功的可能性有20%到25%。
that's precisely that risk window is
这正是风险窗口所在。
your
你的
opportunity right so think of risk not
机会就在眼前，所以不要考虑风险。
as terrifying think of risk as potential
把风险想象成潜在的危险，这很可怕。
opportunity right that's one and we've
机会就在眼前，这是其中之一，而且我们已经……
talked about threads of it but thinking
谈到其中的一些线索，但思考
of it as opportunity right because you
把它当作一个机会，因为你
see something other people don't see you
你看到了别人看不到的东西
see the risks but you have an idea for
你看到了风险，但你有一个想法。
why that risk is something that you may
为什么这种风险是您可能面临的
be able to win on and they won't right
能够赢，但他们不会赢。
so with LinkedIn that was hey I have an
所以，有了LinkedIn，那就是：嘿，我有一个
idea about how the network will grow
关于网络如何发展的想法
even though it's not valuable until
即使它现在没有价值
there's a million people in
那里有100万人
network right that's where that risk
网络就在那儿，风险就在那里。
becomes an opportunity right so the
这便成了一个机会，对吧？
second one also around risk
第二个也与风险有关
is
是
um have a plan B have plans B understand
嗯，要有备选方案，要有备选方案，明白吗？
that you have an idea in your risk
你已经对风险有了想法。
you're playing it and if it's not
你在玩它，如果它不是
working out how do you pivot don't think
弄清楚如何转型，不要想太多
oh the whole thing is going all in and
哦，整个过程都是全力以赴。
I'm just gonna be roadkill if it doesn't
如果不行，我岂不是要被车碾死了？
work no no that's the whole point of the
工作不不，那才是重点。
reason I have this framework of abz
我之所以有这个 abz 框架，是因为它
planning which is in the startup view
创业视角下的规划
which is by the way startup view is
顺便一提，这就是启动视图。
advice they give
他们给出的建议
entrepreneurs shrunk to advice to
企业家们开始向他人寻求建议
individuals right every single chapter
每一章都有正确的人
applies to entrepreneurs in their
适用于企业家
companies right like the abz planning is
像 abz 这样的公司规划是正确的
don't just have a plan a where like well
不要只是有个计划，比如“嗯”。
if it doesn't work I'm dead you're like
如果这招不管用我就死定了，你就像……
well that's a bad strategy like
那可真是个糟糕的策略啊。
sometimes you'll do it sometimes it's
有时你会这样做，有时则不会。
the only thing I have I love this plan a
我唯一拥有的就是我喜欢这个计划。
it's the only thing I have and the only
这是我唯一拥有的东西，也是唯一的
way to do it is to go all in and doesn't
正确的做法是全力以赴，而不是
work I'm dead okay it's very
工作我死了，好吧，这很
scary right um when I do
确实挺吓人的，嗯，当我这么做的时候。
entrepreneurship I have plans B I have a
创业方面，我有备选方案。
plan Z right I I I have thought through
Z计划对吧？我已经考虑周全了。
not every because you can't think
并非总是如此，因为你无法思考
through everything but maneuverability
除了机动性之外，其他一切都无所谓
and how to measure am I on track or not
如何衡量我是否走在正确的轨道上
am I am I increasing my probability of
我是否增加了我的可能性？
success or not am I increasing my
无论成功与否，我是否在提升自己
ability to get to the moon or not and
能否登上月球以及
and be doing risk management smart risks
并进行明智的风险管理风险
take smart
明智行事
risks that's the thing right how do you
风险就是问题所在，对吧？你怎么做？
know when to quit and I'm saying this in
要知道什么时候该放弃，我这么说是因为
a Prof professional context as well as
教授的专业背景以及
an entrepreneurship context so when I
在创业背景下，当我
get around to advising companies I've
抽出时间为我曾经服务过的公司提供咨询。
invested in or friends that now is time
现在是时候投资或结交朋友了。
to quit or now is time to sell you try
是该辞职还是该卖掉你？试试看。
to sell of course but sometimes if you
当然是为了出售，但有时如果你
can't sell that means quit right is your
卖不出去就意味着放弃，对吧？
new plans your new plans a are much
你的新计划有很多
worse than your previous plans a your
比你之前的计划更糟
new plan a is much worse because you
新方案A更糟糕，因为……
pivoted yeah right and your new plan a
转变？是啊，你的新计划是……
is a much worse plan in your plan a
你的计划中有一个更糟糕的方案。
that's when you get to your plan Z it's
这时你就得执行你的零号计划了。
like plan Z is I quit
就像Z计划一样，我辞职了
right okay so you've you've tried
好的，你已经试过了。
something else that's also messed up
还有另一件同样糟糕的事
like okay and in a professional context
好的，在专业语境中
when how do you know to quit when to
何时才能戒烟？
quit the
退出
job um well it could be you have a much
工作嘛，嗯，有可能你有很多
better plan a right like like okay this
最好计划一下，比如这样，好的。
plan a that's okay and then by the way
计划一下，没问题，顺便说一句
this is part of the difference that I
这就是我与众不同之处的一部分。
tell people between should I found a
告诉人们我应该找到一个
company or should I join one it's like
我应该加入一家公司吗？
look one of the problems you have as a
看看你遇到的问题之一
Founder you can't really quit you're
创始人，你不能真的退出，你是
you're you're with the business right
你现在是这家公司的老板，对吧？
it's very dishonorable to quit before
在毕业前辞职是非常不光彩的。
you know the business gets to whatever
你知道，生意最终会发展到什么程度。
it's its design is now sometimes you're
它的设计现在有时是
fired fine but you're you know as a
开火正常，但你知道，你就像一个
Founder you're like people have come and
创始人，你就像人们已经到来一样
enjoyed this because of me being here
因为我在这里，所以很开心。
and doing this and I'm here until the
我会一直做这件事，直到……
business gets to a point where it's it's
商业发展到一定阶段，就到了该结束的地步。
a massive growing concern now once the
如今，这已成为一个日益严重的重大问题。
company's public you can go do something
公司公众可以去做一些事情
or once the company's sold you can go do
或者公司出售后，你就可以去做……
something or once the company is like
某种情况，或者一旦公司像
profitable and really strong you can go
盈利能力强，而且实力雄厚，你可以去
do something but you're there until then
做点什么，但在此之前你都得待在那里。
as a Founder as an employee you're
作为创始人或员工，你
signing up for what I'm the alliance I
我加入的联盟就是我
call a tour of beauty which is I am I've
称之为一次美景之旅，我就是，我已
I'm signed up to make a big difference
我报名参加，希望能做出一番大贡献。
in in the company but I'm not here till
我在公司，但我还没到。
the end and so as your employee you can
最后，作为你的员工，你可以
go look have I delivered against my Tour
去看看我是否完成了我的巡回赛目标
of Duty great and at that point a better
责任重大，而且在那时更好
opportunity comes along so you know uh
机会来了，你就知道……
Matt Kohler who you know now lives here
你认识的马特·科勒现在住在这里。
in London as a you know partner at
在伦敦，作为你知道的合作伙伴
Benchmark like I recruited him out of
就像我把他招进来时那样。
Mackenzie in a LinkedIn three years in
Mackenzie 在 LinkedIn 上三年
he comes to me and says hey I've been
他走过来对我说，嘿，我一直
offered this this opportunity at
提供了这个机会
Facebook I'm like look Matt I love
我在Facebook上说，看，马特，我爱
working with you you're a close friend
和你一起工作，你就像我的挚友。
of mine etc etc you should take that job
我的等等等等，你应该接受那份工作
at Facebook that is the right Next Step
在 Facebook，这是正确的下一步。
for you right and because we're close
对你来说没错，也因为我们关系亲近。
and so forth I think he probably
等等，我想他可能
wouldn't have taken the job if I hadn't
如果不是这样，我是不会接受这份工作的。
said but like LinkedIn resembles my
话虽如此，但LinkedIn就像我的……
brain I want people doing their best
我希望人们都能做到最好。
work their best opportunities and
尽其所能，做到最好
Facebook gave them a great opportunity
Facebook 给了他们一个绝佳的机会
what's really interesting about the
真正有趣的是……
LinkedIn story I've got the deck in
LinkedIn故事：我已经拿到牌组了
front of me here from August 20 2004
这是我眼前这张照片，拍摄于2004年8月20日
yes that's our Greylock series B
是的，那是我们的灰洛克B系列。
deck and what's pretty remarkable and by
甲板以及非常了不起的地方，而且
the way Matt ker how create that deck oh
Matt Ker 制作那套牌组的方式真是令人惊叹。
did he
他真的这么做了吗？
yes I mean it's a it's a pretty good
是的，我的意思是，它相当不错。
deck for a series series B especially
B 系列卡组，特别是
back then it's very simple i' to say
那时候，这很简单，我这么说。
simple as good very very simple yes one
简单易行，非常非常简单，是的。
of the things that really struck out to
真正让我印象深刻的是
me is on this page here which is the
我在这里，也就是这个页面上。
sort of opening I guess vision mission
我猜这算是愿景使命的开端吧
statement whatever you want to call it
声明，随便你怎么称呼它
is it's find and contact the people you
就是找到并联系你认识的人
need through the people you already
你需要通过你已经认识的人来获得帮助
trust and what's quite remarkable
信任，以及真正令人瞩目的地方
although this was written 20 years ago
虽然这篇文章写于20年前
this is still very much what LinkedIn is
这仍然是LinkedIn的本质。
about yes and usually when I see these
差不多吧，通常当我看到这些的时候
decks they started as I don't know hot
他们开始的牌组，我不知道热门牌组
or not and now it's like Facebook and
或者不是，现在它就像Facebook一样。
Instagram whereas this is still so close
Instagram，而这仍然如此接近
to what the vision was yeah well it's
至于最初的愿景，嗯，就是这样。
also my third company I had social net I
另外，我的第三家公司也拥有社交网络。
had PayPal PayPal pivoted a lot right
PayPal 之前做了很多调整
and so I had a good sense of both how to
因此，我对如何做到这一点都有很好的理解。
be longterm and short-term when I
当我考虑长期和短期因素时
started LinkedIn and what is the key to
创建 LinkedIn 账号的关键是什么？
being long-term in this regard well you
就这方面而言，长期来看，嗯……
know what is the you're going to
知道你要做什么
transform the industry oh and what do
改变行业格局，哦，还有什么？
you mean by key as in like
你说的“关键”是指像……那样吗？
if you're trying to build a long-term
如果你想建立一个长期的……
company from the outset yeah what are
公司从一开始就是这样的，是的，是什么？
you thinking about well you're thinking
你在想什么呢？嗯，你在想什么呢？
about like if I'm successful at landing
就像我成功着陆一样
on the beach at expanding into the
在海滩上向外扩展
market how is it that I'm going to be a
市场，我怎么可能成为一个
industry transforming company like
像这样的行业变革型公司
what's the thing that changes millions
是什么改变了数百万人的生活？
of customers lives you know um uh or if
你知道，顾客的生活，嗯，或者如果
it's an Enterprise company you know
你知道，那是一家企业级公司。
whatever like lots of companies within
就像很多公司一样
multiple Industries how am I an
我属于多个行业，我如何才能成为其中一员？
essential part of how they change the
这是他们改变方式的关键部分
way they live they work they do
他们的生活方式、他们的工作方式
business and what do you think of
商业以及你对此有何看法
LinkedIn today because people use it in
如今人们使用LinkedIn，是因为它
such a surprising way I mean people are
真是令人惊讶，我的意思是人们……
building their personal brands on it
他们以此为基础打造个人品牌
it's like a social network yeah I knew
它就像一个社交网络，是的，我知道。
that was all going to be from from
这一切都将从……开始
before this deck I knew that was
在这副牌之前，我就知道那是
possible I have a probability now what
我现在有可能知道概率了
what thing surprised me people build
让我感到惊讶的是，人们建造的东西
dating services on top of it really yes
除此之外，还有约会服务，真的吗？
well I'm in a relationship may you
嗯，我有伴侣，你呢？
haven't seen it but yeah but they're
我还没看过，不过是的，他们是
like well some people want to be dating
有些人就是想谈恋爱。
people who have professional like my
像我这样有专业素养的人
dating set is I want people who have
约会对象设定是：我想要那些有……的人。
good CVS okay I don't want LinkedIn to
简历不错，我不想在领英上添加。
ever build that business fine if you're
如果你能建立起那样的事业，那就太好了。
gonna go build that
我要去建那个
business right no problem right I mean
生意上没问题，对吧？我的意思是
and like for example like one of the ear
例如，就像耳朵的其中一只。
like this was I
就像这样，我
think uh a few months after we raised
想想看，在我们筹集资金几个月后
money from Greylock um on this deck um
这套牌组里有来自灰锁的钱。
one of the surprising uses is like I
其中一个令人惊讶的用途就像我
never had envisioned this use case still
从未设想过这种使用场景
looking for a job an engineer wanted to
一位工程师正在寻找工作
move to Denver from Silicon Valley and
从硅谷搬到丹佛
so it's like didn't know what companies
所以就好像不知道哪些公司
to look at so this engineer went to
为了查看情况，这位工程师去了
LinkedIn and searched for profiles like
LinkedIn 并搜索了类似这样的个人资料。
his then looked at what companies those
然后他看了看那些公司。
people worked at then decided which
人们先在哪工作，然后决定去哪
companies to go look for jobs at it was
公司去那里找工作是
brilliant like it's a very good way of
太棒了，这真是个好办法
saying hey I'm look I'm interested in
我说，嘿，我听着，我对……感兴趣
going and working here
来这里工作和生活
what kinds of companies that are
哪些类型的公司
interesting employ people like
有趣的是，雇佣像我们这样的人很有趣
me are you still interested in building
你还对建造感兴趣吗？
companies in terms of like being a CEO
就公司而言，比如担任首席执行官
and founder again well so I co-founded
再次成为创始人，所以我是联合创始人。
inflection so I'm definitely doing the
语调，所以我肯定是在做
co-founding thing right um and you know
共同创立这件事，对吧，嗯，你知道的
I I anticipate that will happen again um
我预计这种情况还会再次发生。
but will I be the CEO it's not
但我会成为首席执行官吗？这还不好说。
impossible um but it's kind of like
不可能，嗯，但有点像……
because I have these amazing people like
因为我拥有这些很棒的人，比如
Mustafa suan who the COO that I can be
Mustafa Suan，他是首席运营官，我可以成为他。
the co-founder
联合创始人
with that's
就是这样
great yeah I think that's the season of
太好了，我想这就是那个季节了。
life I'm in yeah I don't want to be a
我现在的处境，是的，我不想成为……
CEO anymore which is unfortunate because
首席执行官不再担任此职，这很可惜，因为
I named the podcast I have a CEO when I
我把播客命名为《我有一位CEO》，当时我
was one but I just think there's an
曾经有一个，但我认为还有一个
element of self-awareness which I think
我认为，自我意识的某个要素是……
has really it's and for me the older
确实如此，对我来说，老一辈的
I've gotten the more I'm orientating
我越了解情况就越明白
everything towards being happy yeah and
一切都是为了快乐，是的。
for me it's it's hard to be a CEO and as
对我来说，当CEO很难，而且……
happy as I and free as I want to be so
我如此快乐，如此自由，我如此渴望如此。
then then then you need to build the
然后，然后，然后你需要建造
network and skills by which you're
你的人脉和技能
working with other people who are the
与其他这样的人一起工作
CEOs that's basically what I do now so
CEO们，这基本上就是我现在的工作。
the companies that I've described the
我所描述的这些公司
software business the media company we
软件业务 媒体公司 我们
have here there's people that are
这里有些人
designed and built and much better CEOs
精心设计、建造，以及更优秀的CEO们
than me what do you do you care about
比我更甚，你关心什么？
Legacy only because I care about impact
之所以选择传承，是因为我重视影响。
um so I don't like I I care that I I've
嗯，所以我不喜欢，我不在乎，我已经
actually made a big difference to the
实际上对……产生了很大的影响
ongoing story of humanity um but I don't
人类的故事仍在继续，嗯，但我并不这么认为。
that I mean look it's nice I like I
我的意思是，你看，它很漂亮，我喜欢。
certainly don't mind that people go oh
当然不介意别人发出“哦”的声音。
Reed Hoffman did these amazing things it
里德·霍夫曼做了这些惊人的事情
feels good but I care much more about
感觉不错，但我更在乎的是
the substance like did I do really good
就像我做得真的好吗？
things that was I a very positive impact
那些对我产生非常积极影响的事情
now I'm I'm not I'm not indicating I
现在我不是，我不是在暗示我
have no ego you know the the
你知道，不要自负。
appreciation for having done that that
感谢你做了这件事
feels good but I don't do it for the
感觉很好，但我做这件事不是为了……
appreciation I do it for the
我这样做是为了表达我的感激之情。
thing so do you make decisions based on
所以你会根据什么来做决定？
Legacy at all
传承
only a by
仅由
impact did you did you decide not to
影响有多大？你决定不这么做了吗？
have children uh we did um and it was a
我们有孩子，嗯，那是一个
joint decision of course and I think it
当然，这是共同决定，我认为……
was partially that we realiz we're um
部分原因是我们意识到我们……
you know we're God Parents to a number
你知道我们是很多孩子的教父母。
of children we actually there's three
我们家有三个孩子。
kids here in London that that we're God
伦敦的孩子们认为我们是上帝
Parents to right and uh you know there's
父母对，你知道还有
all kinds of Delights in being a God
成为神所带来的各种喜悦
parent which is you know you show up and
父母，你知道，你出现就意味着……
spend an evening and get to participate
花一个晚上时间参与其中
and and the kids lives and then you know
孩子们的生活，然后你知道
when it's like oh time to change the
当感觉好像该换衣服的时候
diaper and
尿布和
it are there any unchecked boxes in your
你的表格中是否有任何未勾选的复选框？
life I'm sure there are um any major
生活中，我确信会有……嗯，任何重大的
ones yeah
是的
um if you'd ask me um what book um I was
嗯，如果你问我，嗯，什么书，嗯，我当时在……
going to first write when I was an
我第一次写这篇文章的时候还是个……
undergraduate was book on friendship I
本科时读过一本关于友谊的书。
still want to write that book I I've
我仍然想写那本书，我已经……
been taking notes for 30 years on
30年来一直在做笔记
friendship on friendship yep um what
友谊中的友谊，嗯，什么？
would that book be about friendship but
那本书是关于友谊的吗？
specifically what part of why why
具体来说，是哪一部分原因？
everything look there's so few books on
你看，书真少啊。
friendship you go into to a bookstore
你走进书店，与朋友相识
and you say where is your uh your
然后你说你的……你的……在哪里？
section on relationships and they every
关系部分，以及他们每个人
bookstore will go oh over here right
书店会说，哦，这边就在这里，对吧？
relationship with capar romantic
与卡帕尔的浪漫关系
relationship say okay where's your
关系说好吧，你的在哪里
section on
部分
friendship no section on friendship Do
友谊，没有关于友谊的章节。
you have a a book on friendship the
你有一本关于友谊的书。
answer is maybe we have
答案或许是我们有
one your assistant we spoke to your
我们和你的一位助理谈过了
assistant ahead of this conversation
助理在本次对话前
today and she said that friendship and
今天，她说友谊和
connection is a major part of your focus
联系是你关注的重点之一。
at the moment yes always but it it
目前是的，一直都是，但它
always has been now now you're doing
一直都是现在，你现在正在做
intense things with startups part of the
与初创公司打交道的紧张关系是其中的一部分
reason I actually think you should work
我觉得你应该工作的原因
with friends you should hire friends
和朋友一起，你应该雇佣朋友
this is kind of a little bit you know
这有点像你知道的
counter common wisdom is because you
与普遍认知相悖的原因在于你
want to be spending your time with
想和……一起度过时光
friends and that does ADD difficulties
朋友们，这确实会造成注意力缺陷障碍。
right but you want to spend your time
对，但你想把时间花在……
with your friends that's really good are
和朋友们一起玩真的很好
you still friends with Peter the yes you
你还和彼得是朋友吗？是的。
have a lot of disagreements in terms of
在以下方面存在很多分歧：
politics but intense disagreements on
政治方面存在激烈分歧
politics but you still are able to be
政治，但你仍然能够
friends but we also met um with you know
朋友，但我们也遇到了你知道的……
as undergraduates you know in a like
作为本科生，你们都知道这一点
like I knew he was extremely right and
我知道他完全正确，
he knew I was left you know I've become
他知道我被抛弃了，你知道我已经变成了
much more
还有很多
uh business oriented than I was as
比我以前更注重商业。
undergraduates and he's become much more
本科生们，他变得更加……
libertarian
自由主义者
but you know disagreements is a good
但你知道，分歧是好事。
thing can be a good thing we have a
事情可能是件好事，我们拥有……
closing tradition on this podcast where
本播客的结尾传统是……
the last guest leaves a question for the
最后一位客人留下了一个问题。
next guest not knowing who they're going
下一位客人不知道自己要去哪里。
to be leaving it for oh and the question
把它留给……哦，还有这个问题
that's been left for you is a very
留给你的那份非常
interesting one
有趣的一个
okay what are the two things you want
好的，你想要哪两样东西？
your life partner to know about you that
让你的伴侣了解你的这些
they do not know or do not understand
他们不知道或不理解
about you
关于你
yet that's an interesting thing it's an
但那是一件很有趣的事，它……
interesting if someone has an answer to
如果有人知道答案，那就太好了。
that question it suggests that they're
这个问题暗示他们是
not being a particularly good life
生活并不特别美好。
partner I think I have been and will
我认为我一直是，而且将来也会是伴侣。
continue to be a good life partner so I
继续做一个好伴侣，所以我
actually don't have an answer to that
实际上，我没有答案。
question what's her name Michelle yes
问她叫什么名字？米歇尔，是的。
has does she misunderstand you in
她是否误解了你？
anyway
反正
[Music]
[音乐]
um I don't know if it's a
嗯，我不知道它是不是……
misunderstanding because we put a lot of
误解是因为我们投入了很多
energy into understanding each other I
将精力投入到相互理解中
mean like for example we've seen
意思是，例如我们已经看到
marriage counselors together and not
婚姻咨询师在一起，而不是
because we're going we're like fighting
因为我们正在前进，就像在战斗一样。
about something it's because helping
关于某件事，是因为帮助
having a third party help you understand
让第三方帮助你理解
the other person well is like actually
另一个人其实是这样的
in fact a very good thing find someone
事实上，找到某人是一件非常好的事。
who's really good and do that right I do
谁真正擅长并且能把那件事做好，我就是。
that with my partner yeah it's it's it's
和我的伴侣一起，是的，是的，是的
great you should do it you shouldn't be
太好了，你应该这么做，你不应该……
because we're arguing it should be
因为我们认为它应该是
because we are putting lots of energy
因为我们投入了大量精力
into understanding each other I still
我仍然努力去了解彼此。
think there's things about my partner
我觉得我的伴侣身上有些问题
that she doesn't understand about me or
她不了解我，或者
misunderstands about me and I
关于我和我的误会
misunderstand about her yeah of course
对她有误解，当然了。
and by the way I can point out things
顺便说一句，我可以指出一些事情。
that I have learned about her like for
我了解到她喜欢……
example like the local community is what
例如当地社区就是一个例子
really matters to her right I didn't
对她来说这很重要，我并不在意。
really understand that 10 years ago now
现在我才真正理解了10年前的情况。
I understand that right um I'm sure she
我明白了，嗯，我确定她
has those kind of similar things about
也有类似的事情
me
我
but like the moment it occurs to me that
但就在我突然意识到这一点的时候
there's something she doesn't understand
她有些事不明白
about me it comes up at a
关于我，这个问题经常出现。
dinner you know not too many weeks in
你知道，晚餐时间不会太长了。
the future because that's part of how we
未来，因为这是我们方式的一部分
come to our dinners right we come to our
来参加我们的晚餐吧，我们来参加我们的晚餐吧
dinners is if one of us is on you know I
晚餐就是如果我们其中一人值班的时候，你知道的。
had this thought we want to have those
我当时想，我们想要拥有那些
dinners Founders you're investing in
晚餐 创始人 你投资的对象
that are in a stable solid relationship
处于稳定牢固的关系中
before they start the startup
在他们开始创业之前
yeah and then they go on this crazy
是啊，然后他们就开始疯狂地胡闹。
intense Journey do you ever give them
你是否曾带他们踏上过一段精彩的旅程
advice on relationships and how to
关于人际关系以及如何相处的建议
manage that because I have so many
因为我有很多事情要做，所以要设法做到。
Founders come to me and they're like I
创始人来找我，他们会说：
think she's going to break up with me or
我觉得她要跟我分手了
he's going to break up with me because
他要跟我分手，因为
I'm just I'm absent in my head in person
我这个人心不在焉，根本没法和人交流。
you try to have a really good
你努力做到非常好
relationship you try to be as like like
你试图在关系中尽可能地像
I think you should in friendship and in
我认为你应该在友谊和……方面都这样做。
relationships you should try to identify
你应该尝试识别的关系
the things in yourself that the other
你自身那些与他人相关的特质
person may find challenging and you
这个人可能会觉得很有挑战性，而你
should bring them up in advance
应该提前提出这些问题。
M right that is a very good way to build
没错，这的确是很好的构建方式。
deep quality friendships and
深厚的友谊和
relationships so for example in startups
例如，在初创公司中建立关系
Michelle knew that about me so when we
米歇尔知道我的这个秘密，所以当我们
had planned our wedding and we we were
我们计划了我们的婚礼，我们当时
doing a small you know um thing with you
跟你一起做点小事，你知道的，嗯……
know just basically Justice to the peace
基本上只知道维护治安的公正。
and so forth we planned our wedding and
于是，我们开始筹备婚礼。
it was very early days of LinkedIn and I
当时LinkedIn还处于早期阶段，而我
came back home and I said we really need
回到家后，我说我们真的需要
to delay it
拖延时间
right we delayed it a couple weeks right
对，我们推迟了两周。
was like we really need to delay I'm
感觉就像我们真的需要推迟一下。
doing this thing at LinkedIn right now
我现在正在LinkedIn上做这件事
we really need to have it I I don't have
我们真的需要它，但我没有。
time for that and Michelle didn't go ah
时间到了，米歇尔却没走。
she went okay let's make it work because
她接着说，好吧，我们一起努力吧，因为
I'd been clear with her about what the
我已经跟她明确说明了什么
startup Journey was like right I had
创业公司 Journey 就像我之前说的那样。
experience with it before and now
之前和现在的经验
sometimes like we didn't know it before
有时就像我们以前不知道一样
but like look I'm really committed to
但是你看，我真的非常投入
this and it's really important to me
这一点对我来说真的很重要。
that I do that well that should be kind
我做得很好，这应该是一种善意。
of life partner things did you let her
关于生活伴侣的事情，你让她做了什么？
down a l uh I hope not in terms of
往下看，呃，我希望不是这样。
making a plan making a dat we had we had
制定计划，安排日期，我们曾经有过
multiple plans that got blown up right
多个计划都被彻底破坏了
and what about the dealing with the
那么，如何处理这个问题呢？
stress when you come home something I've
回家后感到压力，这是我一直以来的感受。
always struggled with is if work is
我一直纠结的问题是，工作是否是
stressful when I come home I can be
回家后我可能会感到压力很大
absent and then you have to transition
缺席，然后你必须过渡
into this mode of partner but my head is
进入这种伴侣模式，但我的头脑却……
still thinking oh my God cash flow this
还在想，我的天啊，现金流这事儿
or whatever well occasionally that's one
或者其他什么，偶尔也会有这种情况。
of the things that Michelle go like you
米歇尔喜欢你做的事
know I think you're not being fully
我知道我觉得你没有完全坦诚。
present right like that's one of the one
就像这是其中之一一样。
of the kind of as it were key words
就像关键词一样
between us is I think you're not being
我们之间的问题是，我认为你没有……
fully present and that's the stop
完全投入，这就结束了。
thinking about whatever else you're
想着你正在想的其他事情
doing and
做和
focus okay and I'm yes we've had that
集中注意力，好的，是的，我们已经讨论过这个问题了。
conversation more times than I can
对话次数比我能进行的次数还要多
probably remember and count and is it
可能记得并计数，是吗？
easy just do uh you learn to really yes
很简单，你只要学会就行了，真的，是的
you learn to because as you as you like
你学会了，因为你喜欢
you have the okay what is that mean take
你说的“好的”是什么意思？
those other things push them off the
其他那些事情会让他们失去动力。
table Focus or by the way occasionally
表格焦点或顺便偶尔
you go you're right I'm really sorry I'm
你说得对，我真的很抱歉。
just so distracted by this right now
我现在完全被这件事分散了注意力。
would you mind if like like I'm fully
你介意我完全
present tomorrow because a lot of
明天送礼物，因为很多
Founders would Gaslight their partner
创始人会用煤气灯效应操控他们的伴侣
there and say you don't understand you
在那里说你不理解你
don't get it I'm doing this for you this
不明白吗？我这么做都是为了你。
is for us look you hate my work well if
对我们来说，你看你讨厌我的作品，好吧，如果
you're having that conversation if the
如果你正在进行那场对话，那么
person doesn't look the two people need
这个人看起来不像两个人需要的那种人。
to believe in each other and what
彼此信任以及什么
they're doing if the person doesn't
如果那个人不这样做，他们就会这样做。
believe in you and what you're doing
相信你自己和你正在做的事情。
right you have a long-term
没错，你有一个长期的
problem yeah and I guess the
问题是，我想也是。
communication is the very heart of that
沟通是这一切的核心。
right yes Reed we are all very excited
没错，里德，我们都非常兴奋。
for your next book which you said it's
你说过你的下一本书是……
coming out in January January yeah end
一月份上市，一月份结束
of January it's a book called Super
一月份出版的一本书叫做《超级》。
agency what could possibly go right with
机构可能会有什么好事发生
our AI future co-written with Greg bet
我们与 Greg bet 共同撰写的关于人工智能未来的文章
Bato
巴托
Bato what could possibly go right with
巴托，什么事情能顺利进行呢？
our AI future yes an optimistic take
是的，我们对人工智能的未来持乐观态度。
about AI uh yes
关于人工智能，嗯，是的
why should someone in who should read
为什么有人应该读
that book so anyone
那本书所以任何人
who uh believes as I do the only way
谁和我一样相信唯一的方法
that you can possibly get to an
你有可能到达一个
optimistic future is envisioning what
乐观的未来是对未来的展望
some of the things are and head towards
有些事情是，并且朝着……方向发展
it that you don't get to an optimistic
那就是你无法达到乐观的境界。
future by trying to avoid failure by
通过努力避免失败，从而拥有未来
trying to avoid pessimism anyone who
试图避免悲观情绪的人
says okay it's important for me to
他说好的，这对我来说很重要
understand that perspective about
理解这种观点
AI they should read super agency we we
人工智能他们应该读超级机构我们
have a book blurb from yval Harari which
有一段伊瓦尔·赫拉利的推荐语，
says this is a brilliant positive vision
这真是一个绝妙的积极愿景
of the future I disagree with some of
对于未来，我有一些不同的看法。
its main arguments and everyone should
它的主要论点，每个人都应该
read
读
it that's refreshing yes I'll link it
那真是令人耳目一新，好的，我会把链接发给你。
below for anyone that wants to pre-order
下方链接供想要预购的人参考
it um but I highly recommend everybody
嗯，但我强烈推荐给大家
goes and checks out your books which are
去查看你的书，这些书是
iconic because they've shaped the
之所以具有标志性意义，是因为它们塑造了……
thinking of Founders across the world
思考世界各地的创始人
and if even if you're not a Founder the
即使你不是创始人，
startup of view is for everybody
启动视图是面向所有人的
regardless of what you're doing it helps
无论你在做什么，这都有帮助。
you navigate both building a business
你既要经营企业，又要兼顾其他方面。
but also just your cre generally and
但也包括你的个人特质，以及
also masters of scale which is an iconic
他们也是规模的掌控者，这堪称标志性的
podcast that many of us listen to here
我们很多人都在这里收听的播客
where you sit down with some of the
在那里，你可以和一些人坐下来……
greatest founders of all time and
史上最伟大的创始人
understand how they've scaled and built
了解他们是如何扩展和构建的
their companies it's a podcast that I
他们的公司，这是一个我听过的播客。
Know Jack is a massive fan of and one of
Know Jack 是某某的超级粉丝，也是其中之一
the first podcasts they ever got
他们收到的第一批播客
listening to as well highly recommend
听着也觉得很棒，强烈推荐
that I also have the book there and I'll
我那里也有那本书，我会
link all of this stuff below Reed thank
下面这些链接都在这里，谢谢 Reed
you it's a pleasure I look forward to
很高兴见到你，我期待着。
the next one thank you so much it's been
下一个，非常感谢，这真是太棒了。
such an honor and
这是一种莫大的荣幸。
I so so wonderful speaking to someone
和人聊天真是太棒了
that has such diverse
拥有如此多样化的
um contrarian at times opinions but is
嗯，有时观点比较保守，但
willing to stand by them irrespective of
无论如何，我都愿意支持他们。
whether they are um believed or um
无论人们是否相信，
accepted or politically correct with the
被接受或政治正确
dominant narrative at the moment yeah
是的，这是目前的主流叙事。
and that comes from having such a wealth
而这源于拥有如此巨额的财富。
of experience but being fundamentally
经验，但本质上是
well intentioned I think so thank you
我想你的出发点是好的，谢谢。
Reed for the time I really appreciate it
里德，我真的很感激你抽出时间。
it's an honor to get to meet you thank
能见到你真是我的荣幸，谢谢。
you and thanks for creating LinkedIn I
谢谢你，也感谢你创建了LinkedIn。
[__] LinkedIn I think they sponsored
该死的LinkedIn，我觉得他们赞助了。
this podcast so oh awesome I I didn't
这个播客太棒了，我之前没听过。
even know that oh really yeah they do
甚至知道这一点，哦，真的吗？是的，他们确实知道。
yeah so thank you so much appreciate
是的，非常感谢，感激不尽。
it isn't this cool every single
并不是每个地方都这么酷
conversation I have here on the Diary of
我在这里的日记中与人进行了一次对话
a CEO at the very end of it you'll know
最后你会知道，CEO会明白的。
I asked the guest to leave a question in
我请客人留下一个问题。
the Diary of a CEO and what we've done
CEO日记以及我们所做的事情
is we've turned every single question
我们已经把每一个问题都问完了
written in the Diary of a CEO into these
写在《CEO日记》中的这些
conversation cards that you can play at
你可以玩的对话卡片
home so you've got every guest we've
回家吧，这样我们所有的客人都到齐了。
ever had their question and on the back
他们是否曾有过这样的疑问，以及在背面
of it if you scan that QR codee you get
如果你扫描那个二维码，你就能得到它。
to watch the person who answered that
观察回答这个问题的人
question we're finally revealing all of
我们终于要揭晓所有答案了
the questions and the people that
问题和相关人员
answered the question the brand new
回答了这个问题，全新的
version two updated conversation cards
第二版更新了对话卡片
are out right now at Theon conversation
目前正在进行席恩对话
cards.com they've sold out twice
cards.com 上的商品已经售罄两次了。
instantaneously so if you are interested
立即，所以如果您感兴趣的话
in getting hold of some limited edition
设法弄到一些限量版
conversation cards I really really
对话卡片 我真的真的
recommend acting quickly
建议迅速采取行动
a
一个
[Music]
[音乐]